<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>keep us online on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/categories/keep-us-online/</link>
    <description>Recent content in keep us online on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 13:11:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/categories/keep-us-online/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Calcutta HC stays internet shutdown issued by West Bengal Government</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/calcutta-hc-stays-internet-shutdown-issued-by-west-bengal-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 13:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/calcutta-hc-stays-internet-shutdown-issued-by-west-bengal-government/</guid>
      <description>Calcutta HC has stayed an internet shutdown order dated 03.03.2022 issued by the State of West Bengal. The HC was of the view that the order was not issued by a competent authority. The order was stayed in a petition filed by Ashlesh Biradar. IFF provided legal support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revealed: Rajasthan’s Review Committee does not meet or review internet suspension orders. #KeepItOn</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/revealed-rajasthans-review-committee-does-not-meet-or-review-internet-suspension-orders-keepiton/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 18:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/revealed-rajasthans-review-committee-does-not-meet-or-review-internet-suspension-orders-keepiton/</guid>
      <description>In response to an RTI Application, the State of Rajasthan has stated that their review committee does not meet or review internet shutdown orders. This is contrary to Rule 2(6) of Telecom Suspension Rules, 2017. We have filed a first appeal seeking clarity from the State.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gauhati HC allows IFF&#39;s intervention application in petition challenging the constitutionality of internet shutdown rules #KeepItOn</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/gauhati-hc-internet-shutdown-rules-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 09:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/gauhati-hc-internet-shutdown-rules-update/</guid>
      <description>At a hearing dated January 31, 2022, IFF&amp;rsquo;s intervention application challenging the Telecom Suspension Rules, 2017 has been allowed by the Gauhati High Court, and IFF has been impleaded in the case. IFF is now allowed to assist the Court with oral and written submissions in the proceedings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundation for Media Professionals writes to J&amp;K Govt seeking compliance with Anuradha Bhasin</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/foundation-for-media-professionals-writes-to-j-k-govt-seeking-compliance-with-anuradha-bhasin-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 07:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/foundation-for-media-professionals-writes-to-j-k-govt-seeking-compliance-with-anuradha-bhasin-2/</guid>
      <description>In May 2021 the Government of J&amp;amp;K suspended internet services on three occasions, without promptly publishing suspensions orders. Foundation of Media Professionals has addressed a legal notice to the Government of J&amp;amp;K asking them to comply with directions of the Supreme Court in Anuradha Bhasin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rajasthan Government Must Fix Its Internet Shutdown Problem #KeepItOn</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/rajasthan-govt-internet-shutdown-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 06:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/rajasthan-govt-internet-shutdown-representation/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the Rajasthan Government expressing concerns about unauthorised government officials imposing internet shutdowns and lack of periodic review and proactive publication of internet shutdown orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement on long overdue 4G mobile internet restoration in Jammu &amp; Kashmir after 550 days #KeepItOn</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-j-k-4g-restoration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 06:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-j-k-4g-restoration/</guid>
      <description>No citizen of a democracy should have to suffer through what the people of Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir experienced and we will keep pushing for broader internet shutdown reform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Govt agrees to staggered restoration of 4G mobile internet  in J&amp;K before the Supreme Court #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/staggered-4g-restoration-j-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 08:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/staggered-4g-restoration-j-k/</guid>
      <description>During today&amp;rsquo;s hearing in Foundation for Media Professionals&amp;rsquo; contempt petition relating to the internet restrictions in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir, the government agreed to restore 4G mobile internet in one district of Jammu and Kashmir each on a trial basis after 15 August i.e. Independence Day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement and a Call to Action to the Standing Committee on IT on the One Year Anniversary of Internet Restrictions in J&amp;K #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-j-k-internet-restrictions-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 04:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-j-k-internet-restrictions-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>No citizen of a 21st century democracy should have to live in digital darkness for over a year. Read IFF&amp;rsquo;s statement and call to action to the Parliamentary Standing Committee on IT on the  anniversary of the communication shutdown imposed in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir on 05 August 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fight for fast and affordable internet in Andaman &amp; Nicobar Islands continues... #4GforAll #InternetinAndaman</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-fight-for-fast-and-affordable-internet-in-andaman-nicobar-islands-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 04:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-fight-for-fast-and-affordable-internet-in-andaman-nicobar-islands-continues/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to Shri Kuldeep Rai Sharma, the Honourable Member of Parliament for the Andaman and Nicobar Islands stating our concerns and urging him to escalate the matter with PMO and MeitY.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 months after Anuradha Bhasin v. UoI, state governments are still not publishing internet shutdown orders #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/publication-internet-shutdown-orders/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 12:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/publication-internet-shutdown-orders/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to DoT and State Governments of Madhya Pradesh, Meghalaya, Uttar Pradesh and West Bengal seeking proactive publication of internet shutdown orders in accordance with Anuradha Bhasin v. Union of India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For the people of Andaman &amp; Nicobar Islands, 4G internet at reasonable tariffs is still a dream...  #DigitalAndaman #4GforAll</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/for-the-people-of-andaman-nicobar-islands-4g-internet-at-reasonable-tariffs-is-still-a-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 11:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/for-the-people-of-andaman-nicobar-islands-4g-internet-at-reasonable-tariffs-is-still-a-dream/</guid>
      <description>In this blogpost, we aim to highlight the access to internet problems being faced by the citizens of the Andaman and Nicobar Islands with a focus on the delays in the ongoing CANI Submarine Cable Systems Project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Write to DoT and TRAI to Improve Internet Access and Protect Net Neutrality During COVID-19 #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-write-to-dot-and-trai-to-improve-internet-access-and-protect-net-neutrality-during-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 08:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-write-to-dot-and-trai-to-improve-internet-access-and-protect-net-neutrality-during-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>IFF has written to the DoT and TRAI suggesting that government interventions must look toward overcoming the digital divide, appreciating the importance of the internet and mobile services as an essential utility, and protect net neutrality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can’t Drop the Ball on Internet Shutdown Reform #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/cant-drop-the-ball-on-internet-shutdown-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 05:38:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/cant-drop-the-ball-on-internet-shutdown-reform/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the Department of Telecommunications and the Ministry of Parliamentary Affairs urging for review of the Telecom Suspension Rules 2017 based on public consultation and economic impact assessment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOS : Three ways how the Department of Telecom can help #FlattenTheCurve #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/urgent-steps-to-be-taken-by-the-department-of-telecom-due-to-the-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 11:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/urgent-steps-to-be-taken-by-the-department-of-telecom-due-to-the-covid/</guid>
      <description>With many workplaces putting into place work from home plans, voice and data connectivity become critical. To ensure that high quality bandwidth is available to all parts of India we have suggested specific steps to be taken by the Department of Telecom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The J&amp;K Govt cannot ban Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-j-k-govt-cannot-ban-virtual-private-networks-vpns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-j-k-govt-cannot-ban-virtual-private-networks-vpns/</guid>
      <description>Internet Freedom Foundation wrote to the Home Department of Jammu and Kashmir and key central government departments about the unlawful blocking of access to virtual private networks (VPNs) in J&amp;amp;K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We strongly condemn the communications blackout in Jammu and Kashmir and urge an end to internet shutdowns across India</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kashmir_shutdowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 02:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kashmir_shutdowns/</guid>
      <description>The developments of the past few days are of immense consequence to the future of our democracy, and the voices from Jammu and Kashmir need to be heard the loudest, not silenced en masse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the block! Our net neutrality rules require a monitoring and enforcement structure #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/what-the-block-our-net-neutrality-rules-require-a-monitoring-and-enforcement-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 05:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/what-the-block-our-net-neutrality-rules-require-a-monitoring-and-enforcement-structure/</guid>
      <description>A particularly concerning threat to net neutrality, looms the web. IFF has been engaging with users for a few months gathering evidence of extensive blocking. We summarise this to you and explain how this is a violation of Net Neutrality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We urge DOT to be a defender of digital rights. #KeepUsOnline #LetTheNetWork #KeepItOn #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/an-acknowledgment-of-harm-of-internet-shutdowns-by-the-dot-keepusonline-letthenetwork-keepiton/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 06:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/an-acknowledgment-of-harm-of-internet-shutdowns-by-the-dot-keepusonline-letthenetwork-keepiton/</guid>
      <description>We request the Department of Telecom to extend public victories on net neutrality and internet shutdowns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An incremental victory in the Rajasthan HC against Internet Shutdowns #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/an-incremental-victory-in-the-rajasthan-hc-against-internet-shutdowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 08:03:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/an-incremental-victory-in-the-rajasthan-hc-against-internet-shutdowns/</guid>
      <description>While we can expect internet shutdowns in future, it will not be because of competitive examinations in Rajasthan. We thank the Petitioner, Dhirendra Rajpurohit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support parlimentary scrutiny against internet shutdowns #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/continued-action-against-internet-shutdowns-keepusonline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 06:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/continued-action-against-internet-shutdowns-keepusonline/</guid>
      <description>Support advocacy actions against the growing problem of internet shutdowns across India by engaging parliamentarians. We have prepared a short brief to help you set out key facts, figures and arguments on the massive damage caused by shutting down the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We demand disclosure on India&#39;s shutdown law #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-demand-disclosure-on-indias-shutdown-law-keepusonline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 09:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-demand-disclosure-on-indias-shutdown-law-keepusonline/</guid>
      <description>Last week we made considerable progress in our mission to reform India’s Internet Shutdown laws. This work has been extensively covered by The Wire in an opinion piece titled, “The Worst Aspect of India’s Internet Shutdowns Is the Official Secrecy About It”, and “Jan Gan Man Ki Baat, Episode No. 271”.
A Short Recap
 Noticing a growth in the frequency of internet shutdowns and constrained by the lack of movement for reform, on April 22, 2018, we sent a petition to several government ministries and the Prime Minister’s Office (PMO).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
