<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Legal on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/categories/legal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Legal on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 05:51:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/categories/legal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bombay High Court stays the operation of Rule 9(1) and Rule 9(3) of IT Rules, 2021</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/bombay-high-court-stays-the-operation-of-rule-9-1-and-rule-9-3-of-it-rules-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 05:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/bombay-high-court-stays-the-operation-of-rule-9-1-and-rule-9-3-of-it-rules-2021/</guid>
      <description>The Court found these rules, which prescribed a Code of Ethics and a 3-tier grievance redressal mechanism, to be prima facie violative of Article 19(1)(a) and beyond the rule-making power conferred by the Parliament on the Government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MEITY filed a limited affidavit in Supreme Court without confirming or denying if the Government used Pegasus</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/meity-filed-a-limited-affidavit-in-supreme-court-but-did-not-confirm-or-deny-if-the-government-used-pegasus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 14:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/meity-filed-a-limited-affidavit-in-supreme-court-but-did-not-confirm-or-deny-if-the-government-used-pegasus/</guid>
      <description>The Government has filed a limited affidavit before the SC which proposes to constitute a Committee of Experts but does not categorically comment on whether the government used the Pegasus Spyware. The SC has heard submissions on the limited affidavit and has listed the case for 17.08.2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Government again seeks time to respond to Mr T.M. Krishna’s petition</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/the-government-again-seeks-time-to-respond-to-mr-t-m-krishnas-petition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 12:06:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/the-government-again-seeks-time-to-respond-to-mr-t-m-krishnas-petition/</guid>
      <description>In proceedings instituted by Mr TM Krishna, challenging the validity of IT Rules, 2021, the Madras High Court directed the government to explain why appropirate action should not be taken against those responsible for the delay in their filing. The case is now listed for 13th August 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SC directs States, UTs and High Courts to reply to PUCL’s Application</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/supreme-court-issues-notice-to-all-the-states-uts-and-high-courts-in-pucls-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 06:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/supreme-court-issues-notice-to-all-the-states-uts-and-high-courts-in-pucls-application/</guid>
      <description>PUCL&amp;rsquo;s application seeks direction to ensure that authorities do not continue to prosecute individuals under S.66A of the IT Act, 2000. Supreme Court heard PUCL&amp;rsquo;s application and sought responses from all State&amp;rsquo;s, UT&amp;rsquo;s and High Court&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spooked by the Zombie? Ministry of Home Affairs issues notification directing all S.66A cases to stop</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/spooked-by-the-zombie-ministry-of-home-affairs-issues-notification-directing-all-s-66a-cases-to-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 10:52:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/spooked-by-the-zombie-ministry-of-home-affairs-issues-notification-directing-all-s-66a-cases-to-stop/</guid>
      <description>Prompted by our application, the Ministry of Home Affairs, on July 14, 2021 issued a notification directing all law enforcement authorities to stop registering new cases under Section 66A of the Information Technology Act, 2000 and to immediately withdraw all pending cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explained: Supreme Court upholds Delhi Assemblies summons to Facebook</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/explained-supreme-court-upholds-delhi-assemblies-summons-to-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 07:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/explained-supreme-court-upholds-delhi-assemblies-summons-to-facebook/</guid>
      <description>IFF explains the decision of the Supreme Court rejecting the plea filed by the Managing Director of Facebook India, Ajit Mohan against the summons issued by the Peace and Harmony Committee of Delhi Assembly which sought his appearance in an inquiry related to the Delhi Riots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Union of India seeks a transfer of cases challenging IT Rules, 2021</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/union-of-india-seeks-a-transfer-of-cases-challenging-it-rules-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 09:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/union-of-india-seeks-a-transfer-of-cases-challenging-it-rules-2021/</guid>
      <description>A two-judge bench of the Supreme Court has listed the Union of India&amp;rsquo;s transfer petition before another bench on 16th July 2021. The petition seeks a transfer to the Supreme Court of 4 cases challenging IT Rules, 2021 which are pending before different High Courts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indore administration curbs speech on social media</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/indore-administration-curbs-speech-on-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 13:03:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/indore-administration-curbs-speech-on-social-media/</guid>
      <description>Indore administration issued an over-broad order under Section 144(1) CrPC, 1973 banning speech related to Covid-19 on social media platforms. We have filed an application before the  Collector, Indore seeking withdrawal of the Order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buffering Justice : A call for greater participation in the Draft Vision Document for Judicial Digitisation</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/digitization-of-indian-judiciary-phase-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 05:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/digitization-of-indian-judiciary-phase-iii/</guid>
      <description>E-Committee has released the draft vision document of e-Courts Project Phase III. We encourage you to submit your comments on &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ecommittee@aij.gov.in&#34;&gt;ecommittee@aij.gov.in&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, we have provided our inputs on the document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delhi HC issues notice to govt in petition challenging denial of RTI  regarding Aarogya Setu  #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/delhi-hc-hearing-aarogya-setu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 11:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/delhi-hc-hearing-aarogya-setu/</guid>
      <description>Today, the Delhi HC issued notice to the CPIOs of DeitY, MeitY, NeGD and NIC in a petition filed by RTI activist, Saurav Das, challenging denial of information relating to the creation of the Aarogya Setu app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Kanoon defends the right to provide access to court records</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/indian-kanoon-kerala-hc-right-to-be-forgotten/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/indian-kanoon-kerala-hc-right-to-be-forgotten/</guid>
      <description>In response to a petition filed before the Kerala HC, Indian Kanoon has clarified that a right to be forgotten cannot be judicially created without a statutory basis and explained that court records are public documents whose reproduction cannot be prohibited by citing the right to privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement: IFF joins international civil society orgs to oppose the NSO Group’s attempt to evade responsibility for the Pegasus Hack #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/ninth-circuit-amici-brief-whatsapp-nso-group-pegasus-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 05:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/ninth-circuit-amici-brief-whatsapp-nso-group-pegasus-hack/</guid>
      <description>8 civil society organisations from across the world including IFF have filed an amici brief before the Ninth Circuit Federal Court of Appeals in California urging the Court to dismiss the NSO Group&amp;rsquo;s appeal claiming sovereign immunity for the Pegasus hack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF intervenes in Madras HC PIL seeking censorship on online streaming platforms #LetUsChill</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/iff-intervenes-madras-hc-pil-ott-regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 07:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/iff-intervenes-madras-hc-pil-ott-regulation/</guid>
      <description>In the impleadment application, we have cautioned against judicial intervention at this stage because OTT regulation is a complex and technical issue best addressed through legislative and policy making processes involving extensive stakeholder consultation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As internet restrictions in J&amp;K cross 480 days, we await SC judgement #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/non-publication-of-internet-shutdown-review-orders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 07:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/non-publication-of-internet-shutdown-review-orders/</guid>
      <description>Non-publication of orders issued by the Review Committee and Special Committee continues to remain a problem in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir which must be decided by the Supreme Court to ensure independent application of mind by these bodies and implementation of their recommendations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Govt officials to justify denial of information about Aarogya Setu in secret hearing before CIC #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/cic-legal-notice-aarogya-setu-show-cause-hearing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 05:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/cic-legal-notice-aarogya-setu-show-cause-hearing/</guid>
      <description>We sent a legal notice to the Central Information Commission challenging its refusal to let RTI activist, Saurav Das attend the show cause hearing in his complaint which seeks information about creation of the Aarogya Setu app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delhi HC directs govt to consider  representation regarding national Health Data Management Policy #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/ndhm-data-policy-delhi-hc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 08:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/ndhm-data-policy-delhi-hc/</guid>
      <description>The petition heard by the Delhi HC raised concerns about the unreasonably short deadline for submission of feedback at the height of the COVID-19 pandemic, and highlighted how the existing process excludes persons with disabilities, non-English speakers and people without internet access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kerala HC to hear Aarogya Setu petitions in September 2020 #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/kerala-hc-aarogya-setu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 07:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/kerala-hc-aarogya-setu/</guid>
      <description>On 24 August, the Kerala HC heard a writ petition regarding third party data sharing and mandatory imposition of the Aarogya Setu app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Govt agrees to staggered restoration of 4G mobile internet  in J&amp;K before the Supreme Court #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/staggered-4g-restoration-j-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 08:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/staggered-4g-restoration-j-k/</guid>
      <description>During today&amp;rsquo;s hearing in Foundation for Media Professionals&#39; contempt petition relating to the internet restrictions in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir, the government agreed to restore 4G mobile internet in one district of Jammu and Kashmir each on a trial basis after 15 August i.e. Independence Day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FMP files rejoinder before SC about Jammu &amp; Kashmir 4G mobile internet ban #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/fmp-contempt-petition-rejoinder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 08:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/fmp-contempt-petition-rejoinder/</guid>
      <description>During today&amp;rsquo;s hearing before the Supreme Court, the Solicitor General sought an adjournment to go through FMP&amp;rsquo;s rejoinder which challenges secrecy in the functioning of the Special Committee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fridays For Future India resists illegal website blocking #WhatTheBlock</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/fridays-for-future-representation-to-delhi-police/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/fridays-for-future-representation-to-delhi-police/</guid>
      <description>Fridays for Future has written to the Delhi Police objecting to the blocking of its website for encouraging public participation in the consultation process for Draft EIA Notification 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supreme Court directs Govt to file its reply in FMP&#39;s contempt petition #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/fmp-contempt-petition-reply/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 09:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/fmp-contempt-petition-reply/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court has directed the Government to file its reply in a contempt petition relating to the 4G mobile internet ban in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FMP demands compliance with SC directions by Special Committee for restoration of 4G in J&amp;K #KeepUsOnline #4GforAll</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/fmp-demands-compliance-with-sc-judgement-by-special-committee-for-restoration-of-4g-in-j-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 10:36:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/fmp-demands-compliance-with-sc-judgement-by-special-committee-for-restoration-of-4g-in-j-k/</guid>
      <description>FMP wrote to the Special Committee established by the Supreme Court seeking immediate review of internet restrictions in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir within 7 working days and publication of the Committee&amp;rsquo;s recommendations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kerala High Court hears challenges against mandatory imposition of Aarogya Setu</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/kerala-hc-hears-challenges-against-mandatory-imposition-of-aarogya-setu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 12:49:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/kerala-hc-hears-challenges-against-mandatory-imposition-of-aarogya-setu/</guid>
      <description>The Kerala High Court has directed MeitY to file a response to petitions challenging mandatory imposition of Aarogya Setu and to state on record that data collected by the app will not be misused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supreme Court reserves order in petitions seeking restoration of 4G internet in Jammu &amp; Kashmir</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/sc-reserves-judgement-in-petitions-for-4g-restoration-in-j-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 11:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/sc-reserves-judgement-in-petitions-for-4g-restoration-in-j-k/</guid>
      <description>Today, the Supreme Court heard substantive arguments regarding the constitutionality and legality of the internet slowdown in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir during the COVID-19 pandemic and reserved its order in the matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal Notice to BECIL for it&#39;s tender to procure employee tracking smartwatches and a Covid-19 mass surveillance system #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/legal-notice-to-becil-for-its-tender-to-procure-employee-tracking-smartwatches-and-a-mass-surveillance-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 09:04:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/legal-notice-to-becil-for-its-tender-to-procure-employee-tracking-smartwatches-and-a-mass-surveillance-system/</guid>
      <description>IFF has sent a legal notice to a government entity BECIL that intends to procure two items (amongst a larger procurement of various other medical safety devices), i.e.  “Personnel Tracking GPS Solution” and the “Covid–19 Patient Tracking Tool”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SC issues notice in FMP’s petition seeking restoration of 4G internet services in Jammu &amp; Kashmir during COVID-19 crisis #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/sc-issues-notice-in-fmps-petition-seeking-restoration-of-4g-internet-services-in-jammu-kashmir-during-covid-19-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 09:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/sc-issues-notice-in-fmps-petition-seeking-restoration-of-4g-internet-services-in-jammu-kashmir-during-covid-19-crisis/</guid>
      <description>Today, a 3 judge bench of the Supreme Court issued notice in a petition filed by Foundation for Media Professionals against the internet slowdown in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir during the COVID-19 crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MeitY defends blocking of satirical Dowry Calculator website #FreeToMeme</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/meity-defends-blocking-of-satirical-dowry-calculator-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 05:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/meity-defends-blocking-of-satirical-dowry-calculator-website/</guid>
      <description>MeitY&amp;rsquo;s response to Tanul Thakur&amp;rsquo;s petition against the blocking of his Dowry Calculator website demonstrates lack of understanding of satire and non compliance with principles of natural justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Journalists Union defends media&#39;s right to report on MeToo allegations</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/indian-journalists-union-defends-right-of-journalists-to-report-on-metoo-allegations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 06:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/indian-journalists-union-defends-right-of-journalists-to-report-on-metoo-allegations/</guid>
      <description>In the latest hearing in Subodh Gupta&amp;rsquo;s defamation suit, IJU emphasized that news reports cannot be de-indexed without providing the journalists a hearing and argued there was a distinction between merely republishing defamatory allegations and reporting on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SC&#39;s Kashmir communication shutdown judgement is just the beginning of a long uphill campaign</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/scs-judgement-on-kashmir-communication-is-just-the-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 14:17:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/scs-judgement-on-kashmir-communication-is-just-the-beginning/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court&amp;rsquo;s judgement in Anuradha Bhasin v. Union of India is a step in the right direction but fails to provide immediate relief to Kashmiris who have already suffered immense hardship due to the 158 day communication shutdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delhi HC issues notice to the government for blocking satirical Dowry Calculator website</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/delhi-hc-issues-notice-to-the-government-for-blocking-satirical-dowry-calculator-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 05:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/delhi-hc-issues-notice-to-the-government-for-blocking-satirical-dowry-calculator-website/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday, the Delhi High Court issued notice to MeitY, DoT and Ministry of WCD for blocking the satirical Dowry Calculator website without complying with the provisions of Section 69A of the IT Act and the Blocking Rules made thereunder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap Part II: Kashmir Communication Shutdown and Movement Restrictions Cases</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/recap-part-ii-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-movement-restrictions-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 12:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/recap-part-ii-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-movement-restrictions-cases/</guid>
      <description>Part II of the Recap summarizes arguments made by the petitioners and the government about the constitutional validity of the communication shutdown and movement restrictions in Kashmir under Articles 19 and 21 of the Constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap Part I: Kashmir Communication Shutdown and Movement Restrictions Cases</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/recap-part-i-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-movement-restrictions-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 05:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/recap-part-i-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-movement-restrictions-cases/</guid>
      <description>Part I of the Recap summarizes the arguments made by the petitioners and the government about statutory compliance of the orders issued under the Telecom Suspension Rules 2017 and Section 144, Cr.P.C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government says judicial review of severity of the restrictions in Kashmir during August is an “academic exercise”</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/government-says-judicial-review-of-severity-of-the-restrictions-in-kashmir-during-august-is-an-academic-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 14:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/government-says-judicial-review-of-severity-of-the-restrictions-in-kashmir-during-august-is-an-academic-exercise/</guid>
      <description>In yesterday&amp;rsquo;s hearing, the Solicitor General argued that the telecom shutdown was necessary because digital platforms could be used for mobilisation by terrorists and separatists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journalistic bodies oppose communication and movement restrictions in Kashmir before the Supreme Court</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/journalistic-bodies-oppose-communication-and-movement-restrictions-in-kashmir-before-the-supreme-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 07:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/journalistic-bodies-oppose-communication-and-movement-restrictions-in-kashmir-before-the-supreme-court/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s hearing, Mr. Huzefa Ahmadi and Mr. Dushyant Dave advanced arguments on behalf of the Indian Journalists Union and Foundation for Media Professionals respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delhi HC directs Subodh Gupta to respond to impleadment application filed by Indian Journalists Union and allows Scene and Herd to contest anonymously (for now)</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/delhi-hc-directs-subodh-gupta-to-respond-to-impleadment-application-filed-by-indian-journalists-union-and-allows-scene-and-herd-to-contest-anonymously-for-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 13:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/delhi-hc-directs-subodh-gupta-to-respond-to-impleadment-application-filed-by-indian-journalists-union-and-allows-scene-and-herd-to-contest-anonymously-for-now/</guid>
      <description>The Delhi HC has issued notice in the impleadment application filed by the Indian Journalists Union in Subodh Gupta&amp;rsquo;s defamation suit and directed the Plaintiff to respond to concerns about overbroad censorship of news reports which adhere to professional journalistic standards of reporting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Substantive hearing in Anuradha Bhasin v. Union of India commences</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/substantive-hearing-in-anuradha-bhasin-v-union-of-india-commence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 13:36:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/substantive-hearing-in-anuradha-bhasin-v-union-of-india-commence/</guid>
      <description>In today’s hearing, Ms. Vrinda Grover used the govt’s statistics to prove there is no relation between the internet and rise in terrorism and argued there was no application of mind by the govt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A cellphone signal at the end of the tunnel? SC may finally hear substantive challenges to telecommunications shutdown in Kashmir around November</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/government-files-affidavit-in-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-press-freedom-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 12:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/government-files-affidavit-in-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-press-freedom-case/</guid>
      <description>In Kashmir Communication Shutdown and Press Freedom Case, the Govt has argued that the restrictions are necessary because of terrorism and declined to provide any specific information to the Petitioner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook’s Transfer Petition in Madras HC case involving encryption and traceability allowed after Tamil Nadu Government withdraws objections</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/facebooks-transfer-petition-in-madras-hc-case-involving-encryption-and-traceability-allowed-after-tamil-nadu-government-withdraws-objections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 09:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/facebooks-transfer-petition-in-madras-hc-case-involving-encryption-and-traceability-allowed-after-tamil-nadu-government-withdraws-objections/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s hearing, the SC allowed Facebook&amp;rsquo;s transfer petition in Antony Clement Rubin v. Union of India after the Tamil Nadu Government withdrew its objections to the transfer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For the Govt&#39;s Eyes Only? Govt opposes disclosure of orders imposing communication shutdown in Kashmir</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/for-the-govts-eyes-only-govt-opposes-disclosure-of-orders-imposing-communication-shutdown-in-kashmir/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 09:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/for-the-govts-eyes-only-govt-opposes-disclosure-of-orders-imposing-communication-shutdown-in-kashmir/</guid>
      <description>At today&amp;rsquo;s hearing, the Government cited national security concerns and objected to the Petitioner&amp;rsquo;s and the Intervenors&#39; demand for disclosure of orders issued under the Telecom Suspension Rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Action-Packed Hearing in Facebook&#39;s Transfer Petition before the Supreme Court</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/action-packed-hearing-in-facebooks-transfer-petition-before-the-supreme-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 09:35:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/action-packed-hearing-in-facebooks-transfer-petition-before-the-supreme-court/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s hearing, the Supreme Court emphasized that technical and complex issues such as encryption are best addressed by the executive branch and it directed the Central Government to file an affidavit about the status of the Draft Intermediaries Guidelines Rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundation for Media Professionals approaches Supreme Court 
to support journalistic freedom in Kashmir</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/foundation-for-media-professionals-approaches-supreme-court-to-support-journalistic-freedom-in-kashmir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 08:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/foundation-for-media-professionals-approaches-supreme-court-to-support-journalistic-freedom-in-kashmir/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s hearing, the SC wondered if the 40 day long suspension of telecom and internet services in Kashmir was a shutdown or breakdown. It finally directed the Govt. to file its response to the writ petition and intervention applications and urged selective restoration of communication channels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kashmiri student based in Bangalore files petition before the Karnataka HC 
against communication shutdown.</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/kashmiri-student-based-in-bangalore-files-petition-before-the-karnataka-hc-against-communication-shutdown-in-kashmir/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 05:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/kashmiri-student-based-in-bangalore-files-petition-before-the-karnataka-hc-against-communication-shutdown-in-kashmir/</guid>
      <description>The Petition argues that the communication shutdown violates Articles 14, 19 and 21 of the Constitution. The legal basis for the communication shutdown still remains unknown and the interim prayer seeks transparency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF files independent expert&#39;s submission before Madras HC on PIL relating to encryption and traceability</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/iff-files-independent-expert-submission-before-madras-hc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 09:13:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/iff-files-independent-expert-submission-before-madras-hc/</guid>
      <description>IFF has filed an expert submission by Dr. Manoj Prabhakaran (Professor, IIT Bombay) which highlights the risks and long term ineffectiveness of Dr. Kamakoti&amp;rsquo;s proposal to introduce traceability on encrypted platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Data and Information Privacy Code Bill, 2019 introduced in the Lok Sabha today! #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/personal-data-and-information-privacy-code-bill-2019-introduced-in-the-lok-sabha-today-saveourprivacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 12:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/personal-data-and-information-privacy-code-bill-2019-introduced-in-the-lok-sabha-today-saveourprivacy/</guid>
      <description>IFF goes to Parliament with Dr. Ravikumar (Lok Sabha, MP from Tamil Nadu). Today, the Personal Data and Information Privacy Code Bill, 2019 was introduced!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vanakkam! Updates on the Aadhaar-social media linkage and encryption PIL before the Madras HC</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/vanakkam-updates-on-the-aadhaar-social-media-linkage-and-encryption-pil-before-the-madras-hc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 09:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/vanakkam-updates-on-the-aadhaar-social-media-linkage-and-encryption-pil-before-the-madras-hc/</guid>
      <description>At today&amp;rsquo;s hearing, IFF placed on record its written submissions highlighting how proposed changes to the product design of social media platforms would harm user privacy and lead to over-broad automated censorship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Venom, venom, venom. BSNL engaging in code injections.</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/venom-venom-venom-bsnl-engaging-in-code-injections/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 09:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/venom-venom-venom-bsnl-engaging-in-code-injections/</guid>
      <description>Documents reports of code injections producing advertisments and images by BSNL&amp;rsquo;s has led us to question security and legality of their actions. We write to BSNL to take necessary recourse in addressing the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We won’t give up! IFF approaches CIC against MHA’s refusal to disclose surveillance figures.</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/we-wont-give-up-iff-approaches-cic-against-mhas-refusal-to-disclose-surveillance-figures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 10:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/we-wont-give-up-iff-approaches-cic-against-mhas-refusal-to-disclose-surveillance-figures/</guid>
      <description>After the MHA rejected our RTI applications about use of surveillance powers on flimsy grounds, IFF has filed an appeal before the CIC and we are willing to go the distance in this fight for transparency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One down, three to go!</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/one-down-two-to-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 12:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/one-down-two-to-go/</guid>
      <description>The Hon&amp;rsquo;ble High Court of Delhi applies the well-reasoned judgement of the Justice for Rights case in dismissing Nikhil Bhalla&amp;rsquo;s plea for guidelines to regulate online streaming content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF files rejoinder in PIL seeking surveillance reform</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/iff-files-rejoinder-in-pil-seeking-surveillance-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 14:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/iff-files-rejoinder-in-pil-seeking-surveillance-reform/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, IFF filed its rejoinder in the PIL seeking surveillance reform and reemphasized that judicial oversight is necessary in the surveillance process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try again? Gujarat High Court declines to hear our PIL against the PUBG Ban</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/try-again-high-court-declines-to-hear-our-pil-against-the-pubg-ban/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 12:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/try-again-high-court-declines-to-hear-our-pil-against-the-pubg-ban/</guid>
      <description>The Gujarat High Court has declined to hear our petition challenging the ban on PUBG and subsequent arrests of at least 21 young persons. We will continue fighting the good fight and consult our lawyers to figure out the way forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF files PIL against the PUBG Ban in Gujarat.</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/iff-files-pil-against-the-pubg-ban-in-gujarat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 05:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/iff-files-pil-against-the-pubg-ban-in-gujarat/</guid>
      <description>IFF has filed a PIL before the Gujarat High Court challenging the PUBG Ban and the subsequent arrests as violative of Articles 14, 19 and 21 of the Constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need for urgent steps on a fresh petition for censorship of Online Video Streaming websites.</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/here-we-go-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 07:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/here-we-go-again/</guid>
      <description>In yet another PIL filed in the Karnataka High Court, a plea has been placed for the regulation of online viewing content. We write to MEITY and MIB to maintain their positive stance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks to the Delhi High Court for letting us Netflix and chill!</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/take-it-and-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 04:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/take-it-and-go/</guid>
      <description>The Delhi High Court dismissed a PIL asking for TV style censorship on online video streaming services such as netflix, hotstar and amazon prime. We call for further steps by Government to extend this victory!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF will represent your digital rights in the WhatsApp Privacy Case</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/iff-will-represent-your-digital-rights-in-the-whatsapp-privacy-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 15:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/iff-will-represent-your-digital-rights-in-the-whatsapp-privacy-case/</guid>
      <description>Today a constitutional bench of the Supreme Court heard the WhatsApp Privacy Case—Karmaya Singh Sareen v. Union of India SLP (C) No. 804 of 2017—in which the Internet Freedom Foundation intervened to make submissions. The other parties in the case included the Petitioner, the Union Government and private platforms, WhatsApp and Facebook Inc. This case comes from an appeal against a Delhi High Court judgment last year, in a case where two students had filed a legal petition challenging the change in WhatsApp&amp;rsquo;s privacy policy which would allow data sharing with Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement of concern on the Sabu Mathew George Case : Don’t “auto-block” online expression</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/statement-of-concern-on-the-sabu-mathew-george-case-dont-auto-block-online-expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 12:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/statement-of-concern-on-the-sabu-mathew-george-case-dont-auto-block-online-expression/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court of India has over the past one year passed various orders in the case of Sabu Mathew George v. Union of India &amp;amp; Ors. [WP(C) 341/2008] that are undermining internet freedom, particularly the right of free expression online. The case concerns allegations that search engines are acting in contravention of S. 22 of the Pre-Conception and Pre-Natal Diagnostic Techniques (Prohibition of Sex Selection) Act (hereinafter referred to as “the Act”) insofar as they are showing results relating to sex determination kits and techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
