<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>cybersecurity on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/cybersecurity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cybersecurity on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 05:27:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/cybersecurity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IFF writes to the Parliamentary Standing Committee on IT on the “Bulli Bai” and “Sulli Deals” Incidents</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-writes-to-the-standing-committee-bulli-bai-and-sulli-deals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 05:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-writes-to-the-standing-committee-bulli-bai-and-sulli-deals/</guid>
      <description>The Mumbai and Delhi Police have arrested the perpetrators of the fake online auction of Muslim women. But what took so long? We wrote to the Standing Committee with a few recommendations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amina writes to the National Commission for Women and the Telangana State Women’s Commission against targeted harassment of Muslim Women</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-assists-amina-targeted-by-bulli-bai-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 08:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-assists-amina-targeted-by-bulli-bai-app/</guid>
      <description>After much furore around the Bulli Bai incident, some arrests have been made and the investigation is still pending. One of the victims of this incident wrote to the National Commission of Women and the Telangana State Women Commission seeking their intervention in ensuring fair investigation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over to you MeitY: IFF&#39;s representation on CERT-In&#39;s Responsible Vulnerability Disclosure and Coordination Policy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/over-to-you-meity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 05:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/over-to-you-meity/</guid>
      <description>CERT-In responded to our representation on the Responsible Vulnerability Disclosure and Coordination Policy and clarified that the Policy is following the existing provisions of the law. Therefore, now we ask MeitY to amend the law to provide a safe harbour for security researchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t penalise cybersecurity researchers!</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dont-penalise-cybersecurity-researchers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 06:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dont-penalise-cybersecurity-researchers/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to CERT-IN regarding their new Responsible Vulnerability Disclosure and Coordination Policy that penalises cybersecurity researchers for vulnerability disclosures. Such a policy would make researchers reluctant about reporting vulnerabilities and so a robust disclosure mechanism is needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#4 Cybersec Charcha: A Global overview of the state of surveillance after the pegasus revelations</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/4-cybersec-charcha-a-global-overview-of-the-state-of-surveillance-after-the-pegasus-revelations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 12:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/4-cybersec-charcha-a-global-overview-of-the-state-of-surveillance-after-the-pegasus-revelations/</guid>
      <description>Your monthly round-up of all things cybersecurity! This edition of Cybersec Charcha focuses on spyware, the Pegasus Project reports and the booming surveillance industry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
