<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Censorship on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/censorship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Censorship on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 05:49:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/censorship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Oxford Pro Bono Publico releases its report on the Regulation of Digital Media and Intermediaries</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/oxford-pro-bono-publico-releases-its-report-on-the-regulation-of-digital-media-and-intermediaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 05:49:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/oxford-pro-bono-publico-releases-its-report-on-the-regulation-of-digital-media-and-intermediaries/</guid>
      <description>To assist challenges to IT Rules, w​e reached out to Oxford Pro Bono Publico (OPBP) - a research centre at the Oxford University, requesting research on laws in other countries on social media platforms, digital news media and OTT platforms. OPBP has published their research report in December 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As the farmers’ protests saw widespread internet shutdowns, IFF wrote to the Haryana Home Ministry urging restraint</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/as-the-farmers-protests-see-widespread-internet-shutdowns-iff-writes-to-the-haryana-home-ministry-urging-restraint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 05:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/as-the-farmers-protests-see-widespread-internet-shutdowns-iff-writes-to-the-haryana-home-ministry-urging-restraint/</guid>
      <description>Between September 7 and 9, 2021, internet services were suspended in four districts of Haryana due to ongoing farmers’ protests. The order is not available on the Government websites and does not lay out a factual justification. We wrote to the Haryana government to officially publish all orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MeitY blocks information about Actor Sushant Singh’s account takedown</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/meity-blocks-information-about-actor-sushant-singhs-account-takedown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 12:47:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/meity-blocks-information-about-actor-sushant-singhs-account-takedown/</guid>
      <description>Twitter unilaterally and arbitrarily suspended the account of Sushant Singh (@sushant_says) twice, i.e. on February 1 and May 26, 2021. We helped him file RTI requests with the Meity, DoT and MHA. Meity invoked the 2009 Blocking Rules and the RTI Act to deny information to Mr. Singh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Tech releases its transparency reports in compliance with the IT Rules: Here’s what we found</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/big-tech-releases-its-transparency-reports-in-compliance-with-the-it-rules-heres-what-we-found/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 13:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/big-tech-releases-its-transparency-reports-in-compliance-with-the-it-rules-heres-what-we-found/</guid>
      <description>Google, Facebook, Instagram, WhatsApp and Twitter have released their transparency reports in compliance with Rule 4(1)(d) of the Information Technology (Guidelines for Intermediaries and Digital Media Ethics Code) Rules, 2021 (the 2021 IT Rules).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spooked by the Zombie? Ministry of Home Affairs issues notification directing all S.66A cases to stop</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/spooked-by-the-zombie-ministry-of-home-affairs-issues-notification-directing-all-s-66a-cases-to-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 10:52:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/spooked-by-the-zombie-ministry-of-home-affairs-issues-notification-directing-all-s-66a-cases-to-stop/</guid>
      <description>Prompted by our application, the Ministry of Home Affairs, on July 14, 2021 issued a notification directing all law enforcement authorities to stop registering new cases under Section 66A of the Information Technology Act, 2000 and to immediately withdraw all pending cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Was your handle blocked without warning? Here’s what you can do.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/was-your-handle-blocked-without-warning-heres-what-you-can-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/was-your-handle-blocked-without-warning-heres-what-you-can-do/</guid>
      <description>Incidents of arbitrary censorship of online speech have significantly risen  in the recent past. We are frequently asked what can be done if one’s account is blocked. We have prepared a step by step explainer to navigate situations of arbitrary account blockings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PUCL approaches Supreme Court seeking directions against continued prosecutions under the unconstitutional Section 66A</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/pucl-approaches-supreme-court-seeking-directions-against-continued-prosecutions-under-the-unconstitutional-section-66a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 07:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/pucl-approaches-supreme-court-seeking-directions-against-continued-prosecutions-under-the-unconstitutional-section-66a/</guid>
      <description>Supreme Court issues notice in PUCL&amp;rsquo;s application seeking directions against continued enforcement of Section 66A. IFF provided legal assistance to PUCL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter must apply its own policies transparently and consistently when suspending users’ accounts</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/twitter-must-apply-its-own-policies-transparently-and-consistently-when-suspending-users-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 04:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/twitter-must-apply-its-own-policies-transparently-and-consistently-when-suspending-users-accounts/</guid>
      <description>Twitter unilaterally and arbitrarily suspended the account of Sushant Singh (@sushant_says) twice. He sent a formal representation to Twitter highlighting issues with Twitter’s policies and actions, relating to transparency, free expression and consistency, and urged an open dialogue on its policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revealed: RTI Request uncovers MeitY letters to Twitter asking to remove the ‘manipulated media’ tag</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/revealed-rti-request-uncovers-meity-letters-to-twitter-asking-to-remove-the-manipulated-media-tag/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 05:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/revealed-rti-request-uncovers-meity-letters-to-twitter-asking-to-remove-the-manipulated-media-tag/</guid>
      <description>We were provided copies of two letters from MeitY to Twitter, which do not cite any provision of law, but have asked Twitter to refrain from implementing its policy and process of affixing the ‘Manipulated Media’ tag on tweets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madras High Court issues notice in petition challenging the Intermediary Rules 2021 by T. M. Krishna</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/madras-high-court-issues-notice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 05:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/madras-high-court-issues-notice/</guid>
      <description>Madras High issued notice on a writ petition by T.M. Krishna challenging the Intermediary Rules 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delhi Government’s gag order on information on mucormycosis</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/delhi-governments-gag-order-on-information-on-mucormycosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 06:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/delhi-governments-gag-order-on-information-on-mucormycosis/</guid>
      <description>Recently, the Delhi Government issued a notification prohibiting anyone from sharing any information on mucormycosis without the prior permission of the Government. IFF has sent the Government a legal notice urging it to rescind this overbroad order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MEITY has no legal basis to ask social media platforms to remove content in middle of India&#39;s COVID crisis!</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/meity-asks-social-media-platforms-to-remove-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 12:56:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/meity-asks-social-media-platforms-to-remove-content/</guid>
      <description>MEITY has written letters to social media platforms. These letters ask platforms to remove content. We write to MEITY asking them to withdraw these letters as they do not have a legal basis and they curb speech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indore Collector&#39;s welcome response - problematic paragraph repealed</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indore-collectors-welcome-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 16:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indore-collectors-welcome-response/</guid>
      <description>Today, in a major victory for online free speech, the Collector, Indore issued an order repealing paragraph 7 of Indore&amp;rsquo;s 144 order, and replacing it with clearer language, prohibiting only posts &amp;ldquo;that pose a danger to public peace, law and order, and health of the public&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indore administration curbs speech on social media</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indore-administration-curbs-speech-on-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 13:03:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indore-administration-curbs-speech-on-social-media/</guid>
      <description>Indore administration issued an over-broad order under Section 144(1) CrPC, 1973 banning speech related to Covid-19 on social media platforms. We have filed an application before the  Collector, Indore seeking withdrawal of the Order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MEITY responds to our representation to unblock Twitter accounts. Confirms orders and denies disclosure.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/meity-response-to-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 08:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/meity-response-to-representation/</guid>
      <description>In February, we had written to MeitY with regards to the blocking of Twitter accounts. MeitY responded to us recently, saying that they did nothing wrong. We have written back to the Ministry this week explaining how they are constitutionally required to disclose the blocking orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tandav is a Case Study for OTT censorship under the IT Rules, 2021 #LetUsChill</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/tandav-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 07:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/tandav-case-study/</guid>
      <description>Documents accessed through RTI paint a grim picture for creativity and diversity of content for online streaming platforms in India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#LetUsChill: Confusion and Opacity over OTT guidelines</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ott-transparency-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 13:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ott-transparency-representation/</guid>
      <description>The Ministry of Information &amp;amp; Broadcasting may be considering regulating online content on Over-The-Top (OTT) platforms. We wrote a letter to the Ministry, in which we detailed potential harms, asked for clarity, and requested a thorough implementation of the pre-legislative consultation policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Kanoon defends the right to provide access to court records</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indian-kanoon-kerala-hc-right-to-be-forgotten/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indian-kanoon-kerala-hc-right-to-be-forgotten/</guid>
      <description>In response to a petition filed before the Kerala HC, Indian Kanoon has clarified that a right to be forgotten cannot be judicially created without a statutory basis and explained that court records are public documents whose reproduction cannot be prohibited by citing the right to privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF intervenes in Madras HC PIL seeking censorship on online streaming platforms #LetUsChill</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-intervenes-madras-hc-pil-ott-regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 07:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-intervenes-madras-hc-pil-ott-regulation/</guid>
      <description>In the impleadment application, we have cautioned against judicial intervention at this stage because OTT regulation is a complex and technical issue best addressed through legislative and policy making processes involving extensive stakeholder consultation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Section 118A repeal important steps remain for the Government of Kerala</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/after-section-118a-repeals-important-steps-remain-for-the-government-of-kerala/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 08:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/after-section-118a-repeals-important-steps-remain-for-the-government-of-kerala/</guid>
      <description>Read our proposals to the Government of Kerala to help avoid any overbroad or unnecessary criminalisation of online speech while also making sure abuse, threats or any of the harms that emerge on social media can be checked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement: Today’s notification on online news media and OTT platforms will require greater vigilance #LetUsChill</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-on-online-news-media-and-ott-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 11:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-on-online-news-media-and-ott-platforms/</guid>
      <description>The Central Government has notified the Ministry of Information and Broadcasting (MIB) as having jurisdiction over online news and also OTT video streaming platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over 240 lawyers urge Twitter to re-instate Prashant Bhushan&#39;s tweets #FreeToMeme</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/joint-letter-to-twitter-about-removal-of-prashant-bhushan-tweets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 05:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/joint-letter-to-twitter-about-removal-of-prashant-bhushan-tweets/</guid>
      <description>Today, 243 lawyers including senior advocates wrote to Twitter Inc. seeking reinstatement of Mr. Prashant Bhushan&amp;rsquo;s tweets which became the subject of contempt of court proceedings before the Supreme Court of India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIFT&#39;s Social Media Policy, 2020 violates the Right to Freedom of Speech and Expression</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/nifts-social-media-policy-2020-violates-the-right-to-freedom-of-speech-and-expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 07:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/nifts-social-media-policy-2020-violates-the-right-to-freedom-of-speech-and-expression/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the Director General of NIFT as well as the Ministry of Textiles asking them to recall the policy which hampers the right to freedom of speech and expression of the students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding app bans with a nuanced policy approach #WhatTheBlock</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/app-ban-guidelines-policy-recommendations-to-meity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 04:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/app-ban-guidelines-policy-recommendations-to-meity/</guid>
      <description>The Government is looking to strengthen its stance on banning mobile apps. It is planning to come out with guidelines, flouting which any app can be banned. We feel that such wide scale banning operations undermine your digital rights. So, we wrote to them urging them to rethink the move.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on IFF’s Zombie Tracker</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/update-on-zombie-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 08:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/update-on-zombie-tracker/</guid>
      <description>IFF, in collaboration with CivicDataLab, is building a “Zombie Tracker” to track cases under S. 66A, Information Technology Act, at the district level. S.66A of the IT Act is termed as a legal zombie since, even though it was declared unconstitutional in 2015, its use is ongoing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MeitY defends blocking of satirical Dowry Calculator website #FreeToMeme</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/meity-defends-blocking-of-satirical-dowry-calculator-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 05:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/meity-defends-blocking-of-satirical-dowry-calculator-website/</guid>
      <description>MeitY&amp;rsquo;s response to Tanul Thakur&amp;rsquo;s petition against the blocking of his Dowry Calculator website demonstrates lack of understanding of satire and non compliance with principles of natural justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read our follow up letter to Justice A.P. Shah on self-censorship by Hotstar and the IAMAI’s self regulation code #LetUsChill</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/read-our-follow-up-letter-to-justice-a-p-shah-on-self-censorship-by-hotstar-and-the-iamais-self-regulation-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 03:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/read-our-follow-up-letter-to-justice-a-p-shah-on-self-censorship-by-hotstar-and-the-iamais-self-regulation-code/</guid>
      <description>IFF has written to Justice AP Shah and the Internet and Mobile Association of India (IAMAI). In it we have expressed our concerns of self censorship by Hotstar and pressure by Government to get the entire online content industry to follow the IAMAI&amp;rsquo;s Code for Self-Regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF writes to the Delhi Committee for Peace and Harmony on their social media crackdown #FreeToMeme</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-writes-to-the-delhi-committee-for-peace-and-harmony-on-their-social-media-crackdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 12:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-writes-to-the-delhi-committee-for-peace-and-harmony-on-their-social-media-crackdown/</guid>
      <description>The Delhi Government constituted a Committee for Peace and Harmony to investigate hateful content and fake news over social media. As it stands it will enable over censorship and chilling effect. IFF has written a letter to the Committee’s chairperson along with Delhi CM Arvind Kejriwal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An open letter to Justice A.P. Shah on the online video self-regulatory code</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/a-gentle-open-letter-to-justice-a-p-shah-on-the-online-video-self-regulatory-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 18:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/a-gentle-open-letter-to-justice-a-p-shah-on-the-online-video-self-regulatory-code/</guid>
      <description>We write a letter to Justice Shah placing our concerns on the online video streaming self-regulatory body that he has been reported to head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online video streaming and TV are not the same. So why is the IAMAI trying to make it so?</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/online-video-streaming-and-tv-are-not-the-same-so-why-is-the-iamai-trying-to-make-it-so/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 11:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/online-video-streaming-and-tv-are-not-the-same-so-why-is-the-iamai-trying-to-make-it-so/</guid>
      <description>The Internet and Mobile Association of India (IAMAI) launched a self-regulation code for online video streaming platforms. We have written to IAMAI asking them to roll it back since it is a precursor to self-censorship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Journalists Union defends media&#39;s right to report on MeToo allegations</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indian-journalists-union-defends-right-of-journalists-to-report-on-metoo-allegations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 06:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indian-journalists-union-defends-right-of-journalists-to-report-on-metoo-allegations/</guid>
      <description>In the latest hearing in Subodh Gupta&amp;rsquo;s defamation suit, IJU emphasized that news reports cannot be de-indexed without providing the journalists a hearing and argued there was a distinction between merely republishing defamatory allegations and reporting on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Young Indians are mature enough to have a conversation on porn. Parliamentary Committee should invite further inputs.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/porn-is-complex-we-call-for-further-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 04:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/porn-is-complex-we-call-for-further-study/</guid>
      <description>We made submissions to the ad-hoc committee constituted to study the impact of porn on social media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A &#39;Certifiable&#39; Dampener: The Ministry of Information and Broadcasting wants certification of online viewing content.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/a-certifiable-dampener/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 06:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/a-certifiable-dampener/</guid>
      <description>The Ministry of Information and Broadcasting brings back into the discussion certification of online viewing content. We write on the need for a transparent and public consultation and highlight concerns with certification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is porn being blocked in India? #WhatTheBlock</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/why-is-porn-being-blocked-in-india-whattheblock/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 06:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/why-is-porn-being-blocked-in-india-whattheblock/</guid>
      <description>RTI response from MeitY reveals that blocking of porn in India is a result of three court orders and ISPs have not been directed to pro-actively block porn websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vanakkam! Updates on the Aadhaar-social media linkage and encryption PIL before the Madras HC</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/vanakkam-updates-on-the-aadhaar-social-media-linkage-and-encryption-pil-before-the-madras-hc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 09:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/vanakkam-updates-on-the-aadhaar-social-media-linkage-and-encryption-pil-before-the-madras-hc/</guid>
      <description>At today&amp;rsquo;s hearing, IFF placed on record its written submissions highlighting how proposed changes to the product design of social media platforms would harm user privacy and lead to over-broad automated censorship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tale of Rogue Pirates, Ashok Kumars and ISPs caught in the middle: RTI data on court ordered website blocking reveals worrying trends  #WhatTheBlock</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/a-tale-of-rogue-pirates-ashok-kumars-and-isps-caught-in-the-middle-rti-data-on-court-ordered-website-blocking-reveals-worrying-trends-whattheblock/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 07:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/a-tale-of-rogue-pirates-ashok-kumars-and-isps-caught-in-the-middle-rti-data-on-court-ordered-website-blocking-reveals-worrying-trends-whattheblock/</guid>
      <description>RTI data reveals that 31 court orders in IP infringement cases have led to blocking of thousands of websites. Most of these orders have been passed ex parte and permit blocking of the whole website rather than specific URLs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing out the big guns. Justice for Rights appeals.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-appeal-to-an-appeal-justice-for-rights-goes-to-court-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 10:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-appeal-to-an-appeal-justice-for-rights-goes-to-court-again/</guid>
      <description>A Special Leave Petition was filed by the Justice for Rights foundation in the Supreme Court of India against the decision of the Delhi High Court on regulation of content on online viewing platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One down, three to go!</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/one-down-two-to-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 12:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/one-down-two-to-go/</guid>
      <description>The Hon&amp;rsquo;ble High Court of Delhi applies the well-reasoned judgement of the Justice for Rights case in dismissing Nikhil Bhalla&amp;rsquo;s plea for guidelines to regulate online streaming content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An alternative to bans. A Letter to MEITY.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/an-alternative-to-bans-a-letter-to-meity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 13:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/an-alternative-to-bans-a-letter-to-meity/</guid>
      <description>In a letter written to MEITY, IFF reasons the need for alternative measures to addressing the safety of minors instead of resorting to disproportionate bans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement on the TikTok Ban</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-on-the-tic-tok-ban/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 04:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-on-the-tic-tok-ban/</guid>
      <description>We are in the process of conferring with legal counsel and will be taking steps to ensure that the fundamental rights of internet users are considered by the Hon’ble Court. As with all of IFF’s work, subsequent steps and updates will be informed regularly and transparently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Section 66A returns to its grave after accidental resurrection.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/section-66a-returns-to-its-grave-leaving-us-to-netflix-and-chill-in-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 09:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/section-66a-returns-to-its-grave-leaving-us-to-netflix-and-chill-in-peace/</guid>
      <description>The Delhi High Court today promptly agreed to remove an inadvertent reference to the unconstitutional Section 66A in its judgement rejecting censorship of online platforms like Netflix and Amazon Prime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Appeal: Please, do not jail PUBG users.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/please-do-not-jail-pugb-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 09:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/please-do-not-jail-pugb-users/</guid>
      <description>As per media reports which surfaced yesterday the Rajkot Police Department has arrested 7 youths for playing the PUBG online video game. Clearly things have spiralled out of control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the block! Our net neutrality rules require a monitoring and enforcement structure #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/what-the-block-our-net-neutrality-rules-require-a-monitoring-and-enforcement-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 05:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/what-the-block-our-net-neutrality-rules-require-a-monitoring-and-enforcement-structure/</guid>
      <description>A particularly concerning threat to net neutrality, looms the web. IFF has been engaging with users for a few months gathering evidence of extensive blocking. We summarise this to you and explain how this is a violation of Net Neutrality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need for urgent steps on a fresh petition for censorship of Online Video Streaming websites.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/here-we-go-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 07:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/here-we-go-again/</guid>
      <description>In yet another PIL filed in the Karnataka High Court, a plea has been placed for the regulation of online viewing content. We write to MEITY and MIB to maintain their positive stance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too many cooks won&#39;t spoil this broth. Need for larger participation by the Parliamentary Committee on IT.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/too-many-cooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 09:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/too-many-cooks/</guid>
      <description>As the Parliamentary Committee on Information Technology widens the ambit of its hearings to other online platforms, we ask them to ensure the inclusion of civil society organisations, academics and experts. We also raise some questions regarding the criteria and scope of these hearings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks to the Delhi High Court for letting us Netflix and chill!</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/take-it-and-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 04:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/take-it-and-go/</guid>
      <description>The Delhi High Court dismissed a PIL asking for TV style censorship on online video streaming services such as netflix, hotstar and amazon prime. We call for further steps by Government to extend this victory!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need for the Parliamentary Committee on IT to broaden participation and move towards outcomes</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/need-for-the-parliamentary-committee-on-it-to-broaden-participation-and-move-towards-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 09:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/need-for-the-parliamentary-committee-on-it-to-broaden-participation-and-move-towards-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>Next week the Parliamentary Committee on IT will hold a hearing on, ‘Safeguarding citizens’ data on social/online news media platforms’. It invites Government officials &amp;amp; Twitter. Public participation is necessary on this vital issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We urge MEITY to press reboot on the Intermediary Rules #SaveOurPrivacy #RightToMeme</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-urge-meity-to-press-reboot-on-the-intermediary-rules-saveourprivacy-righttomeme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 07:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-urge-meity-to-press-reboot-on-the-intermediary-rules-saveourprivacy-righttomeme/</guid>
      <description>We urge MEITY to recall the Draft of “The Information Technology [Intermediary Guidelines (Amendment) Rules] 2018 and then start afresh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We urge for a rethink on the proposed self-censorship norms for video streaming platforms</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-urge-a-rethink-on-the-proposed-self-censorship-for-video-streaming-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 05:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-urge-a-rethink-on-the-proposed-self-censorship-for-video-streaming-platforms/</guid>
      <description>A new proposal for self-censorship for online streaming platforms is being privately considered for endorsement by the Government. It is likely to lead to greater censorship and throttle creativity and freedom of speech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement of concern on the Sabu Mathew George Case : Don’t “auto-block” online expression</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-of-concern-on-the-sabu-mathew-george-case-dont-auto-block-online-expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 12:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-of-concern-on-the-sabu-mathew-george-case-dont-auto-block-online-expression/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court of India has over the past one year passed various orders in the case of Sabu Mathew George v. Union of India &amp;amp; Ors. [WP(C) 341/2008] that are undermining internet freedom, particularly the right of free expression online. The case concerns allegations that search engines are acting in contravention of S. 22 of the Pre-Conception and Pre-Natal Diagnostic Techniques (Prohibition of Sex Selection) Act (hereinafter referred to as “the Act”) insofar as they are showing results relating to sex determination kits and techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
