<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Submission on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/categories/submission/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Submission on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:03:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/categories/submission/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ensuring Equity, Accessibility and Transparency in Court: Our Comments on the Supreme Court&#39;s Draft Vision Document</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ensuring-equity-accessibility-and-transparency-in-court-our-comments-on-the-supreme-courts-draft-vision-document/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ensuring-equity-accessibility-and-transparency-in-court-our-comments-on-the-supreme-courts-draft-vision-document/</guid>
      <description>Read our comments pursuant to the Draft Vision &amp;amp; Roadmap for Phase III of the eCourts Project released by the The eCommittee of the Supreme Court for consultation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Protection and the National Population Register #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/data-protection-and-the-national-population-register/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 11:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/data-protection-and-the-national-population-register/</guid>
      <description>IFF&amp;rsquo;s brief highlights how NPR violates data protection principles of lawfulness, consent, purpose limitation, data minimization and accountability. Based on this case study, the brief identifies various loopholes in the PDP Bill and recommends necessary changes to the Joint Parliamentary Committee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say no to overregulation of digital news media</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/say-no-to-overregulation-of-digital-news-media-and-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 12:29:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/say-no-to-overregulation-of-digital-news-media-and-social-media/</guid>
      <description>In its current form, the RPP Bill is plagued by definitional confusion and lack of a clearly stated purpose. We urge the government to start from a clean slate by publishing a whitepaper and conducting public consultation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We must prevent cloud cartels.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-must-prevent-cloud-cartel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-must-prevent-cloud-cartel/</guid>
      <description>The TRAI invited comments on a consultation paper that suggested a framework for the registration of industry bodies for cloud services. We make our submission with concerns of jurisdiction, cartelisation and self-regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF submits comments to the Standing Committee on Science &amp; Tech highlighting worries with the DNA Bill, 2019.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/i-just-took-a-dna-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 05:32:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/i-just-took-a-dna-test/</guid>
      <description>The DNA Bill has been re-introduced in the Lok Sabha and also referred to the Standing Committee on Science and Technology which has invited comments. We had a lot of comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urgent speech law reform needed to protect online freedom in India.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/urgent-speech-law-reform-needed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 11:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/urgent-speech-law-reform-needed/</guid>
      <description>With the formation of the new Government and our best foot forward, we call upon the Central Government to take steps to address the arbitrary arrests of social media users and pursue the reform of speech law in India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blocking of satirical dowry calculator website prompts us to take action! #WhatTheBlock #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/blocking-of-satirical-dowry-calculator-website-prompts-us-to-take-action-whattheblock-savetheinternet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 09:10:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/blocking-of-satirical-dowry-calculator-website-prompts-us-to-take-action-whattheblock-savetheinternet/</guid>
      <description>The blocking of Dowry Calculator is characteristic of India&amp;rsquo;s outrage driven and opaque website blocking process. We write to MEITY for public disclosure of all website blocking orders and deletion of the confidentiality requirement in the IT Blocking Rules 2009.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting India’s WiFi</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/troubleshooting-indias-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/troubleshooting-indias-wifi/</guid>
      <description>A recently-closed consultation paper by the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) explored how public WiFi could bring high-speed Internet to a large number of unconnected Indians. The Internet Freedom Foundation regards this as a very important issue and we have formally submitted our inputs to this consultation; this post explains our position.
In the consultation paper, TRAI pointed out that our country has woefully few public WiFi hotspots, even compared to other countries far smaller than ours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF Comments on the Draft Geospatial  Information Regulation Bill, 2016</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-comments-on-the-draft-geospatial-information-regulation-bill-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-comments-on-the-draft-geospatial-information-regulation-bill-2016/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year, the Ministry of Home Affairs to the Government of India put out a draft bill for comment - the Geospatial Information Regulation Bill, 2016.
As an organisation, one of IFF&amp;rsquo;s core areas is promoting an Internet which preserves freedom for users, designers, scholars and entrepreneurs. Such freedom today is being exercised by most users to generate and contribute geospatial information. Every Indian today with a smartphone is a cartographer who is helping map and digitise India.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
