<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>internet shutdowns on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/internet-shutdowns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in internet shutdowns on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 07:12:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/internet-shutdowns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IFF provides inputs to UN on Internet Shutdowns</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ohchr-internet-shutdowns-submission/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 07:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ohchr-internet-shutdowns-submission/</guid>
      <description>The submission to United Nations analyses the legal basis of internet shutdowns in India, the instances of disruptions, their impact on human rights and the efforts by the Indian Government to improve internet connectivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gauhati HC allows IFF&#39;s intervention application in petition challenging the constitutionality of internet shutdown rules #KeepItOn</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/gauhati-hc-internet-shutdown-rules-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 09:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/gauhati-hc-internet-shutdown-rules-update/</guid>
      <description>At a hearing dated January 31, 2022, IFF&amp;rsquo;s intervention application challenging the Telecom Suspension Rules, 2017 has been allowed by the Gauhati High Court, and IFF has been impleaded in the case. IFF is now allowed to assist the Court with oral and written submissions in the proceedings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A challenge to internet shutdown rules: Gauhati HC agrees to hear IFF&#39;s application</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/gauhati-hc-intervention/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 08:25:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/gauhati-hc-intervention/</guid>
      <description>Gauhati High Court agreed to hear IFF&amp;rsquo;s application question rules which empower the government to suspend internet services without any judicial/independent oversight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concerned with frequent internet suspensions, Parliamentary Committee recommends an overhaul.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/concerned-with-frequent-internet-suspensions-parliamentary-committee-recommends-an-overhaul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 08:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/concerned-with-frequent-internet-suspensions-parliamentary-committee-recommends-an-overhaul/</guid>
      <description>The Standing Committee on IT has published its report on ‘Suspension of telecom services/internet and its impact’. The report has a range of recommendations including a review of the legal regime for suspension of internet services and establishing a database of internet shutdown orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Revealed] Jaipur Internet Shutdown Orders: Cut, Copy, Paste!</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/revealed-jaipur-internet-shutdown-orders-cut-copy-paste-keep-it-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 09:22:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/revealed-jaipur-internet-shutdown-orders-cut-copy-paste-keep-it-on/</guid>
      <description>We filed RTI applications to determine the extent of the Rajasthan government’s compliance with directions in Anuradha Bhasin. We have received a response from the Jaipur DC, who issued 30 Internet shutdown orders, which follow an identical copy, cut, paste format — same as Udaipur!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for October 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-october-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 05:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-october-2021/</guid>
      <description>Since our last report for the month of September, IFF has filed 49 RTI requests. Here is an overview of the requests filed and an analysis of the responses we have received from the different public authorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Revealed] Udaipur Internet Shutdown Orders: Cut, Copy, Paste!</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/revealed-udaipur-internet-shutdown-orders-cut-copy-paste/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 04:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/revealed-udaipur-internet-shutdown-orders-cut-copy-paste/</guid>
      <description>We filed Right to Information applications to determine the extent of compliance with directions in Anuradha Bhasin. We found that the office of the Udaipur Divisional Commissioner has issued 26 internet shutdown orders, most of which are similar!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The internet cannot be suspended in entire districts to prevent cheating in exams - IFF writes to the Rajasthan Government.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-internet-cannot-be-suspended-in-entire-districts-to-prevent-cheating-in-exams-iff-writes-to-the-rajasthan-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 04:46:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-internet-cannot-be-suspended-in-entire-districts-to-prevent-cheating-in-exams-iff-writes-to-the-rajasthan-government/</guid>
      <description>IFF writes to the officers of the Rajasthan Government expressing concerns about the unlawful, unnecessary, disproportionate and improperly ordered internet shutdowns on September 26, 2021, purportedly ordered to prevent cheating in the Rajasthan Eligibility Exam for Teachers 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As the farmers’ protests saw widespread internet shutdowns, IFF wrote to the Haryana Home Ministry urging restraint</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/as-the-farmers-protests-see-widespread-internet-shutdowns-iff-writes-to-the-haryana-home-ministry-urging-restraint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 05:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/as-the-farmers-protests-see-widespread-internet-shutdowns-iff-writes-to-the-haryana-home-ministry-urging-restraint/</guid>
      <description>Between September 7 and 9, 2021, internet services were suspended in four districts of Haryana due to ongoing farmers’ protests. The order is not available on the Government websites and does not lay out a factual justification. We wrote to the Haryana government to officially publish all orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ahead of its visit to J&amp;K, IFF apprised the Parliamentary Standing Committee on IT of repeated internet shutdowns</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ahead-of-its-visit-to-j-k-iff-apprised-the-parliamentary-standing-committee-on-it-of-repeated-internet-shutdowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 11:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ahead-of-its-visit-to-j-k-iff-apprised-the-parliamentary-standing-committee-on-it-of-repeated-internet-shutdowns/</guid>
      <description>We addressed a letter to the Parliamentary Standing Committee on Information Technology, travelling to Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir (J&amp;amp;K). The letter highlighted that the government was shutting down the internet in J&amp;amp;K without complying with the Supreme Court’s directions in Anuradha Bhasin vs Union of India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet shutdown in Meghalaya without suspension order!</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/meghalaya-stays-without-internet-for-three-days-but-the-govt-is-yet-to-publish-an-order-of-suspension/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 09:34:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/meghalaya-stays-without-internet-for-three-days-but-the-govt-is-yet-to-publish-an-order-of-suspension/</guid>
      <description>Since August 15, 2021, internet services have been suspended in four districts of Meghalaya due to ongoing civil unrest. We wrote to the Meghalaya government to publish all orders related to the current internet shutdowns as well as proactively publish any subsequent internet shutdown orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundation for Media Professionals writes to J&amp;K Govt seeking compliance with Anuradha Bhasin</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/foundation-for-media-professionals-writes-to-j-k-govt-seeking-compliance-with-anuradha-bhasin-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 07:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/foundation-for-media-professionals-writes-to-j-k-govt-seeking-compliance-with-anuradha-bhasin-2/</guid>
      <description>In May 2021 the Government of J&amp;amp;K suspended internet services on three occasions, without promptly publishing suspensions orders. Foundation of Media Professionals has addressed a legal notice to the Government of J&amp;amp;K asking them to comply with directions of the Supreme Court in Anuradha Bhasin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rajasthan Government Must Fix Its Internet Shutdown Problem #KeepItOn</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/rajasthan-govt-internet-shutdown-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 06:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/rajasthan-govt-internet-shutdown-representation/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the Rajasthan Government expressing concerns about unauthorised government officials imposing internet shutdowns and lack of periodic review and proactive publication of internet shutdown orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement on long overdue 4G mobile internet restoration in Jammu &amp; Kashmir after 550 days #KeepItOn</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-j-k-4g-restoration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 06:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-j-k-4g-restoration/</guid>
      <description>No citizen of a democracy should have to suffer through what the people of Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir experienced and we will keep pushing for broader internet shutdown reform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint statement against internet shutdowns to suppress farmers&#39; protests #KeepItOn</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/joint-statement-internet-shutdown-farmers-protests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 07:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/joint-statement-internet-shutdown-farmers-protests/</guid>
      <description>IFF along with FSMI and SFLC.in raises alarm about the use of internet shutdowns to undermine the fundamental right to peaceful protest. Such internet shutdowns will only increase the risk of violence and misinformation and they cannot be considered necessary or proportionate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for January, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-january-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 07:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-january-2021/</guid>
      <description>Read more about RTI work for the month of January, 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for December, 2020</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iffs-right-to-information-report-for-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 04:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iffs-right-to-information-report-for-december/</guid>
      <description>In this monthly series, we aim to provide information about how our RTI work is carried out and utilised to demand transparency and accountability from public authorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As internet restrictions in J&amp;K cross 480 days, we await SC judgement #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/non-publication-of-internet-shutdown-review-orders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 07:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/non-publication-of-internet-shutdown-review-orders/</guid>
      <description>Non-publication of orders issued by the Review Committee and Special Committee continues to remain a problem in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir which must be decided by the Supreme Court to ensure independent application of mind by these bodies and implementation of their recommendations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amendment to the Telecom Suspension Rules offers little protection against arbitrary and prolonged internet shutdowns #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/telecom-suspension-rules-amendment-15-day-time-limit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 11:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/telecom-suspension-rules-amendment-15-day-time-limit/</guid>
      <description>The central government&amp;rsquo;s recent amendment to the Telecom Suspension Rules will have limited utility and represents a missed opportunity for wider reform because it fails to incorporate directions issued by the SC requiring proactive publication and periodic review of internet shutdown orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTI responses from Andhra Pradesh and Gujarat show compliance failure with the Anuradha Bhasin Internet Shutdown decision</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/rti-responses-from-andhra-pradesh-and-gujarat-show-compliance-failure-with-the-anuradha-bhasin-internet-shutdown-decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/rti-responses-from-andhra-pradesh-and-gujarat-show-compliance-failure-with-the-anuradha-bhasin-internet-shutdown-decision/</guid>
      <description>11 months on from the Supreme Court&amp;rsquo;s decision on internet shutdowns in the matter of Anuradha Bhasin v Union of India, there is still no compliance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTI responses from MP and Meghalaya show compliance failure with the Anuradha Bhasin Internet Shutdown decision</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/rti-responses-from-mp-and-meghalaya-show-compliance-failure-with-the-anuradha-bhasin-internet-shutdown-decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 04:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/rti-responses-from-mp-and-meghalaya-show-compliance-failure-with-the-anuradha-bhasin-internet-shutdown-decision/</guid>
      <description>Nine months after the Supreme Court&amp;rsquo;s decision on internet shutdowns in the matter of Anuradha Bhasin v Union of India, there is still no compliance with the Court&amp;rsquo;s decision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Govt agrees to staggered restoration of 4G mobile internet  in J&amp;K before the Supreme Court #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/staggered-4g-restoration-j-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 08:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/staggered-4g-restoration-j-k/</guid>
      <description>During today&amp;rsquo;s hearing in Foundation for Media Professionals&#39; contempt petition relating to the internet restrictions in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir, the government agreed to restore 4G mobile internet in one district of Jammu and Kashmir each on a trial basis after 15 August i.e. Independence Day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement and a Call to Action to the Standing Committee on IT on the One Year Anniversary of Internet Restrictions in J&amp;K #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-j-k-internet-restrictions-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 04:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-j-k-internet-restrictions-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>No citizen of a 21st century democracy should have to live in digital darkness for over a year. Read IFF&amp;rsquo;s statement and call to action to the Parliamentary Standing Committee on IT on the  anniversary of the communication shutdown imposed in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir on 05 August 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FMP files rejoinder before SC about Jammu &amp; Kashmir 4G mobile internet ban #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/fmp-contempt-petition-rejoinder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 08:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/fmp-contempt-petition-rejoinder/</guid>
      <description>During today&amp;rsquo;s hearing before the Supreme Court, the Solicitor General sought an adjournment to go through FMP&amp;rsquo;s rejoinder which challenges secrecy in the functioning of the Special Committee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supreme Court directs Govt to file its reply in FMP&#39;s contempt petition #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/fmp-contempt-petition-reply/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 09:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/fmp-contempt-petition-reply/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court has directed the Government to file its reply in a contempt petition relating to the 4G mobile internet ban in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 months after Anuradha Bhasin v. UoI, state governments are still not publishing internet shutdown orders #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/publication-internet-shutdown-orders/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 12:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/publication-internet-shutdown-orders/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to DoT and State Governments of Madhya Pradesh, Meghalaya, Uttar Pradesh and West Bengal seeking proactive publication of internet shutdown orders in accordance with Anuradha Bhasin v. Union of India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FMP demands compliance with SC directions by Special Committee for restoration of 4G in J&amp;K #KeepUsOnline #4GforAll</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/fmp-demands-compliance-with-sc-judgement-by-special-committee-for-restoration-of-4g-in-j-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 10:36:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/fmp-demands-compliance-with-sc-judgement-by-special-committee-for-restoration-of-4g-in-j-k/</guid>
      <description>FMP wrote to the Special Committee established by the Supreme Court seeking immediate review of internet restrictions in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir within 7 working days and publication of the Committee&amp;rsquo;s recommendations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FMP approaches Special Committee established by SC for restoration of 4G internet in J&amp;K #KeepUsOnline #4GforAll</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/fmp-approaches-special-committee-established-by-sc-for-restoration-of-4g-internet-in-j-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 05:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/fmp-approaches-special-committee-established-by-sc-for-restoration-of-4g-internet-in-j-k/</guid>
      <description>Foundation for Media Professionals wrote to the Special Committee emphasising that blanket orders cannot be issued to indiscriminately slow down internet services in all districts of Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir especially since there are less restrictive alternatives available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supreme Court reserves order in petitions seeking restoration of 4G internet in Jammu &amp; Kashmir</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/sc-reserves-judgement-in-petitions-for-4g-restoration-in-j-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 11:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/sc-reserves-judgement-in-petitions-for-4g-restoration-in-j-k/</guid>
      <description>Today, the Supreme Court heard substantive arguments regarding the constitutionality and legality of the internet slowdown in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir during the COVID-19 pandemic and reserved its order in the matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Write to DoT and TRAI to Improve Internet Access and Protect Net Neutrality During COVID-19 #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-write-to-dot-and-trai-to-improve-internet-access-and-protect-net-neutrality-during-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 08:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-write-to-dot-and-trai-to-improve-internet-access-and-protect-net-neutrality-during-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>IFF has written to the DoT and TRAI suggesting that government interventions must look toward overcoming the digital divide, appreciating the importance of the internet and mobile services as an essential utility, and protect net neutrality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supreme Court directs Govt to file reply to petition seeking restoration of 4G internet in J&amp;K #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/supreme-court-directs-govt-to-file-reply-to-petition-seeking-4g-restoration-in-j-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 08:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/supreme-court-directs-govt-to-file-reply-to-petition-seeking-4g-restoration-in-j-k/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court has directed the Government to file its response to petitions seeking restoration of 4G internet in J&amp;amp;K by Sunday i.e. 26 April and the matter will be listed again next Monday i.e. 27 April.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SC issues notice in FMP’s petition seeking restoration of 4G internet services in Jammu &amp; Kashmir during COVID-19 crisis #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/sc-issues-notice-in-fmps-petition-seeking-restoration-of-4g-internet-services-in-jammu-kashmir-during-covid-19-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 09:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/sc-issues-notice-in-fmps-petition-seeking-restoration-of-4g-internet-services-in-jammu-kashmir-during-covid-19-crisis/</guid>
      <description>Today, a 3 judge bench of the Supreme Court issued notice in a petition filed by Foundation for Media Professionals against the internet slowdown in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir during the COVID-19 crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can’t Drop the Ball on Internet Shutdown Reform #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/cant-drop-the-ball-on-internet-shutdown-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 05:38:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/cant-drop-the-ball-on-internet-shutdown-reform/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the Department of Telecommunications and the Ministry of Parliamentary Affairs urging for review of the Telecom Suspension Rules 2017 based on public consultation and economic impact assessment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet slowdown in Jammu and Kashmir could cost lives during COVID 19 pandemic #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/internet-slowdown-in-jammu-and-kashmir-could-cost-lives-during-covid-19-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 05:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/internet-slowdown-in-jammu-and-kashmir-could-cost-lives-during-covid-19-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>IFF wrote to the Jammu and Kashmir Government and Ministry of Home Affairs seeking restoration of 4G internet services in Kashmir during the COVID 19 crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the Block?! IFF has heard your complaints and is taking action #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/what-the-block-iff-has-heard-your-complaints-and-is-taking-action-savetheinternet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 03:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/what-the-block-iff-has-heard-your-complaints-and-is-taking-action-savetheinternet/</guid>
      <description>IFF received multiple complaints of irregular website blocking by ISPs in Bengaluru and Hyderabad. The ISPs, namely ACT and BSNL, said they received directions from the DoT. Since this appears to be a network neutrality violation, IFF has written to the DoT and TRAI to look into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The J&amp;K Govt cannot ban Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-j-k-govt-cannot-ban-virtual-private-networks-vpns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-j-k-govt-cannot-ban-virtual-private-networks-vpns/</guid>
      <description>Internet Freedom Foundation wrote to the Home Department of Jammu and Kashmir and key central government departments about the unlawful blocking of access to virtual private networks (VPNs) in J&amp;amp;K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing cheating in exams is not a valid reason to shut down the Internet #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/preventing-cheating-in-exams-is-not-a-valid-reason-to-shut-down-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 07:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/preventing-cheating-in-exams-is-not-a-valid-reason-to-shut-down-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the West Bengal Government to apprise them that measures to suspend internet services to prevent cheating in exams is illegal</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundation for Media Professionals approaches J&amp;K Govt seeking compliance with SC judgement</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/foundation-for-media-professionals-approaches-j-k-govt-seeking-compliance-with-sc-judgement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 12:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/foundation-for-media-professionals-approaches-j-k-govt-seeking-compliance-with-sc-judgement/</guid>
      <description>FMP writes to Govt of Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir demanding compliance with the guidelines laid down by the Supreme Court and highlighting unconstitutionality and technical infeasibility of a whitelisting regime of internet censorship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SC&#39;s Kashmir communication shutdown judgement is just the beginning of a long uphill campaign</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/scs-judgement-on-kashmir-communication-is-just-the-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 14:17:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/scs-judgement-on-kashmir-communication-is-just-the-beginning/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court&amp;rsquo;s judgement in Anuradha Bhasin v. Union of India is a step in the right direction but fails to provide immediate relief to Kashmiris who have already suffered immense hardship due to the 158 day communication shutdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MHA and DOT need to issue advisories against Internet Shutdowns.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/an-advisory-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 12:06:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/an-advisory-on/</guid>
      <description>We write to the MHA and the DOT on the urgent need for an advisory against disruptions of internet services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement against Internet Shutdowns in the North East</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-on-internet-shutdowns-in-the-north-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 06:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-on-internet-shutdowns-in-the-north-east/</guid>
      <description>Internet shutdowns are a pan-India problem and there is no conclusive evidence that they prevent violence. We urge the Central Government to consider issuing an advisory on the frequent use of internet disruptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rajasthan internet shutdown orders continue to be issued by unauthorized officials</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/rajasthan-internet-shutdown-orders-continue-to-be-passed-by-unauthorized-officials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 11:51:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/rajasthan-internet-shutdown-orders-continue-to-be-passed-by-unauthorized-officials/</guid>
      <description>Rajasthan internet shutdown orders continue to be issued by Divisional Commissioners who lack authority to suspend telecom services. Further, many orders were issued in circumstances which do not seem to satisfy the public emergency/public safety requirement under the law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap Part II: Kashmir Communication Shutdown and Movement Restrictions Cases</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/recap-part-ii-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-movement-restrictions-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 12:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/recap-part-ii-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-movement-restrictions-cases/</guid>
      <description>Part II of the Recap summarizes arguments made by the petitioners and the government about the constitutional validity of the communication shutdown and movement restrictions in Kashmir under Articles 19 and 21 of the Constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap Part I: Kashmir Communication Shutdown and Movement Restrictions Cases</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/recap-part-i-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-movement-restrictions-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 05:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/recap-part-i-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-movement-restrictions-cases/</guid>
      <description>Part I of the Recap summarizes the arguments made by the petitioners and the government about statutory compliance of the orders issued under the Telecom Suspension Rules 2017 and Section 144, Cr.P.C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government says judicial review of severity of the restrictions in Kashmir during August is an “academic exercise”</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/government-says-judicial-review-of-severity-of-the-restrictions-in-kashmir-during-august-is-an-academic-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 14:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/government-says-judicial-review-of-severity-of-the-restrictions-in-kashmir-during-august-is-an-academic-exercise/</guid>
      <description>In yesterday&amp;rsquo;s hearing, the Solicitor General argued that the telecom shutdown was necessary because digital platforms could be used for mobilisation by terrorists and separatists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journalistic bodies oppose communication and movement restrictions in Kashmir before the Supreme Court</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/journalistic-bodies-oppose-communication-and-movement-restrictions-in-kashmir-before-the-supreme-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 07:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/journalistic-bodies-oppose-communication-and-movement-restrictions-in-kashmir-before-the-supreme-court/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s hearing, Mr. Huzefa Ahmadi and Mr. Dushyant Dave advanced arguments on behalf of the Indian Journalists Union and Foundation for Media Professionals respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Substantive hearing in Anuradha Bhasin v. Union of India commences</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/substantive-hearing-in-anuradha-bhasin-v-union-of-india-commence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 13:36:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/substantive-hearing-in-anuradha-bhasin-v-union-of-india-commence/</guid>
      <description>In today’s hearing, Ms. Vrinda Grover used the govt’s statistics to prove there is no relation between the internet and rise in terrorism and argued there was no application of mind by the govt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bihar’s internet shutdown orders reveal vague but relatively narrow suspension of mass messaging platforms</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/bihars-internet-shutdown-orders-reveal-vague-but-relatively-narrow-suspension-of-mass-messaging-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 06:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/bihars-internet-shutdown-orders-reveal-vague-but-relatively-narrow-suspension-of-mass-messaging-platforms/</guid>
      <description>Internet shutdown orders issued by the Bihar Government reveal blocking of specific mass messaging platforms such as Facebook, Twitter, WhatsApp etc. rather than suspension of internet services in their entirety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For the Govt&#39;s Eyes Only? Govt opposes disclosure of orders imposing communication shutdown in Kashmir</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/for-the-govts-eyes-only-govt-opposes-disclosure-of-orders-imposing-communication-shutdown-in-kashmir/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 09:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/for-the-govts-eyes-only-govt-opposes-disclosure-of-orders-imposing-communication-shutdown-in-kashmir/</guid>
      <description>At today&amp;rsquo;s hearing, the Government cited national security concerns and objected to the Petitioner&amp;rsquo;s and the Intervenors&#39; demand for disclosure of orders issued under the Telecom Suspension Rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FMP&#39;s and IJU&#39;s intervention permitted in Anuradha Bhasin&#39;s petition</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/fmp-and-ijus-intervention-permitted-in-anuradha-bhasins-petition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 11:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/fmp-and-ijus-intervention-permitted-in-anuradha-bhasins-petition/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court allows Foundation for Media Professionals and Indian Journalists Union to intervene in Anuradha Bhasin&amp;rsquo;s petition against the communication shutdown in Kashmir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundation for Media Professionals approaches Supreme Court 
to support journalistic freedom in Kashmir</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/foundation-for-media-professionals-approaches-supreme-court-to-support-journalistic-freedom-in-kashmir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 08:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/foundation-for-media-professionals-approaches-supreme-court-to-support-journalistic-freedom-in-kashmir/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s hearing, the SC wondered if the 40 day long suspension of telecom and internet services in Kashmir was a shutdown or breakdown. It finally directed the Govt. to file its response to the writ petition and intervention applications and urged selective restoration of communication channels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kashmiri student based in Bangalore files petition before the Karnataka HC 
against communication shutdown.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kashmiri-student-based-in-bangalore-files-petition-before-the-karnataka-hc-against-communication-shutdown-in-kashmir/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 05:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kashmiri-student-based-in-bangalore-files-petition-before-the-karnataka-hc-against-communication-shutdown-in-kashmir/</guid>
      <description>The Petition argues that the communication shutdown violates Articles 14, 19 and 21 of the Constitution. The legal basis for the communication shutdown still remains unknown and the interim prayer seeks transparency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We strongly condemn the communications blackout in Jammu and Kashmir and urge an end to internet shutdowns across India</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kashmir_shutdowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 02:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kashmir_shutdowns/</guid>
      <description>The developments of the past few days are of immense consequence to the future of our democracy, and the voices from Jammu and Kashmir need to be heard the loudest, not silenced en masse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We urge DOT to be a defender of digital rights. #KeepUsOnline #LetTheNetWork #KeepItOn #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/an-acknowledgment-of-harm-of-internet-shutdowns-by-the-dot-keepusonline-letthenetwork-keepiton/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 06:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/an-acknowledgment-of-harm-of-internet-shutdowns-by-the-dot-keepusonline-letthenetwork-keepiton/</guid>
      <description>We request the Department of Telecom to extend public victories on net neutrality and internet shutdowns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An incremental victory in the Rajasthan HC against Internet Shutdowns #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/an-incremental-victory-in-the-rajasthan-hc-against-internet-shutdowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 08:03:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/an-incremental-victory-in-the-rajasthan-hc-against-internet-shutdowns/</guid>
      <description>While we can expect internet shutdowns in future, it will not be because of competitive examinations in Rajasthan. We thank the Petitioner, Dhirendra Rajpurohit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support parlimentary scrutiny against internet shutdowns #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/continued-action-against-internet-shutdowns-keepusonline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 06:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/continued-action-against-internet-shutdowns-keepusonline/</guid>
      <description>Support advocacy actions against the growing problem of internet shutdowns across India by engaging parliamentarians. We have prepared a short brief to help you set out key facts, figures and arguments on the massive damage caused by shutting down the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We demand disclosure on India&#39;s shutdown law #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-demand-disclosure-on-indias-shutdown-law-keepusonline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 09:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-demand-disclosure-on-indias-shutdown-law-keepusonline/</guid>
      <description>Last week we made considerable progress in our mission to reform India’s Internet Shutdown laws. This work has been extensively covered by The Wire in an opinion piece titled, “The Worst Aspect of India’s Internet Shutdowns Is the Official Secrecy About It”, and “Jan Gan Man Ki Baat, Episode No. 271”.
A Short Recap
 Noticing a growth in the frequency of internet shutdowns and constrained by the lack of movement for reform, on April 22, 2018, we sent a petition to several government ministries and the Prime Minister’s Office (PMO).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
