<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>RTIReport on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/categories/rtireport/</link>
    <description>Recent content in RTIReport on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 06:11:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/categories/rtireport/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for November 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-november-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 06:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-november-2021/</guid>
      <description>Since our last report for the month of September, IFF has filed 37 RTI requests and 1 first appeal. Here is an overview of the requests filed and an analysis of the responses we have received from the different public authorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for October 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-october-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 05:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-october-2021/</guid>
      <description>Since our last report for the month of September, IFF has filed 49 RTI requests. Here is an overview of the requests filed and an analysis of the responses we have received from the different public authorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for September, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-september-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 07:36:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-september-2021/</guid>
      <description>In September, IFF filed IFF has filed 26 RTI requests and 3 First Appeals with various public authorities to uncover vital information on issues of public interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for August, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-august-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 07:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-august-2021/</guid>
      <description>In the month of August, IFF has filed 64 RTI requests, 5 First Appeals and 1 Second Appeal. In this report, we give you an overview of the requests filed and an analysis of the responses we have received from the different public authorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for July, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-july-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 10:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-july-2021/</guid>
      <description>Since our last report for the month of June, IFF has filed 29 RTI requests, 3 First Appeals and 3 Second Appeals. Here, we give you an overview of the requests filed and why demanding transparency and accountability from Government authorities is important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for June, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-june-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 06:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-june-2021/</guid>
      <description>Since our last report for the month of May, IFF has filed 18  RTI requests, 2 First Appeals and 1 Second Appeal. Here, we give you an overview of the requests filed and why demanding transparency and accountability from Government authorities essential in our fight to protect digital rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for May, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-may-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 06:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-may-2021/</guid>
      <description>Since our last report in the month of April, IFF has filed 32 RTI requests and 1 first appeal. Here, we give you an overview of the requests filed and explain why demanding transparency from government authorities is one of the key elements in our fight to protect digital rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for April, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-april-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-april-2021/</guid>
      <description>Since our last report in the month of March, IFF has filed 7 RTI requests. Here, we give you an overview of the requests filed and why demanding transparency from government authorities is one of the key elements in our fight to protect digital rights which has taken a hit in the lockdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for March, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-march-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 05:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-march-2021/</guid>
      <description>Since our last report in the month of February, IFF has filed 23 RTI requests, 5 first appeals and 1 second appeal. . Here, we give you an overview of the requests filed and why demanding transparency from government authorities is one of the key elements in our fight to protect digital rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for February, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-february-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 05:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-february-2021/</guid>
      <description>Since our last report in the month of January, IFF has filed 41 RTI requests. Here, we give you an overview of the requests filed and why demanding transparency and accountability from government authorities is one of the key elements in our fight to protect digital rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for January, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-january-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 07:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-january-2021/</guid>
      <description>Read more about RTI work for the month of January, 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
