<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRAI on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/categories/trai/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TRAI on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 09:44:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/categories/trai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is the DoT doing a rethink on net neutrality? We press for transparency and enforcement #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/is-the-dot-doing-a-rethink-on-net-neutrality-we-press-for-transparency-and-enforcement-savetheinternet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 09:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/is-the-dot-doing-a-rethink-on-net-neutrality-we-press-for-transparency-and-enforcement-savetheinternet/</guid>
      <description>We were alarmed by a recent report that the Department of Telecommunications (DoT) is citing fiscal constraints in establishing a Multi Stakeholder Body (MSB). We wrote to the DoT, pressing for transparency and enforcement of net neutrality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the need for citizen oriented growth in the telecom sector</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/on-the-need-for-citizen-oriented-growth-in-the-telecom-sector/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 05:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/on-the-need-for-citizen-oriented-growth-in-the-telecom-sector/</guid>
      <description>IFF submitted comments to TRAI&amp;rsquo;s Supplementary Consultation Paper on Roadmap to Promote Broadband Connectivity and Enhanced Broadband Speed. Here, we highlighted the need for direct performance based incentives and about issues with public wifi networks that must be addressed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Internet Access: An Explainer</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/improving-internet-access-an-explainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 08:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/improving-internet-access-an-explainer/</guid>
      <description>In this explainer, we delve into the various executive and policy measures taken to expand India&amp;rsquo;s digital infrastructure and improve internet access. We have focused mainly on the National Digital Communications Policy, 2018, since it is is cornerstone of India&amp;rsquo;s digital infrastructure framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arbitrary blocking of websites by Indian ISPs continues unabated #WhatTheBlock</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/arbitrary-blocking-of-websites-by-indian-isps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 10:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/arbitrary-blocking-of-websites-by-indian-isps/</guid>
      <description>Railwire seems to be arbitrarily blocking access to  Reddit and DuckDuckGo. After Railwire subscribers sent us repeated reports on SaveTheInternet.in and also tagged us on social media we wrote to them today asking them to remove these blocks and follow the license conditions for ISPs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policies of Telecom Service Providers - Or Why You Shouldn&#39;t Just Click Accept</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/privacy-policies-of-telecom-service-providers-or-why-you-shouldnt-just-click-accept/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 06:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/privacy-policies-of-telecom-service-providers-or-why-you-shouldnt-just-click-accept/</guid>
      <description>We analysed the privacy of policies of the 4 large telecom service providers to check not only whether they were Puttaswamy-compliant, but also whether they would need updating in the face of the  Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019. We found certain alarming issues in these policies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read IFF&#39;s Comments on TRAI&#39;s Consultation Paper on Broadband Access and Connectivity</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/read-iffs-comments-on-trais-consultation-paper-on-broadband-access-and-connectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/read-iffs-comments-on-trais-consultation-paper-on-broadband-access-and-connectivity/</guid>
      <description>In our comments, we highlighted the need to revamp the policy and regulatory initiatives surrounding the broadband infrastructure in the country to ensure that every citizen has access to the internet irrespective of their geographical location or social and economic status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF Writes To TRAI Reminding Them That Users Must Be At The Centre of Net Neutrality #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/iff-writes-to-trai-reminding-them-that-users-must-be-at-the-centre-of-net-neutrality-savetheinternet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 06:34:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/iff-writes-to-trai-reminding-them-that-users-must-be-at-the-centre-of-net-neutrality-savetheinternet/</guid>
      <description>On June 29, 2020 IFF has shared a supplementary submission with TRAI on net neutrality monitoring and enforcement. The purpose behind this is to emphasise the importance of focusing on strong implementation and enforcement; and the centrality of public/user participation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Write to DoT and TRAI to Improve Internet Access and Protect Net Neutrality During COVID-19 #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/we-write-to-dot-and-trai-to-improve-internet-access-and-protect-net-neutrality-during-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 08:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/we-write-to-dot-and-trai-to-improve-internet-access-and-protect-net-neutrality-during-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>IFF has written to the DoT and TRAI suggesting that government interventions must look toward overcoming the digital divide, appreciating the importance of the internet and mobile services as an essential utility, and protect net neutrality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOS : Three ways how the Department of Telecom can help #FlattenTheCurve #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/urgent-steps-to-be-taken-by-the-department-of-telecom-due-to-the-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 11:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/urgent-steps-to-be-taken-by-the-department-of-telecom-due-to-the-covid/</guid>
      <description>With many workplaces putting into place work from home plans, voice and data connectivity become critical. To ensure that high quality bandwidth is available to all parts of India we have suggested specific steps to be taken by the Department of Telecom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Valentine’s, we send a love letter for net neutrality to TRAI #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/on-valentines-we-send-a-love-letter-for-net-neutrality-to-trai-savetheinternet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 11:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/on-valentines-we-send-a-love-letter-for-net-neutrality-to-trai-savetheinternet/</guid>
      <description>IFF responded to TRAI’s public consultation on net neutrality enforcement and highlighted the need to reduce discretion, increase transparency and accountability, boost the local measurement ecosystem, and build better more-inclusive institutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read our summary of TRAI’s consultation paper on net neutrality enforcement #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/trai-consultation-on-net-neutrality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 10:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/trai-consultation-on-net-neutrality/</guid>
      <description>Read our summary and participate in TRAI&amp;rsquo;s Consultation on Traffic Management Practices (TMPs) and Multi-Stakeholder Body for Net Neutrality by Jan. 31, 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For preventing red tape and impairing innovation we submit counter-comments to TRAI on the could services consultation</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/we-provide-the-trai-with-our-counter-comments-on-the-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 07:54:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/we-provide-the-trai-with-our-counter-comments-on-the-cloud/</guid>
      <description>We just submitted our counter comments on the paper to prevent red-rape and over regulation of the cloud services sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We must prevent cloud cartels.</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/we-must-prevent-cloud-cartel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/we-must-prevent-cloud-cartel/</guid>
      <description>The TRAI invited comments on a consultation paper that suggested a framework for the registration of industry bodies for cloud services. We make our submission with concerns of jurisdiction, cartelisation and self-regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Net Neutrality enforcement in India needs to find its bearings.</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/net-neutrality-in-india-needs-to-find-its-bearings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/net-neutrality-in-india-needs-to-find-its-bearings/</guid>
      <description>TRAI will release a new round of consultation on the compliance of net neutrality. We continue to restate the need for an enforcement mechanism and transparency and disclosure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OTT Regulation: Understanding the economic basis #SaveTheInternet #NetNeutrality</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/ott-regulation-understanding-the-economic-basis-savetheinternet-netneutrality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/ott-regulation-understanding-the-economic-basis-savetheinternet-netneutrality/</guid>
      <description>One of the core questions in the ongoing OTT consultation paper floated by the TRAI are the revenue losses by large telecom companies which would impair future telecom network investment. We look at the data&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help the TRAI set its digital priorities for 2019 #AskTRAI</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/help-the-trai-set-its-digital-priorities-for-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 04:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/help-the-trai-set-its-digital-priorities-for-2019/</guid>
      <description>We wrote a letter to the TRAI asking it to involve the public in determining its regulatory priorities for next year. Your voice matters. Reach out to us, let us know issues and problems you would like to be addressed in 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRAI’s recommendations are another big victory for Net Neutrality  - but follow up action is needed!</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/trais-recommendations-are-another-big-victory-for-net-neutrality-but-follow-up-action-is-needed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/trais-recommendations-are-another-big-victory-for-net-neutrality-but-follow-up-action-is-needed/</guid>
      <description>IFF notes with appreciation the recommendations issued by Telecommunication Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) on Net Neutrality despite push back from some quarters of the telecommunication industry against any additional regulations. By taking a decisive stand on upholding Net Neutrality, TRAI has built upon the strong foundation it had laid down in 2016 by issuing regulations prohibiting Discriminatory Tariffs for Data Services.
We welcome these recommendations for the following reasons:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We call on the TRAI to protect user privacy in the Indian telecom sector!</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/we-call-on-the-trai-to-protect-user-privacy-in-the-indian-telecom-sector/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/we-call-on-the-trai-to-protect-user-privacy-in-the-indian-telecom-sector/</guid>
      <description>Fresh off the historic nine judge decision of the Supreme Court holding privacy as a fundamental right, IFF has called on the TRAI to protect user privacy and data protection in its ongoing public consultation “Privacy, Security and Ownership of the Data in the Telecom Sector”. We previously posted a short summary of this consultation paper back in September.
You can read our full November 6 comments to the TRAI here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
