<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Official Announcement on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://internerfreedom.in/tags/official-announcement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Official Announcement on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://internerfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 12:41:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://internerfreedom.in/tags/official-announcement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Personal Data and Information Privacy Code Bill, 2019 introduced in the Lok Sabha today! #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/personal-data-and-information-privacy-code-bill-2019-introduced-in-the-lok-sabha-today-saveourprivacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 12:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/personal-data-and-information-privacy-code-bill-2019-introduced-in-the-lok-sabha-today-saveourprivacy/</guid>
      <description>IFF goes to Parliament with Dr. Ravikumar (Lok Sabha, MP from Tamil Nadu). Today, the Personal Data and Information Privacy Code Bill, 2019 was introduced!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SaveTheInternet.in is live.</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/savetheinternet-in-is-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 09:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/savetheinternet-in-is-live/</guid>
      <description>SaveTheInternet.in is live.
With the rampant website blockings being conducted by ISP’s, IFF has taken the step to  activate the SaveTheInternet.in website. It includes a reporting tool and petition to take this movement forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guess who&#39;s back, back again? #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/savetheinternet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 12:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/savetheinternet/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few months, IFF has identified violations of Net Neutrality through blocking of website access. In light of these current threats to net neutrality, it has taken the step to activate the SaveTheInternet.in website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Innovation through organisational support</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/org_supporters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 07:29:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/org_supporters/</guid>
      <description>Innovation is a common value shared by IFF and India&amp;rsquo;s vibrant start up economy. There are many who believe their business has the capacity for social good and support constitutional goals. For this reason, we have decided to spur innovation by opening up to organisational donors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Republic Day letter from IFF</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/a-republic-day-letter-from-iff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 06:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/a-republic-day-letter-from-iff/</guid>
      <description>This republic day we reflect on our constitutional promises. For liberty, fraternity, equality and justice in technology. In 2019 we promise to keep up momentum on the internet freedom tableau!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over One Million Submissions to TRAI in 12 Days</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/one-million-submissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 11:37:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/one-million-submissions/</guid>
      <description>Unprecedented public response in India’s policy making history Citizens, businesses, startups and political leaders demand #NetNeutrality Volunteer-led “Save The Internet” Showcases Internet-enabled Model of Public Participation  23 April, Delhi - The SaveTheInternet.in Coalition, a group of over 50 volunteers from across India, concerned about safeguarding an open Internet and net neutrality, today announced that over one million email submissions had been sent to India’s telecom regulatory body, the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI), via savetheinternet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear parliamentarians, we are not affiliated with any political party. Net neutrality affects everyone.</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/letter-to-parliamentarians/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 05:52:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/letter-to-parliamentarians/</guid>
      <description>The Internet has become an integral part of all of our lives. We use it to do our work, connect with people and gain knowledge.
You, our representatives, and your parties, also use it to gather research about the issues faced by your constituents, the challenges faced by different parts of our country, and the expert knowledge needed to legislate for India’s future and shape our national decisions. You use it to communicate directly with your supporters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Response to #airtelpledge</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/airtelpledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 09:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/airtelpledge/</guid>
      <description>On April 18th, Airtel sent a letter, called #airtelpledge (read), to all its employees and all its postpaid users, making some claims and promises about Airtel Zero. We’re addressing a few claims made in the letter here:
  Airtel said that it is committed to Net Neutrality. However, Airtel cannot be committed to Net Neutrality while simultaneously violating it. The TRAI consultation paper (read) itself says on page 77:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
