<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>accesstointernet on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/accesstointernet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in accesstointernet on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 13:11:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/accesstointernet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Calcutta HC stays internet shutdown issued by West Bengal Government</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/calcutta-hc-stays-internet-shutdown-issued-by-west-bengal-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 13:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/calcutta-hc-stays-internet-shutdown-issued-by-west-bengal-government/</guid>
      <description>Calcutta HC has stayed an internet shutdown order dated 03.03.2022 issued by the State of West Bengal. The HC was of the view that the order was not issued by a competent authority. The order was stayed in a petition filed by Ashlesh Biradar. IFF provided legal support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF provides inputs to UN on Internet Shutdowns</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ohchr-internet-shutdowns-submission/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 07:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ohchr-internet-shutdowns-submission/</guid>
      <description>The submission to United Nations analyses the legal basis of internet shutdowns in India, the instances of disruptions, their impact on human rights and the efforts by the Indian Government to improve internet connectivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gauhati HC allows IFF&#39;s intervention application in petition challenging the constitutionality of internet shutdown rules #KeepItOn</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/gauhati-hc-internet-shutdown-rules-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 09:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/gauhati-hc-internet-shutdown-rules-update/</guid>
      <description>At a hearing dated January 31, 2022, IFF&amp;rsquo;s intervention application challenging the Telecom Suspension Rules, 2017 has been allowed by the Gauhati High Court, and IFF has been impleaded in the case. IFF is now allowed to assist the Court with oral and written submissions in the proceedings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF releases the second edition of the Connectivity Tracker #MapTheDigitalDivide</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-second-edition-connectivity-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 07:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-second-edition-connectivity-tracker/</guid>
      <description>IFF’s #connectivitytracker for Jan 2022 is here!  In this edition of the report, we analyze the data on telecom and internet connectivity, digital divide in the context of access to online education, and the progress of government schemes aimed at improving internet access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concerned with frequent internet suspensions, Parliamentary Committee recommends an overhaul.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/concerned-with-frequent-internet-suspensions-parliamentary-committee-recommends-an-overhaul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 08:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/concerned-with-frequent-internet-suspensions-parliamentary-committee-recommends-an-overhaul/</guid>
      <description>The Standing Committee on IT has published its report on ‘Suspension of telecom services/internet and its impact’. The report has a range of recommendations including a review of the legal regime for suspension of internet services and establishing a database of internet shutdown orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The National Digital Education Architecture: An explainer</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-national-digital-education-architecture-an-explainer-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 05:13:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-national-digital-education-architecture-an-explainer-2/</guid>
      <description>In our latest explainer, we look at the National Digital Education Architecture, detailing what this policy entails and exploring its legislative and policy origins. We also explore issues of a lack of internet access, low digital literacy, and an inadequate consent framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Revealed] Jaipur Internet Shutdown Orders: Cut, Copy, Paste!</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/revealed-jaipur-internet-shutdown-orders-cut-copy-paste-keep-it-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 09:22:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/revealed-jaipur-internet-shutdown-orders-cut-copy-paste-keep-it-on/</guid>
      <description>We filed RTI applications to determine the extent of the Rajasthan government’s compliance with directions in Anuradha Bhasin. We have received a response from the Jaipur DC, who issued 30 Internet shutdown orders, which follow an identical copy, cut, paste format — same as Udaipur!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing IFF’s Connectivity Tracker #MapTheDigitalDivide</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/introducing-iffs-connectivity-tracker-mapthedigitaldivide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 07:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/introducing-iffs-connectivity-tracker-mapthedigitaldivide/</guid>
      <description>IFF is introducing its Connectivity Tracker, compiling available data related to connectivity each quarter, like: telecom subscriptions, internet connections, penetration rates, average data usage per user, and more. This edition contains data from Jan &amp;lsquo;20 to Aug &amp;lsquo;21.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>118 days since… still no justice for those targeted by the “Sulli Deals” incident.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/118-days-since-still-no-justice-for-those-targeted-by-the-sulli-deals-incident/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 05:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/118-days-since-still-no-justice-for-those-targeted-by-the-sulli-deals-incident/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the Delhi Police asking them to expeditiously investigate the &amp;lsquo;Sulli Deals&amp;rsquo; incident to provide closure and support to those targeted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRAI’s final roadmap for connectivity and broadband access is a mixed bag #AccessToInternet</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/trais-final-roadmap-for-connectivity-and-broadband-access-a-mixed-bag-accesstointernet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 04:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/trais-final-roadmap-for-connectivity-and-broadband-access-a-mixed-bag-accesstointernet/</guid>
      <description>After multiple rounds of consultation, the TRAI released its final recommendations on the Roadmap to promote broadband connectivity and enhanced broadband speed. Some of the recommendations we had made during the consultations were reflected in the final report, albeit with certain modifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As the farmers’ protests saw widespread internet shutdowns, IFF wrote to the Haryana Home Ministry urging restraint</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/as-the-farmers-protests-see-widespread-internet-shutdowns-iff-writes-to-the-haryana-home-ministry-urging-restraint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 05:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/as-the-farmers-protests-see-widespread-internet-shutdowns-iff-writes-to-the-haryana-home-ministry-urging-restraint/</guid>
      <description>Between September 7 and 9, 2021, internet services were suspended in four districts of Haryana due to ongoing farmers’ protests. The order is not available on the Government websites and does not lay out a factual justification. We wrote to the Haryana government to officially publish all orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The E Shram Portal: An Explainer</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-e-shram-portal-an-explainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 05:25:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-e-shram-portal-an-explainer/</guid>
      <description>On 26th August, 2021, the Labour Minister Bhupender Yadav launched the E-Shram portal. The portal will help unorganised workers receive social security benefits. We decided to create this explainer to help you understand what the portal is and what are the various issues facing the portal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We wrote to the Department of Financial Services asking them to conduct a consultation on the E-Rupi programme</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-to-the-department-of-financial-services-asking-them-to-conduct-a-consultation-on-the-e-rupi-programme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 07:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-to-the-department-of-financial-services-asking-them-to-conduct-a-consultation-on-the-e-rupi-programme/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the Department of Financial Services about the E-Rupi. We pointed out several issues such as surveillance and financial exploitation, the lack of data protection, and exclusion. We suggested that a consultation be conducted, and that data protection norms be specified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF&#39;s recommendations for the United Health Interface</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/read-our-submission-on-the-unified-health-interface-consultation-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 01:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/read-our-submission-on-the-unified-health-interface-consultation-paper/</guid>
      <description>IFF has submitted its comments on the NDHM’s consultation paper on the Unified Health Interface.Our comments are focused on five key issues: the need for diverse feedback, market capture by the private sector, digital exclusion, financial exploitation, and the need for public digital infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the need for citizen oriented growth in the telecom sector</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/on-the-need-for-citizen-oriented-growth-in-the-telecom-sector/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 05:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/on-the-need-for-citizen-oriented-growth-in-the-telecom-sector/</guid>
      <description>IFF submitted comments to TRAI&amp;rsquo;s Supplementary Consultation Paper on Roadmap to Promote Broadband Connectivity and Enhanced Broadband Speed. Here, we highlighted the need for direct performance based incentives and about issues with public wifi networks that must be addressed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MEITY responds to our representation to unblock Twitter accounts. Confirms orders and denies disclosure.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/meity-response-to-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 08:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/meity-response-to-representation/</guid>
      <description>In February, we had written to MeitY with regards to the blocking of Twitter accounts. MeitY responded to us recently, saying that they did nothing wrong. We have written back to the Ministry this week explaining how they are constitutionally required to disclose the blocking orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Internet Access: An Explainer</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/improving-internet-access-an-explainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 08:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/improving-internet-access-an-explainer/</guid>
      <description>In this explainer, we delve into the various executive and policy measures taken to expand India&amp;rsquo;s digital infrastructure and improve internet access. We have focused mainly on the National Digital Communications Policy, 2018, since it is is cornerstone of India&amp;rsquo;s digital infrastructure framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#ElectionFever: What do party manifestos have in store for tech and digital rights?</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/2021assemblyelections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 09:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/2021assemblyelections/</guid>
      <description>With state elections incoming, we thought we would do our bit for #electionfever by analysing the manifestos of political parties across the spectrum. Our analysis is guided by our focus areas and is meant to help voters understand how political parties are looking at these issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PM-WANI Scheme: An Explainer</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/pm-wani-explainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 05:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/pm-wani-explainer/</guid>
      <description>The PM-WANI scheme aims to increase internet connectivity across the country by implementing a decentralised system of public access points. We created an explainer in which we discuss how, while a step towards the right direction, the scheme faces both foundational and implementational challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed signals: Observations on the 2021-22 Budget</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/budget-2021-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 13:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/budget-2021-22/</guid>
      <description>Budget 2021-22 is a mixed bag. Though it contains praiseworthy allocations towards programs such as Digital India and the USOF and provides a stimulus to R&amp;amp;D, allocations towards the PMGDISHA remain low, while concerns remain that signficant capital expenditure may not take place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is internet access not a basic necessity? Should our privacy not be safeguarded in health and education?</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/economic-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 06:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/economic-survey/</guid>
      <description>While the emphasis laid on improving access and equity is commendable, there are certain concerns that the Economic Survey must address. These include questions raised about the commercialisation of healthcare and the viability of remote learning, as well as the overarching data paradigm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We wrote to the UGC and the Ministry of Education on exam proctoring</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-to-the-ugc-and-the-ministry-of-education-on-exam-proctoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-to-the-ugc-and-the-ministry-of-education-on-exam-proctoring/</guid>
      <description>Following multiple reports of the use of exam proctoring technology by various universities across the country, we wrote to the University Grants Commission and the Ministry of Education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridge the #DigitalDivide: On chronic inequalities in internet access</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/on-chronic-inequalities-in-internet-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 06:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/on-chronic-inequalities-in-internet-access/</guid>
      <description>Data from the 5th NFHS survey indicates that while internet access is increasing, a significant digital divide remains as a result of issues such as gender gaps and rural-urban gaps. These inequalities are also borne out by other government statistics and our conversations with stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arbitrary blocking of websites by Indian ISPs continues unabated #WhatTheBlock</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/arbitrary-blocking-of-websites-by-indian-isps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 10:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/arbitrary-blocking-of-websites-by-indian-isps/</guid>
      <description>Railwire seems to be arbitrarily blocking access to  Reddit and DuckDuckGo. After Railwire subscribers sent us repeated reports on SaveTheInternet.in and also tagged us on social media we wrote to them today asking them to remove these blocks and follow the license conditions for ISPs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTI responses from Andhra Pradesh and Gujarat show compliance failure with the Anuradha Bhasin Internet Shutdown decision</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/rti-responses-from-andhra-pradesh-and-gujarat-show-compliance-failure-with-the-anuradha-bhasin-internet-shutdown-decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/rti-responses-from-andhra-pradesh-and-gujarat-show-compliance-failure-with-the-anuradha-bhasin-internet-shutdown-decision/</guid>
      <description>11 months on from the Supreme Court&amp;rsquo;s decision on internet shutdowns in the matter of Anuradha Bhasin v Union of India, there is still no compliance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read IFF&#39;s Comments on TRAI&#39;s Consultation Paper on Broadband Access and Connectivity</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/read-iffs-comments-on-trais-consultation-paper-on-broadband-access-and-connectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/read-iffs-comments-on-trais-consultation-paper-on-broadband-access-and-connectivity/</guid>
      <description>In our comments, we highlighted the need to revamp the policy and regulatory initiatives surrounding the broadband infrastructure in the country to ensure that every citizen has access to the internet irrespective of their geographical location or social and economic status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We wrote to the DoT about Odisha&#39;s internet connectivity issues #4GforAll</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-to-the-dot-about-odishas-internet-connectivity-issues-4gforall/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 03:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-to-the-dot-about-odishas-internet-connectivity-issues-4gforall/</guid>
      <description>We asked them to ensure that the BharatNet Project, which aims to provide fast internet connectivity to the whole country, is operationalised according to pre-existing timelines so that these issues can be resolved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fight for fast and affordable internet in Andaman &amp; Nicobar Islands continues... #4GforAll #InternetinAndaman</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-fight-for-fast-and-affordable-internet-in-andaman-nicobar-islands-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 04:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-fight-for-fast-and-affordable-internet-in-andaman-nicobar-islands-continues/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to Shri Kuldeep Rai Sharma, the Honourable Member of Parliament for the Andaman and Nicobar Islands stating our concerns and urging him to escalate the matter with PMO and MeitY.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We wrote to the PMO &amp; DoT on the Access to Internet issue which is persisting in the Andaman &amp; Nicobar Islands #DigitalAndamans #4GforAll</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-to-the-pmo-dot-on-the-access-to-internet-issue-which-is-persisting-in-the-andaman-nicobar-islands/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 08:10:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-to-the-pmo-dot-on-the-access-to-internet-issue-which-is-persisting-in-the-andaman-nicobar-islands/</guid>
      <description>We have written to the Prime Minister’s Office and the Department of Telecommunications highlighting the prevalent issues in A&amp;amp;N Islands and providing certain recommendations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For the people of Andaman &amp; Nicobar Islands, 4G internet at reasonable tariffs is still a dream...  #DigitalAndaman #4GforAll</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/for-the-people-of-andaman-nicobar-islands-4g-internet-at-reasonable-tariffs-is-still-a-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 11:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/for-the-people-of-andaman-nicobar-islands-4g-internet-at-reasonable-tariffs-is-still-a-dream/</guid>
      <description>In this blogpost, we aim to highlight the access to internet problems being faced by the citizens of the Andaman and Nicobar Islands with a focus on the delays in the ongoing CANI Submarine Cable Systems Project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
