<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Filings on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/categories/filings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Filings on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:44:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/categories/filings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Social media giants have released the second round of &#39;Compliance Reports&#39;. We’ve analysed the data.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/google-facebook-and-twitters-second-round-of-compliance-reports-an-analysis-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/google-facebook-and-twitters-second-round-of-compliance-reports-an-analysis-2/</guid>
      <description>We analyse the transparency reports submitted by Google, Facebook, Instagram, WhatsApp and Twitter in compliance with Rule 4(1)(d) of the Information Technology (Guidelines for Intermediaries and Digital Media Ethics Code) Rules, 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delhi HC issues notice to govt in petition challenging denial of RTI  regarding Aarogya Setu  #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/delhi-hc-hearing-aarogya-setu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 11:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/delhi-hc-hearing-aarogya-setu/</guid>
      <description>Today, the Delhi HC issued notice to the CPIOs of DeitY, MeitY, NeGD and NIC in a petition filed by RTI activist, Saurav Das, challenging denial of information relating to the creation of the Aarogya Setu app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Kanoon defends the right to provide access to court records</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indian-kanoon-kerala-hc-right-to-be-forgotten/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indian-kanoon-kerala-hc-right-to-be-forgotten/</guid>
      <description>In response to a petition filed before the Kerala HC, Indian Kanoon has clarified that a right to be forgotten cannot be judicially created without a statutory basis and explained that court records are public documents whose reproduction cannot be prohibited by citing the right to privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Journalists Union defends media&#39;s right to report on MeToo allegations</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indian-journalists-union-defends-right-of-journalists-to-report-on-metoo-allegations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 06:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indian-journalists-union-defends-right-of-journalists-to-report-on-metoo-allegations/</guid>
      <description>In the latest hearing in Subodh Gupta&amp;rsquo;s defamation suit, IJU emphasized that news reports cannot be de-indexed without providing the journalists a hearing and argued there was a distinction between merely republishing defamatory allegations and reporting on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delhi HC issues notice to the government for blocking satirical Dowry Calculator website</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/delhi-hc-issues-notice-to-the-government-for-blocking-satirical-dowry-calculator-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 05:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/delhi-hc-issues-notice-to-the-government-for-blocking-satirical-dowry-calculator-website/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday, the Delhi High Court issued notice to MeitY, DoT and Ministry of WCD for blocking the satirical Dowry Calculator website without complying with the provisions of Section 69A of the IT Act and the Blocking Rules made thereunder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap Part II: Kashmir Communication Shutdown and Movement Restrictions Cases</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/recap-part-ii-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-movement-restrictions-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 12:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/recap-part-ii-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-movement-restrictions-cases/</guid>
      <description>Part II of the Recap summarizes arguments made by the petitioners and the government about the constitutional validity of the communication shutdown and movement restrictions in Kashmir under Articles 19 and 21 of the Constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government says judicial review of severity of the restrictions in Kashmir during August is an “academic exercise”</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/government-says-judicial-review-of-severity-of-the-restrictions-in-kashmir-during-august-is-an-academic-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 14:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/government-says-judicial-review-of-severity-of-the-restrictions-in-kashmir-during-august-is-an-academic-exercise/</guid>
      <description>In yesterday&amp;rsquo;s hearing, the Solicitor General argued that the telecom shutdown was necessary because digital platforms could be used for mobilisation by terrorists and separatists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journalistic bodies oppose communication and movement restrictions in Kashmir before the Supreme Court</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/journalistic-bodies-oppose-communication-and-movement-restrictions-in-kashmir-before-the-supreme-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 07:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/journalistic-bodies-oppose-communication-and-movement-restrictions-in-kashmir-before-the-supreme-court/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s hearing, Mr. Huzefa Ahmadi and Mr. Dushyant Dave advanced arguments on behalf of the Indian Journalists Union and Foundation for Media Professionals respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delhi HC directs Subodh Gupta to respond to impleadment application filed by Indian Journalists Union and allows Scene and Herd to contest anonymously (for now)</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/delhi-hc-directs-subodh-gupta-to-respond-to-impleadment-application-filed-by-indian-journalists-union-and-allows-scene-and-herd-to-contest-anonymously-for-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 13:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/delhi-hc-directs-subodh-gupta-to-respond-to-impleadment-application-filed-by-indian-journalists-union-and-allows-scene-and-herd-to-contest-anonymously-for-now/</guid>
      <description>The Delhi HC has issued notice in the impleadment application filed by the Indian Journalists Union in Subodh Gupta&amp;rsquo;s defamation suit and directed the Plaintiff to respond to concerns about overbroad censorship of news reports which adhere to professional journalistic standards of reporting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A cellphone signal at the end of the tunnel? SC may finally hear substantive challenges to telecommunications shutdown in Kashmir around November</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/government-files-affidavit-in-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-press-freedom-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 12:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/government-files-affidavit-in-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-press-freedom-case/</guid>
      <description>In Kashmir Communication Shutdown and Press Freedom Case, the Govt has argued that the restrictions are necessary because of terrorism and declined to provide any specific information to the Petitioner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook’s Transfer Petition in Madras HC case involving encryption and traceability allowed after Tamil Nadu Government withdraws objections</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/facebooks-transfer-petition-in-madras-hc-case-involving-encryption-and-traceability-allowed-after-tamil-nadu-government-withdraws-objections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 09:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/facebooks-transfer-petition-in-madras-hc-case-involving-encryption-and-traceability-allowed-after-tamil-nadu-government-withdraws-objections/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s hearing, the SC allowed Facebook&amp;rsquo;s transfer petition in Antony Clement Rubin v. Union of India after the Tamil Nadu Government withdrew its objections to the transfer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For the Govt&#39;s Eyes Only? Govt opposes disclosure of orders imposing communication shutdown in Kashmir</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/for-the-govts-eyes-only-govt-opposes-disclosure-of-orders-imposing-communication-shutdown-in-kashmir/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 09:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/for-the-govts-eyes-only-govt-opposes-disclosure-of-orders-imposing-communication-shutdown-in-kashmir/</guid>
      <description>At today&amp;rsquo;s hearing, the Government cited national security concerns and objected to the Petitioner&amp;rsquo;s and the Intervenors&#39; demand for disclosure of orders issued under the Telecom Suspension Rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FMP&#39;s and IJU&#39;s intervention permitted in Anuradha Bhasin&#39;s petition</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/fmp-and-ijus-intervention-permitted-in-anuradha-bhasins-petition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 11:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/fmp-and-ijus-intervention-permitted-in-anuradha-bhasins-petition/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court allows Foundation for Media Professionals and Indian Journalists Union to intervene in Anuradha Bhasin&amp;rsquo;s petition against the communication shutdown in Kashmir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Action-Packed Hearing in Facebook&#39;s Transfer Petition before the Supreme Court</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/action-packed-hearing-in-facebooks-transfer-petition-before-the-supreme-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 09:35:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/action-packed-hearing-in-facebooks-transfer-petition-before-the-supreme-court/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s hearing, the Supreme Court emphasized that technical and complex issues such as encryption are best addressed by the executive branch and it directed the Central Government to file an affidavit about the status of the Draft Intermediaries Guidelines Rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundation for Media Professionals approaches Supreme Court 
to support journalistic freedom in Kashmir</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/foundation-for-media-professionals-approaches-supreme-court-to-support-journalistic-freedom-in-kashmir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 08:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/foundation-for-media-professionals-approaches-supreme-court-to-support-journalistic-freedom-in-kashmir/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s hearing, the SC wondered if the 40 day long suspension of telecom and internet services in Kashmir was a shutdown or breakdown. It finally directed the Govt. to file its response to the writ petition and intervention applications and urged selective restoration of communication channels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kashmiri student based in Bangalore files petition before the Karnataka HC 
against communication shutdown.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kashmiri-student-based-in-bangalore-files-petition-before-the-karnataka-hc-against-communication-shutdown-in-kashmir/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 05:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kashmiri-student-based-in-bangalore-files-petition-before-the-karnataka-hc-against-communication-shutdown-in-kashmir/</guid>
      <description>The Petition argues that the communication shutdown violates Articles 14, 19 and 21 of the Constitution. The legal basis for the communication shutdown still remains unknown and the interim prayer seeks transparency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF files independent expert&#39;s submission before Madras HC on PIL relating to encryption and traceability</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-files-independent-expert-submission-before-madras-hc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 09:13:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-files-independent-expert-submission-before-madras-hc/</guid>
      <description>IFF has filed an expert submission by Dr. Manoj Prabhakaran (Professor, IIT Bombay) which highlights the risks and long term ineffectiveness of Dr. Kamakoti&amp;rsquo;s proposal to introduce traceability on encrypted platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vanakkam! Updates on the Aadhaar-social media linkage and encryption PIL before the Madras HC</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/vanakkam-updates-on-the-aadhaar-social-media-linkage-and-encryption-pil-before-the-madras-hc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 09:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/vanakkam-updates-on-the-aadhaar-social-media-linkage-and-encryption-pil-before-the-madras-hc/</guid>
      <description>At today&amp;rsquo;s hearing, IFF placed on record its written submissions highlighting how proposed changes to the product design of social media platforms would harm user privacy and lead to over-broad automated censorship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We won’t give up! IFF approaches CIC against MHA’s refusal to disclose surveillance figures.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wont-give-up-iff-approaches-cic-against-mhas-refusal-to-disclose-surveillance-figures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 10:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wont-give-up-iff-approaches-cic-against-mhas-refusal-to-disclose-surveillance-figures/</guid>
      <description>After the MHA rejected our RTI applications about use of surveillance powers on flimsy grounds, IFF has filed an appeal before the CIC and we are willing to go the distance in this fight for transparency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF files rejoinder in PIL seeking surveillance reform</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-files-rejoinder-in-pil-seeking-surveillance-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 14:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-files-rejoinder-in-pil-seeking-surveillance-reform/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, IFF filed its rejoinder in the PIL seeking surveillance reform and reemphasized that judicial oversight is necessary in the surveillance process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try again? Gujarat High Court declines to hear our PIL against the PUBG Ban</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/try-again-high-court-declines-to-hear-our-pil-against-the-pubg-ban/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 12:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/try-again-high-court-declines-to-hear-our-pil-against-the-pubg-ban/</guid>
      <description>The Gujarat High Court has declined to hear our petition challenging the ban on PUBG and subsequent arrests of at least 21 young persons. We will continue fighting the good fight and consult our lawyers to figure out the way forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF files PIL against the PUBG Ban in Gujarat.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-files-pil-against-the-pubg-ban-in-gujarat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 05:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-files-pil-against-the-pubg-ban-in-gujarat/</guid>
      <description>IFF has filed a PIL before the Gujarat High Court challenging the PUBG Ban and the subsequent arrests as violative of Articles 14, 19 and 21 of the Constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Section 66A returns to its grave after accidental resurrection.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/section-66a-returns-to-its-grave-leaving-us-to-netflix-and-chill-in-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 09:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/section-66a-returns-to-its-grave-leaving-us-to-netflix-and-chill-in-peace/</guid>
      <description>The Delhi High Court today promptly agreed to remove an inadvertent reference to the unconstitutional Section 66A in its judgement rejecting censorship of online platforms like Netflix and Amazon Prime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF Comments on the Draft Geospatial  Information Regulation Bill, 2016</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-comments-on-the-draft-geospatial-information-regulation-bill-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-comments-on-the-draft-geospatial-information-regulation-bill-2016/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year, the Ministry of Home Affairs to the Government of India put out a draft bill for comment - the Geospatial Information Regulation Bill, 2016.
As an organisation, one of IFF&amp;rsquo;s core areas is promoting an Internet which preserves freedom for users, designers, scholars and entrepreneurs. Such freedom today is being exercised by most users to generate and contribute geospatial information. Every Indian today with a smartphone is a cartographer who is helping map and digitise India.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
