<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Kerala High Court on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/kerala-high-court/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kerala High Court on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 09:09:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/kerala-high-court/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Union of India seeks a transfer of cases challenging IT Rules, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/union-of-india-seeks-a-transfer-of-cases-challenging-it-rules-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 09:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/union-of-india-seeks-a-transfer-of-cases-challenging-it-rules-2021/</guid>
      <description>A two-judge bench of the Supreme Court has listed the Union of India&amp;rsquo;s transfer petition before another bench on 16th July 2021. The petition seeks a transfer to the Supreme Court of 4 cases challenging IT Rules, 2021 which are pending before different High Courts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kerala HC restrains coercive action on the operation of Part III of the Intermediaries Rules, 2021 for LiveLaw</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kerala-hc-grants-a-stay-of-the-operation-of-part-iii-of-the-intermediaries-rules-2021-to-livelaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 09:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kerala-hc-grants-a-stay-of-the-operation-of-part-iii-of-the-intermediaries-rules-2021-to-livelaw/</guid>
      <description>In a major victory for online publishers of legal news and literature, today the Kerala High Court granted a stay of the operation of Part III of the Information Technology Rules, 2021 to LiveLaw Media Pvt. Ltd. in a writ petition filed by LiveLaw Media Pvt. Ltd., M. A. Rashid and Manu Sebastian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Kanoon defends the right to provide access to court records</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indian-kanoon-kerala-hc-right-to-be-forgotten/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indian-kanoon-kerala-hc-right-to-be-forgotten/</guid>
      <description>In response to a petition filed before the Kerala HC, Indian Kanoon has clarified that a right to be forgotten cannot be judicially created without a statutory basis and explained that court records are public documents whose reproduction cannot be prohibited by citing the right to privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Section 118A repeal important steps remain for the Government of Kerala</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/after-section-118a-repeals-important-steps-remain-for-the-government-of-kerala/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 08:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/after-section-118a-repeals-important-steps-remain-for-the-government-of-kerala/</guid>
      <description>Read our proposals to the Government of Kerala to help avoid any overbroad or unnecessary criminalisation of online speech while also making sure abuse, threats or any of the harms that emerge on social media can be checked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kerala HC to hear Aarogya Setu petitions in September 2020 #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kerala-hc-aarogya-setu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 07:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kerala-hc-aarogya-setu/</guid>
      <description>On 24 August, the Kerala HC heard a writ petition regarding third party data sharing and mandatory imposition of the Aarogya Setu app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We wrote to the Kerala Government and the Expert Committee formed on the Sprinklr Inc. Data Protection issue in Kerala highlighting the need for preserving the ideal of Constitutional Federalism #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-to-the-kerala-government-and-the-expert-committee-formed-on-the-sprinklr-inc-data-protection-issue-in-kerala-highlighting-the-need-for-preserving-the-ideal-of-constitutional-fe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 10:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-to-the-kerala-government-and-the-expert-committee-formed-on-the-sprinklr-inc-data-protection-issue-in-kerala-highlighting-the-need-for-preserving-the-ideal-of-constitutional-fe/</guid>
      <description>In our representation to the Government of Kerala and the Expert Committee formed on the issue, we have pointed out certain lacunae in the Kerala HC order addressing the issue and have made specific suggestions on how best to resolve them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kerala High Court hears challenges against mandatory imposition of Aarogya Setu</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kerala-hc-hears-challenges-against-mandatory-imposition-of-aarogya-setu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 12:49:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kerala-hc-hears-challenges-against-mandatory-imposition-of-aarogya-setu/</guid>
      <description>The Kerala High Court has directed MeitY to file a response to petitions challenging mandatory imposition of Aarogya Setu and to state on record that data collected by the app will not be misused.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
