<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>IT Rules on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/it-rules/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IT Rules on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 06:36:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/it-rules/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>#SocialMediaComplianceWatch: analysis of Social Media Compliance Reports for the month of January 2022</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ssmi-compliance-jan-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 06:36:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ssmi-compliance-jan-2022/</guid>
      <description>Google (including YouTube), Facebook, Instagram (both are now under Meta), ShareChat, Snap, Twitter and WhatsApp have released their reports in compliance with Rule 4(1)(d) of the IT Rules 2021 for the month of January, 2022. We have analysed them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News publishers furnish their details voluntarily, MIB claims in RTI Appeal</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/rule-18-it-rules-rti-appeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 06:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/rule-18-it-rules-rti-appeal/</guid>
      <description>News publishers were sent notices under the IT Rules, even after major parts of the IT Rules were stayed. The MIB said that news publishers have only offered this information “voluntarily”, i.e. that there is no compulsion to respond to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh&#39;s Proposed Regulation = Indian IT Rules, 2021. Overreaching, invasive and suppressive.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/report-on-bangladeshs-regulation-of-digital-social-media-and-ott-platforms-and-it-rules-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 07:35:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/report-on-bangladeshs-regulation-of-digital-social-media-and-ott-platforms-and-it-rules-2021/</guid>
      <description>The regulator in Bangladesh invited comments on draft rules which are similar to IT Rules, 2021. In response, IFF has submitted a report which details India&amp;rsquo;s experience with IT Rules, 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxford Pro Bono Publico releases its report on the Regulation of Digital Media and Intermediaries</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/oxford-pro-bono-publico-releases-its-report-on-the-regulation-of-digital-media-and-intermediaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 05:49:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/oxford-pro-bono-publico-releases-its-report-on-the-regulation-of-digital-media-and-intermediaries/</guid>
      <description>To assist challenges to IT Rules, w​e reached out to Oxford Pro Bono Publico (OPBP) - a research centre at the Oxford University, requesting research on laws in other countries on social media platforms, digital news media and OTT platforms. OPBP has published their research report in December 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#SocialMediaComplianceWatch: analysis of Social Media Compliance Reports for the month of December 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ssmi-compliance-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 12:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ssmi-compliance-december/</guid>
      <description>Google (including YouTube), Facebook, Instagram (now Meta), ShareChat, Snap, Twitter and WhatsApp have released their reports under Rule 4(1)(d) of the IT Rules 2021 for the month of Dec &amp;lsquo;21. The latest of these was published by Meta and was made available in late Jan &amp;lsquo;22. We&amp;rsquo;ve analysed them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#SocialMediaComplianceWatch: analysis of Social Media Compliance Reports of November, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ssmi-compliance-november/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 07:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ssmi-compliance-november/</guid>
      <description>Google (including YouTube), Facebook, Instagram, ShareChat, Snap, Twitter and WhatsApp have released their reports in compliance with Rule 4(1)(d) of the IT Rules 2021 for the month of November, 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revealed: Over two thousand news publishers furnished their details to the MIB, despite Bombay HC’s stay</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/revealed-two-thousand-news-publishers-furnished-details-to-mib/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 06:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/revealed-two-thousand-news-publishers-furnished-details-to-mib/</guid>
      <description>IFF filed an RTI Application to find out whether the MIB has issued notices for information to news publishers, and to which publishers. The MIB has admitted that it has indeed issued two such notices, and that more than two thousand publishers have responded to these notices!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#SocialMediaComplianceWatch: analysis of Social Media Compliance Reports of October, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/compliance-report-oct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 09:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/compliance-report-oct/</guid>
      <description>Social Media platforms have released their reports for Oct  2021 in compliance with Rule 4(1)(d), IT Rules 2021. They continue to suffer from the same shortcomings, which exhibits lack of effort on the part of the SSMIs and the govt. to further transparency and accountability in platform governance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#SocialMediaComplianceWatch: analysis of Social Media Compliance Reports of September, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ssmis-compliance-reports-for-september/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 06:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ssmis-compliance-reports-for-september/</guid>
      <description>SSMI reports in compliance with Rule 4(1)(d) of the Information Technology (Guidelines for Intermediaries and Digital Media Ethics Code) Rules, 2021 have been analysed for the month of September.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DHC directs CIC to decide IFF’s appeals within 8 weeks</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dhc-directs-cic-to-decide-iffs-appeals-within-8-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 08:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dhc-directs-cic-to-decide-iffs-appeals-within-8-weeks/</guid>
      <description>Delhi High Court directs CIC to decide IFF&amp;rsquo;s appeals which seek statistical data regarding the surveillance orders under Section 69 of the Information Technology Act, 2000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factcheck! The IT Rules 2021 FAQ</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/factcheck-of-the-it-rules-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 08:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/factcheck-of-the-it-rules-faq/</guid>
      <description>MEITY has published Frequently Asked Questions to ‘bring clarity’ to IT Rules, 21. We separate the Facts from the Claims made in the FAQ document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social media giants have released their Compliance Reports for the month of August. We’ve analysed them.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/social-media-giants-have-released-their-compliance-reports-for-the-month-of-august-weve-analysed-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 05:17:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/social-media-giants-have-released-their-compliance-reports-for-the-month-of-august-weve-analysed-them/</guid>
      <description>Google (including YouTube), Facebook, Instagram, WhatsApp and Twitter have released their reports in compliance with Rule 4(1)(d) of the IT Rules 2021 for the month of August.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
