<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Supreme Court on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://internerfreedom.in/tags/supreme-court/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Supreme Court on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://internerfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 10:52:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://internerfreedom.in/tags/supreme-court/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spooked by the Zombie? Ministry of Home Affairs issues notification directing all S.66A cases to stop</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/spooked-by-the-zombie-ministry-of-home-affairs-issues-notification-directing-all-s-66a-cases-to-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 10:52:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/spooked-by-the-zombie-ministry-of-home-affairs-issues-notification-directing-all-s-66a-cases-to-stop/</guid>
      <description>Prompted by our application, the Ministry of Home Affairs, on July 14, 2021 issued a notification directing all law enforcement authorities to stop registering new cases under Section 66A of the Information Technology Act, 2000 and to immediately withdraw all pending cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explained: Supreme Court upholds Delhi Assemblies summons to Facebook</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/explained-supreme-court-upholds-delhi-assemblies-summons-to-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 07:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/explained-supreme-court-upholds-delhi-assemblies-summons-to-facebook/</guid>
      <description>IFF explains the decision of the Supreme Court rejecting the plea filed by the Managing Director of Facebook India, Ajit Mohan against the summons issued by the Peace and Harmony Committee of Delhi Assembly which sought his appearance in an inquiry related to the Delhi Riots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Union of India seeks a transfer of cases challenging IT Rules, 2021</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/union-of-india-seeks-a-transfer-of-cases-challenging-it-rules-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 09:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/union-of-india-seeks-a-transfer-of-cases-challenging-it-rules-2021/</guid>
      <description>A two-judge bench of the Supreme Court has listed the Union of India&amp;rsquo;s transfer petition before another bench on 16th July 2021. The petition seeks a transfer to the Supreme Court of 4 cases challenging IT Rules, 2021 which are pending before different High Courts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PUCL approaches Supreme Court seeking directions against continued prosecutions under the unconstitutional Section 66A</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/pucl-approaches-supreme-court-seeking-directions-against-continued-prosecutions-under-the-unconstitutional-section-66a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 07:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/pucl-approaches-supreme-court-seeking-directions-against-continued-prosecutions-under-the-unconstitutional-section-66a/</guid>
      <description>Supreme Court issues notice in PUCL&amp;rsquo;s application seeking directions against continued enforcement of Section 66A. IFF provided legal assistance to PUCL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Striking the balance between privacy and public interest in judicial proceedings: Our comments to the Supreme Court’s Draft Live Streaming Rules</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/striking-the-balance-between-privacy-and-public-interest-in-judicial-proceedings-our-comments-to-the-supreme-courts-draft-live-streaming-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 08:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/striking-the-balance-between-privacy-and-public-interest-in-judicial-proceedings-our-comments-to-the-supreme-courts-draft-live-streaming-rules/</guid>
      <description>Draft Model Rules for Live-Streaming and Recording of Court Proceedings were released by the Supreme Court’s e-Committee. IFF submitted its comments to the Draft Rules welcoming the Rules, and suggesting that the Rules can strike a better balance between  privacy and public interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundation for Media Professionals writes to J&amp;K Govt seeking compliance with Anuradha Bhasin</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/foundation-for-media-professionals-writes-to-j-k-govt-seeking-compliance-with-anuradha-bhasin-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 07:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/foundation-for-media-professionals-writes-to-j-k-govt-seeking-compliance-with-anuradha-bhasin-2/</guid>
      <description>In May 2021 the Government of J&amp;amp;K suspended internet services on three occasions, without promptly publishing suspensions orders. Foundation of Media Professionals has addressed a legal notice to the Government of J&amp;amp;K asking them to comply with directions of the Supreme Court in Anuradha Bhasin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live and let Live: The Supreme Court releases draft rules for live streaming of court proceedings</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/live-and-let-live-the-supreme-court-releases-draft-rules-for-live-streaming-of-court-proceedings-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 14:11:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/live-and-let-live-the-supreme-court-releases-draft-rules-for-live-streaming-of-court-proceedings-2/</guid>
      <description>The e-Committee has released draft rules for live streaming of all proceedings in all courts. We strongly welcome this step, and offer small changes which can further improve the Rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We write to the Supreme Court e-Committee with CDL to improve the eCourts platform</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/we-write-to-the-supreme-court-e-committee-with-cdl-to-improve-the-ecourts-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 07:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/we-write-to-the-supreme-court-e-committee-with-cdl-to-improve-the-ecourts-platform/</guid>
      <description>We write to Supreme Court e-Committee highlighting the difficulties we faced on eCourt platform while building the Zombie Tracker. We have also provided our recommendations which seek to enable others to conduct data-driven research of judicial trends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indore administration curbs speech on social media</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/indore-administration-curbs-speech-on-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 13:03:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/indore-administration-curbs-speech-on-social-media/</guid>
      <description>Indore administration issued an over-broad order under Section 144(1) CrPC, 1973 banning speech related to Covid-19 on social media platforms. We have filed an application before the  Collector, Indore seeking withdrawal of the Order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buffering Justice : A call for greater participation in the Draft Vision Document for Judicial Digitisation</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/digitization-of-indian-judiciary-phase-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 05:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/digitization-of-indian-judiciary-phase-iii/</guid>
      <description>E-Committee has released the draft vision document of e-Courts Project Phase III. We encourage you to submit your comments on &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ecommittee@aij.gov.in&#34;&gt;ecommittee@aij.gov.in&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, we have provided our inputs on the document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comments on the Draft Social Security Rules to safeguard worker&#39;s rights #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/worker-surveillance-through-labour-reforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 09:12:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/worker-surveillance-through-labour-reforms/</guid>
      <description>The Ministry of Labour released the Draft Code on Social Security (Central) Rules, 2020. In our comments on the draft, we have highlighted the following issues: mandatory aadhaar based verification and inadequate security safeguards for employee databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Section 118A repeal important steps remain for the Government of Kerala</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/after-section-118a-repeals-important-steps-remain-for-the-government-of-kerala/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 08:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/after-section-118a-repeals-important-steps-remain-for-the-government-of-kerala/</guid>
      <description>Read our proposals to the Government of Kerala to help avoid any overbroad or unnecessary criminalisation of online speech while also making sure abuse, threats or any of the harms that emerge on social media can be checked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As internet restrictions in J&amp;K cross 480 days, we await SC judgement #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/non-publication-of-internet-shutdown-review-orders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 07:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/non-publication-of-internet-shutdown-review-orders/</guid>
      <description>Non-publication of orders issued by the Review Committee and Special Committee continues to remain a problem in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir which must be decided by the Supreme Court to ensure independent application of mind by these bodies and implementation of their recommendations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Govt agrees to staggered restoration of 4G mobile internet  in J&amp;K before the Supreme Court #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/staggered-4g-restoration-j-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 08:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/staggered-4g-restoration-j-k/</guid>
      <description>During today&amp;rsquo;s hearing in Foundation for Media Professionals&#39; contempt petition relating to the internet restrictions in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir, the government agreed to restore 4G mobile internet in one district of Jammu and Kashmir each on a trial basis after 15 August i.e. Independence Day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FMP files rejoinder before SC about Jammu &amp; Kashmir 4G mobile internet ban #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/fmp-contempt-petition-rejoinder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 08:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/fmp-contempt-petition-rejoinder/</guid>
      <description>During today&amp;rsquo;s hearing before the Supreme Court, the Solicitor General sought an adjournment to go through FMP&amp;rsquo;s rejoinder which challenges secrecy in the functioning of the Special Committee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supreme Court directs Govt to file its reply in FMP&#39;s contempt petition #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/fmp-contempt-petition-reply/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 09:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/fmp-contempt-petition-reply/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court has directed the Government to file its reply in a contempt petition relating to the 4G mobile internet ban in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FMP demands compliance with SC directions by Special Committee for restoration of 4G in J&amp;K #KeepUsOnline #4GforAll</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/fmp-demands-compliance-with-sc-judgement-by-special-committee-for-restoration-of-4g-in-j-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 10:36:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/fmp-demands-compliance-with-sc-judgement-by-special-committee-for-restoration-of-4g-in-j-k/</guid>
      <description>FMP wrote to the Special Committee established by the Supreme Court seeking immediate review of internet restrictions in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir within 7 working days and publication of the Committee&amp;rsquo;s recommendations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supreme Court reserves order in petitions seeking restoration of 4G internet in Jammu &amp; Kashmir</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/sc-reserves-judgement-in-petitions-for-4g-restoration-in-j-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 11:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/sc-reserves-judgement-in-petitions-for-4g-restoration-in-j-k/</guid>
      <description>Today, the Supreme Court heard substantive arguments regarding the constitutionality and legality of the internet slowdown in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir during the COVID-19 pandemic and reserved its order in the matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supreme Court directs Govt to file reply to petition seeking restoration of 4G internet in J&amp;K #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/supreme-court-directs-govt-to-file-reply-to-petition-seeking-4g-restoration-in-j-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 08:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/supreme-court-directs-govt-to-file-reply-to-petition-seeking-4g-restoration-in-j-k/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court has directed the Government to file its response to petitions seeking restoration of 4G internet in J&amp;amp;K by Sunday i.e. 26 April and the matter will be listed again next Monday i.e. 27 April.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SC issues notice in FMP’s petition seeking restoration of 4G internet services in Jammu &amp; Kashmir during COVID-19 crisis #KeepUsOnline</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/sc-issues-notice-in-fmps-petition-seeking-restoration-of-4g-internet-services-in-jammu-kashmir-during-covid-19-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 09:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/sc-issues-notice-in-fmps-petition-seeking-restoration-of-4g-internet-services-in-jammu-kashmir-during-covid-19-crisis/</guid>
      <description>Today, a 3 judge bench of the Supreme Court issued notice in a petition filed by Foundation for Media Professionals against the internet slowdown in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir during the COVID-19 crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SC&#39;s Kashmir communication shutdown judgement is just the beginning of a long uphill campaign</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/scs-judgement-on-kashmir-communication-is-just-the-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 14:17:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/scs-judgement-on-kashmir-communication-is-just-the-beginning/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court&amp;rsquo;s judgement in Anuradha Bhasin v. Union of India is a step in the right direction but fails to provide immediate relief to Kashmiris who have already suffered immense hardship due to the 158 day communication shutdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap Part II: Kashmir Communication Shutdown and Movement Restrictions Cases</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/recap-part-ii-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-movement-restrictions-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 12:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/recap-part-ii-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-movement-restrictions-cases/</guid>
      <description>Part II of the Recap summarizes arguments made by the petitioners and the government about the constitutional validity of the communication shutdown and movement restrictions in Kashmir under Articles 19 and 21 of the Constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap Part I: Kashmir Communication Shutdown and Movement Restrictions Cases</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/recap-part-i-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-movement-restrictions-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 05:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/recap-part-i-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-movement-restrictions-cases/</guid>
      <description>Part I of the Recap summarizes the arguments made by the petitioners and the government about statutory compliance of the orders issued under the Telecom Suspension Rules 2017 and Section 144, Cr.P.C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government says judicial review of severity of the restrictions in Kashmir during August is an “academic exercise”</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/government-says-judicial-review-of-severity-of-the-restrictions-in-kashmir-during-august-is-an-academic-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 14:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/government-says-judicial-review-of-severity-of-the-restrictions-in-kashmir-during-august-is-an-academic-exercise/</guid>
      <description>In yesterday&amp;rsquo;s hearing, the Solicitor General argued that the telecom shutdown was necessary because digital platforms could be used for mobilisation by terrorists and separatists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journalistic bodies oppose communication and movement restrictions in Kashmir before the Supreme Court</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/journalistic-bodies-oppose-communication-and-movement-restrictions-in-kashmir-before-the-supreme-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 07:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/journalistic-bodies-oppose-communication-and-movement-restrictions-in-kashmir-before-the-supreme-court/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s hearing, Mr. Huzefa Ahmadi and Mr. Dushyant Dave advanced arguments on behalf of the Indian Journalists Union and Foundation for Media Professionals respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Substantive hearing in Anuradha Bhasin v. Union of India commences</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/substantive-hearing-in-anuradha-bhasin-v-union-of-india-commence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 13:36:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/substantive-hearing-in-anuradha-bhasin-v-union-of-india-commence/</guid>
      <description>In today’s hearing, Ms. Vrinda Grover used the govt’s statistics to prove there is no relation between the internet and rise in terrorism and argued there was no application of mind by the govt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A cellphone signal at the end of the tunnel? SC may finally hear substantive challenges to telecommunications shutdown in Kashmir around November</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/government-files-affidavit-in-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-press-freedom-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 12:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/government-files-affidavit-in-kashmir-communication-shutdown-and-press-freedom-case/</guid>
      <description>In Kashmir Communication Shutdown and Press Freedom Case, the Govt has argued that the restrictions are necessary because of terrorism and declined to provide any specific information to the Petitioner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FMP&#39;s and IJU&#39;s intervention permitted in Anuradha Bhasin&#39;s petition</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/fmp-and-ijus-intervention-permitted-in-anuradha-bhasins-petition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 11:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/fmp-and-ijus-intervention-permitted-in-anuradha-bhasins-petition/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court allows Foundation for Media Professionals and Indian Journalists Union to intervene in Anuradha Bhasin&amp;rsquo;s petition against the communication shutdown in Kashmir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundation for Media Professionals approaches Supreme Court 
to support journalistic freedom in Kashmir</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/foundation-for-media-professionals-approaches-supreme-court-to-support-journalistic-freedom-in-kashmir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 08:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/foundation-for-media-professionals-approaches-supreme-court-to-support-journalistic-freedom-in-kashmir/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s hearing, the SC wondered if the 40 day long suspension of telecom and internet services in Kashmir was a shutdown or breakdown. It finally directed the Govt. to file its response to the writ petition and intervention applications and urged selective restoration of communication channels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates from the Supreme Court: Facebook&#39;s transfer petition of the Aadhaar-social media linking case in the Madras HC.</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/updates-on-the-facebooks-transfer-petition-of-the-aadhaar-linking-madras-hc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 10:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/updates-on-the-facebooks-transfer-petition-of-the-aadhaar-linking-madras-hc/</guid>
      <description>The Hon&amp;rsquo;ble SC issues notice to respondents, permits hearings to be continued in the Madras HC but directs that no final orders be given.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF files rejoinder in PIL seeking surveillance reform</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/iff-files-rejoinder-in-pil-seeking-surveillance-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 14:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/iff-files-rejoinder-in-pil-seeking-surveillance-reform/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, IFF filed its rejoinder in the PIL seeking surveillance reform and reemphasized that judicial oversight is necessary in the surveillance process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supreme Court issues notice on IFF&#39;s petition for surveillance reform #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/supreme-court-issues-notice-on-iffs-petition-for-survelliance-reform-saveourprivacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 08:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/supreme-court-issues-notice-on-iffs-petition-for-survelliance-reform-saveourprivacy/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court today agreed to hear a case on the digital snooping powers of the government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF will represent your digital rights in the WhatsApp Privacy Case</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/iff-will-represent-your-digital-rights-in-the-whatsapp-privacy-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 15:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/iff-will-represent-your-digital-rights-in-the-whatsapp-privacy-case/</guid>
      <description>Today a constitutional bench of the Supreme Court heard the WhatsApp Privacy Case—Karmaya Singh Sareen v. Union of India SLP (C) No. 804 of 2017—in which the Internet Freedom Foundation intervened to make submissions. The other parties in the case included the Petitioner, the Union Government and private platforms, WhatsApp and Facebook Inc. This case comes from an appeal against a Delhi High Court judgment last year, in a case where two students had filed a legal petition challenging the change in WhatsApp&amp;rsquo;s privacy policy which would allow data sharing with Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement of concern on the Sabu Mathew George Case : Don’t “auto-block” online expression</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/statement-of-concern-on-the-sabu-mathew-george-case-dont-auto-block-online-expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 12:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/statement-of-concern-on-the-sabu-mathew-george-case-dont-auto-block-online-expression/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court of India has over the past one year passed various orders in the case of Sabu Mathew George v. Union of India &amp;amp; Ors. [WP(C) 341/2008] that are undermining internet freedom, particularly the right of free expression online. The case concerns allegations that search engines are acting in contravention of S. 22 of the Pre-Conception and Pre-Natal Diagnostic Techniques (Prohibition of Sex Selection) Act (hereinafter referred to as “the Act”) insofar as they are showing results relating to sex determination kits and techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
