<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Health Data on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/health-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health Data on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 14:08:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/health-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IFF submits its comments on the Draft Health Data Retention Policy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-comments-on-draft-health-data-retention/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 14:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-comments-on-draft-health-data-retention/</guid>
      <description>IFF has provided our comments on the Consultation Paper on Proposed Health Data Retention Policy. In our comments, we have tried to highlight the harms of mandatory data retention, issues around a fragmented healthcare regime and data portability issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read our Joint Letter with C-Help &amp; FMES to NHA on CoWIN’s updated API #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/read-our-joint-letter-with-c-help-fmes-to-nha-on-cowins-updated-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 07:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/read-our-joint-letter-with-c-help-fmes-to-nha-on-cowins-updated-api/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the National Health Authority with C-Help &amp;amp; FMES on their updated API which would allow government and private entities to know the vaccination status of individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF&#39;s recommendations for the United Health Interface</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/read-our-submission-on-the-unified-health-interface-consultation-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 01:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/read-our-submission-on-the-unified-health-interface-consultation-paper/</guid>
      <description>IFF has submitted its comments on the NDHM’s consultation paper on the Unified Health Interface.Our comments are focused on five key issues: the need for diverse feedback, market capture by the private sector, digital exclusion, financial exploitation, and the need for public digital infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing the NDHM’s Health Data Management Policy: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/analysing-the-ndhms-health-data-management-policy-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 08:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/analysing-the-ndhms-health-data-management-policy-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Along with the Centre for Health Equity, Law, and Policy, we have drafted a working paper analysing the NDHM&amp;rsquo;s Health Data Management Policy. Here, we look at issues of consent and confidentiality, data privacy and security, exclusion, and private sector access to health data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing the NDHM’s Health Data Management Policy: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/analysing-the-ndhms-health-data-management-policy-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 06:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/analysing-the-ndhms-health-data-management-policy-part-1/</guid>
      <description>We have drafted a working paper on the National Digital Health Mission’s Health Data Management Policy with the Centre for Health Equity, Law, and Policy. This post is part 1 of our analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delhi Government’s gag order on information on mucormycosis</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/delhi-governments-gag-order-on-information-on-mucormycosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 06:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/delhi-governments-gag-order-on-information-on-mucormycosis/</guid>
      <description>Recently, the Delhi Government issued a notification prohibiting anyone from sharing any information on mucormycosis without the prior permission of the Government. IFF has sent the Government a legal notice urging it to rescind this overbroad order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint Statement: Ensure equitable access to COVID-19 vaccines and health care resources</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/joint-statement-ensure-equitable-access-to-covid-vaccines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 07:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/joint-statement-ensure-equitable-access-to-covid-vaccines/</guid>
      <description>India is in a crisis. As people across the country battle the second wave of COVID-19, ensuring equitable, fast and easy access to healthcare, medicines and the vaccines is critical. The undersigned organizations and persons call on the Central Government, State Governments, Health Secretaries of the Union and the States, and the District Magistrates to ensure that the vaccination process focuses on increasing reach and accessibility, that there are no onerous ID requirements, including Aadhaar, for access to health services or vaccinations, and that health data is not misused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move fast, break things? Not when sensitive health data is at stake! #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ndhm-data-privacy-policy-consultation-submission/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 06:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ndhm-data-privacy-policy-consultation-submission/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the National Health Authority seeking enactment of general and sectoral data protection laws and meaningful public consultation prior to deployment of any national digital health ID programme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Digital Health Mission Data Policy Consultation: Not now, not like this, not without all of us! #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ndhm-data-policy-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 04:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ndhm-data-policy-representation/</guid>
      <description>Post Delhi HC hearing, a follow up  representation was sent by the petitioner highlighting continuing violation of statutory obligations and urging the government to re-calculate deadline for submission of feedback after implementing recommended changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delhi HC directs govt to consider  representation regarding national Health Data Management Policy #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ndhm-data-policy-delhi-hc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 08:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ndhm-data-policy-delhi-hc/</guid>
      <description>The petition heard by the Delhi HC raised concerns about the unreasonably short deadline for submission of feedback at the height of the COVID-19 pandemic, and highlighted how the existing process excludes persons with disabilities, non-English speakers and people without internet access.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
