<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>pegasus on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/categories/pegasus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pegasus on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 04:46:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/categories/pegasus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Our Response to the SC’s Technical Committee on Pegasus #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/our-response-to-the-scs-technical-committee-on-pegasus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 04:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/our-response-to-the-scs-technical-committee-on-pegasus/</guid>
      <description>Read our response to queries sent by the Technical Committee set up by the Hon&amp;rsquo;ble Supreme Court of India for investigating the use of the Pegasus spyware in India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress of Pegasus investigations around the world #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/progress_of_pegasus_investigations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 05:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/progress_of_pegasus_investigations/</guid>
      <description>Countries around the world were rocked by the Pegasus revelations. We take a look at the actions being taken in other jurisdictions in light of the shocking reports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF’s Statement on the Supreme Court Pegasus Committee</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iffs-statement-on-the-sc-pegasus-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 08:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iffs-statement-on-the-sc-pegasus-committee/</guid>
      <description>Read our statement on the committee of technical experts appointed by the Supreme Court of India to look into the Pegasus spyware revelations made in July.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SC appoints a committee to examine the use of Pegasus Spyware in India</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/sc-appoints-a-committee-to-examine-the-use-of-pegasus-spyware-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 07:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/sc-appoints-a-committee-to-examine-the-use-of-pegasus-spyware-in-india/</guid>
      <description>Supreme Court has appointed a committee of technical experts overseen by Justice R. V. Raveendran, to examine the use of Pegasus Spyware on Indian Citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pegasus Scandal: it&#39;s been two months with no investigation! #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/pegasus-2-months-on-still-no-investigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 09:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/pegasus-2-months-on-still-no-investigation/</guid>
      <description>Read our submission to the West Bengal Commission of Inquiry on the Pegasus issue in which we highlight the need to question the relevant government stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Arsenal Reports: The rise of targeted surveillance in India</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-arsenal-reports-bhima-koregaon-arrests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 07:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-arsenal-reports-bhima-koregaon-arrests/</guid>
      <description>The reports by Arsenal Consulting show that  some of the BK-16 were surveilled and incriminating documents planted on their computers. We analyse what this means for the rise of targeted surveillance in India in light of the recent Pegasus revelations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#4 Cybersec Charcha: A Global overview of the state of surveillance after the pegasus revelations</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/4-cybersec-charcha-a-global-overview-of-the-state-of-surveillance-after-the-pegasus-revelations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 12:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/4-cybersec-charcha-a-global-overview-of-the-state-of-surveillance-after-the-pegasus-revelations/</guid>
      <description>Your monthly round-up of all things cybersecurity! This edition of Cybersec Charcha focuses on spyware, the Pegasus Project reports and the booming surveillance industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pegasus: Rupesh Kumar Singh and Ipsa Shatakshi and other journalists approach SC</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/pegasus-rupesh-kumar-singh-and-ipsa-shatakshi-and-other-journalists-approach-sc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 06:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/pegasus-rupesh-kumar-singh-and-ipsa-shatakshi-and-other-journalists-approach-sc/</guid>
      <description>Rupesh Kumar Singh and Ipsa Shatakshi, activists reporting on issues related to Adivasi people in Jharkhand, approached the SC asking to declare that the use of a spyware such as Pegasus is unconstitutional. IFF has provided legal assistance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Line-by-line verification of the IT Minister&#39;s Statement on the Pegasus Hacks</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/line-by-line-verification-of-the-it-ministers-statement-on-the-pegasus-hacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 08:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/line-by-line-verification-of-the-it-ministers-statement-on-the-pegasus-hacks/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we present to you a line-by-line verification of the IT Minister&amp;rsquo;s statement on Pegasus, wherein we use a constitutional, legal, and people-centric lens to debunk and correct falsehoods and misinterpretations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State Governments need to step up on the Pegasus issue</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/state-governments-need-to-step-up-on-the-pegasus-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 05:34:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/state-governments-need-to-step-up-on-the-pegasus-issue/</guid>
      <description>Cognisant of the legal injuries as well as the violations of fundamental rights that have occurred in light of the Pegasus spyware revelations, we wrote to the state governments of Maharashtra &amp;amp; Chhattisgarh to institute investigations into the use of spyware against citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear Standing Committee, We Have Some Questions on Pegasus</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dear-standing-committee-we-have-some-questions-on-pegasus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 07:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dear-standing-committee-we-have-some-questions-on-pegasus/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the Standing Committee on IT with questions for the MHA, MeitY and MoC related to the Pegasus revelations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF’s Statement on Hacking Revelations made by the Pegasus Project</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iffs-statement-on-hacking-revelations-made-by-the-pegasus-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 05:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iffs-statement-on-hacking-revelations-made-by-the-pegasus-project/</guid>
      <description>Read our statement in response to the revelations made by the Pegasus Project which revealed that over 300 verified Indian mobile telephone numbers were targeted by the Israeli spyware firm, NSO Group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement: IFF joins international civil society orgs to oppose the NSO Group’s attempt to evade responsibility for the Pegasus Hack #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ninth-circuit-amici-brief-whatsapp-nso-group-pegasus-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 05:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ninth-circuit-amici-brief-whatsapp-nso-group-pegasus-hack/</guid>
      <description>8 civil society organisations from across the world including IFF have filed an amici brief before the Ninth Circuit Federal Court of Appeals in California urging the Court to dismiss the NSO Group&amp;rsquo;s appeal claiming sovereign immunity for the Pegasus hack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement: One year of inaction, delay and evasion on the NSO-Pegasus hack #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/nso-pegasus-hack-one-year-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 05:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/nso-pegasus-hack-one-year-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>Despite multiple government and parliamentary bodies examining the Pegasus hack, a whole year has passed and we still do not know who was responsible for this egregious violation of the privacy of human rights defenders in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The need to investigate the NSO Group, which was behind the Pegasus software, is now more than ever. #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-need-to-investigate-the-nso-group-which-was-behind-the-pegasus-software-is-now-more-than-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 06:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-need-to-investigate-the-nso-group-which-was-behind-the-pegasus-software-is-now-more-than-ever/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the Chief Ministers of Maharashtra and Chhattisgarh urging them to establish committees to investigate the Whatsapp hack. Our key recommendations were to include victim and expert testimony in the investigation which should be carried out in a transparent manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We ask the Committee on IT to let those targeted by Pegasus be heard!</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/heres-what-we-ask-the-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 06:12:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/heres-what-we-ask-the-committee/</guid>
      <description>We ask the Standing Committee to invite those affected by Pegasus to provide testimonials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We provide the Standing Committees on Home Affairs with suggestions as they discuss the Pegasus scandal.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-ask-the-standing-committees-on-home-affairs-and-information-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 08:07:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-ask-the-standing-committees-on-home-affairs-and-information-technology/</guid>
      <description>Press reports indicate interest has been showed by the Standing Committee on Home Affairs in examining the matter. We wrote to them with a few suggestions on the issue to take into consideration at their meeting today.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
