<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>PDPB on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://internerfreedom.in/tags/pdpb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PDPB on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://internerfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 06:47:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://internerfreedom.in/tags/pdpb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>#PrivacyOfThePeople - Why Student Data should be Students’ Data</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/why-student-data-should-be-students-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 06:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/why-student-data-should-be-students-data/</guid>
      <description>In the continuation of our weekly series #PrivacyOfThePeople, we examine the growing interest in students’ data and what the Bill has to say when it comes to student data. We explore the need to secure such data as well as why current regulations inadequately protect student data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: India’s incoming data laws need our urgent attention</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/update-indias-incoming-data-laws-need-our-urgent-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 10:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/update-indias-incoming-data-laws-need-our-urgent-attention/</guid>
      <description>The report of the Joint Parliamentary Committee on the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019 is to be submitted next week. In this blogpost, we look at the possible ways forward for the Bill, highlight some of the issues that may emerge, and provide recommendations for addressing them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will India&#39;s Healthcare Data Be Protected? #PrivacyOfThePeople</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/will-indias-healthcare-data-be-protected-privacy-of-the-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 05:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/will-indias-healthcare-data-be-protected-privacy-of-the-people/</guid>
      <description>In the continuation of our weekly series #PrivacyOfThePeople, we look at the impact of the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019 in relation to healthcare data. We explore the need to secure such data as well as why private companies and foreign hackers are interested in the data of senior citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Data Protection Bill and Social Media Users: #PrivacyOfThePeople</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/privacyofthepeople-social-media-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 06:13:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/privacyofthepeople-social-media-users/</guid>
      <description>In our new weekly series  #PrivacyOfThePeople, we look at the impact of the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019 on different sections of society.  In this post, we discuss whether the Bill actually protects user data  when it comes to social media platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#PrivacyOfThePeople - Agristack and Farmers’ Issues</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/privacy-of-the-people-agristack-and-farmer-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 12:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/privacy-of-the-people-agristack-and-farmer-issues/</guid>
      <description>In the second post in our #PrivacyOfThePeople series, we discuss the issue of farmer rights under the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019 with respect to aggressive digitization by governmental initiatives. Who really benefits from Agristack systems and how does a loss of privacy affect farmers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#PrivacyofThePeople - ASHA Workers and Employee Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/privacyofthepeople-asha-workers-and-employee-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 10:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/privacyofthepeople-asha-workers-and-employee-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>In our new series #PrivacyofThePeople, we will look at the impact of the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019 on different sections of society. In this post, we discuss how the Bill affects workplace surveillance at large through the ASHA workers’ recent fight for digital privacy and detail .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our recommendations to protect Indians against data breaches</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/our-recommendations-to-protect-indians-against-data-breaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 06:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/our-recommendations-to-protect-indians-against-data-breaches/</guid>
      <description>In view of the rise in data breaches, we write to MEITY with recommendations to prevent data breaches and provide redressal against them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: Protecting whistleblowers, digital security researchers, and vulnerability testers</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-protecting-whistleblowers-digital-security-researchers-and-vulnerability-testers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 08:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-protecting-whistleblowers-digital-security-researchers-and-vulnerability-testers/</guid>
      <description>In Part 10 of the #DataProtectionTop10 series, we discuss the need for protection of whistleblowers, digital security researchers, and vulnerability testers. We recommend that the Bill make suitable amendments to provide clear provisions detailing such protections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: Some holes that need to be plugged</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-some-holes-that-need-to-be-plugged/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 06:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-some-holes-that-need-to-be-plugged/</guid>
      <description>In Part 9 of the #DataProtectionTop10, we analyse some miscellaneous provisions in the PDPB and recommend that the Bill acknowledge a natural person as the owner of her data, provide sound provisions for facilitating the transition to the new regime, and give the RTI Act precedence over the Bill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: On the Importance of a Strong, Transparent, and Independent Data Protection Authority</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-on-the-importance-of-a-strong-and-independent-data-protection-authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 07:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-on-the-importance-of-a-strong-and-independent-data-protection-authority/</guid>
      <description>We analyse the provisions in the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019 which relate to the Data Protection Authority of India (DPA) and its independence, transparency, and constitution. We recommend that it not be bound by the Central Government&amp;rsquo;s orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Despite CIC’s observation that MeitY&#39;s response to us was “grossly improper,&#34; MeitY issues the same response again #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/meity-response-was-grossly-improper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 06:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/meity-response-was-grossly-improper/</guid>
      <description>CIC directed the CPIO to re-visit our original RTI and provide a revised reply and info, if (comments on consultation on PDPB). However, the CPIO simply cited the same exemption under S.8 of the RTI Act that she had provided before the CIC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: 
State Security and Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-state-security-and-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 09:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-state-security-and-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>In Part 7 of the #DataProtectionTop 10 series, we discuss the provisions in the Bill which enable the State to engage in large scale surveillance. Blanket exemptions without a sound oversight and review mechanism raise concerns. Thus, we recommend that a chapter on surveillance reforms be inserted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: Data Localisation</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectionttop10-data-localisation-a-threat-to-free-and-open-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 06:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectionttop10-data-localisation-a-threat-to-free-and-open-internet/</guid>
      <description>In part 6 of the #DataProtectionTop10 series, we look at the restrictions imposed by the PDPB on the transfer of personal data outside India. We recommend that the Bill explicitly define critical personal data and not impose undue restrictions that affect the open nature of the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: Voluntary Social Media Verification</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-voluntary-social-media-verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 08:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-voluntary-social-media-verification/</guid>
      <description>In Part 5 of the #DataProtectionTop10 series, we analyse the various issues with the inclusion of social media intermediaries under the  Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019, and the provision for voluntary verification of user accounts.  We recommend that the relevant clauses be removed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: On the need to protect the rights of users</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-on-the-need-to-protect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 08:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-on-the-need-to-protect/</guid>
      <description>In part 4 of the #DataProtectionTop10 series, we explore the issues with the user rights under the Bill. Certain rights are not absolute and contain significant exemptions. The Bill also fails to include certain rights. To address these concerns, we recommend changes to strengthen user rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: Exceptions to Consent - A Torn Safety Net</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-exceptions-to-consent-a-torn-safety-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 08:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-exceptions-to-consent-a-torn-safety-net/</guid>
      <description>In part 3 of the #DataProtectionTop10 series, we look into various issues regarding the consent provisions for the processing of the personal data under the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: Impostors under the Personal Data Protection Bill</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-imposters-under-the-personal-data-protection-bill/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 07:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-imposters-under-the-personal-data-protection-bill/</guid>
      <description>In post 2 of the #DataProtectionTop10 series, we examine provisions on government access to non-personal data and setting up of privacy sandboxes, and discuss potential changes that could be made to include a more rights based perspective on non-personal data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: Lost in Muddled Objectives</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-lost-in-muddled-objectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 07:59:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-lost-in-muddled-objectives/</guid>
      <description>This is a new series on the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019 to deal exclusively with the issues and pathways for reform under the Bill. In this post we look at the objective and the Preamble of the Bill, and guage whether the bill serve ordinary Indians or the government and large corporations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#StartfromScratch: Constitutional Utopias of Digital Protection</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/constitutional-utopias-of-digital-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 04:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/constitutional-utopias-of-digital-protection/</guid>
      <description>In the final piece in our series on the Data Protection Bill, we first explain the 7 fundamental principles of the Indian Privacy Code. Then we analyse two alternative data protection bills: the Data (Privacy and Protection) Bill, 2017 and the Personal Data and Information Privacy Code Bill, 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breach please! Why companies like Facebook need to be held accountable by CERT-IN.</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/breach-please-why-companies-like-fb-need-to-be-held-accountable-by-cert-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 05:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/breach-please-why-companies-like-fb-need-to-be-held-accountable-by-cert-in/</guid>
      <description>Personal data of 60 Lakh Indian Facebook users is available on the internet for free. We provide suggestions on what you can do and we update you on the steps we have taken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#StartFromScratch: Why is the data protection bill being criticized?</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/why-is-the-data-bill-being-criticized/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 06:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/why-is-the-data-bill-being-criticized/</guid>
      <description>In the third edition of #StartFromScratch, we explain the key issues with the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CIC observes that IT Ministry&#39;s denial on RTI for comments on the Data Protection Bill is, &#34;grossly improper&#34; #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/persist-transparency-dpd-cic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 05:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/persist-transparency-dpd-cic/</guid>
      <description>In a positive order in our second appeal related to the Data Protection Bill, the CIC directed the CPIO of MeitY to re-visit the RTI application and provide us with a revised reply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#StartFromScratch: The data bill series, part 1!</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/startfromscratch-the-data-bill-series-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 13:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/startfromscratch-the-data-bill-series-part-1/</guid>
      <description>This is the first blogpost in our series on the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019, as we explain what the Bill is, what concerns have been raised about it, and what we can expect after its implementation. Do check out our social media to see the corresponding videos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policies of Telecom Service Providers - Or Why You Shouldn&#39;t Just Click Accept</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/privacy-policies-of-telecom-service-providers-or-why-you-shouldnt-just-click-accept/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 06:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/privacy-policies-of-telecom-service-providers-or-why-you-shouldnt-just-click-accept/</guid>
      <description>We analysed the privacy of policies of the 4 large telecom service providers to check not only whether they were Puttaswamy-compliant, but also whether they would need updating in the face of the  Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019. We found certain alarming issues in these policies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Empowerment is a result of Data Rights</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/data-empowerment-is-a-result-of-data-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 06:57:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/data-empowerment-is-a-result-of-data-rights/</guid>
      <description>IFF has submitted its comments on the draft Data Empowerment and Protection Architecture Policy. Our comments highlighted four main issues: ensuring truly informed consent, orienting new technology towards citizens, implementing a robust regulatory mechanism, and expanding the role of civil society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening the Joint Parliamentary Committee process on the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/strengthening-the-working-of-the-jpc-on-the-pdpb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 06:03:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/strengthening-the-working-of-the-jpc-on-the-pdpb/</guid>
      <description>The Joint Parliamentary Committee for Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019 is considering a revolutionary legislative proposal. To strengthen its process we request that the JPC work within its mandate and not consider extraneous issues, and that it consider more consultations with civil society.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
