<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Breach on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/categories/data-breach/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Breach on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 05:29:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/categories/data-breach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Government Wants To Sell Your Data | #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-government-wants-to-sell-your-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 05:29:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-government-wants-to-sell-your-data/</guid>
      <description>We respond to the Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology&amp;rsquo;s Draft Data Access Policy. The policy raises serious privacy concerns due to its perverse economic incentives on data sharing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student data exposed on Andhra Pradesh Government Examination website!</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ap-gov-students-data-leak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 14:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ap-gov-students-data-leak/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr
Sai Sravan Prabhala, a cyber-security researcher, informed us of a critical vulnerability exposing the sensitive personal information of minors. This existed on the website of the Directorate of Government Examinations, Government of Andhra Pradesh’s for the 2021 examinations. While this functionality itself has been removed, to prevent it from occurring again assisted by Sai, we have written to them and CERT-In.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF explains: An Election Commission vulnerability that could expose your phone number!</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ec-vulnerability-ph-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 09:38:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ec-vulnerability-ph-number/</guid>
      <description>A vulnerability in the ECI’s National Voters Service Portal website was exposed by an independent security researcher in December last year. The vulnerability allowed access to un-redacted, registered phone numbers of voters. The vulnerability was eventually patched by the ECI IT team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#6 Cybersec Charcha: What comes after Breach Pe Breach?</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/6-cybersec-charcha-what-comes-after-breach-pe-breach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 07:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/6-cybersec-charcha-what-comes-after-breach-pe-breach/</guid>
      <description>Data breaches are now becoming increasingly common. In a scenario like this, it becomes really important to learn not only how you can protect yourself, but also the measures you can take if your data is leaked in a data breach.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
