<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>year in review on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/categories/year-in-review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in year in review on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 10:47:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/categories/year-in-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2021: New beginnings in digital security</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digisec-review-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 10:47:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digisec-review-2021/</guid>
      <description>2021 was an important year for us because we did a lot of new things. Over this short year end catch up on digital security, we’ll walk you through what we did, our achievements and disappointments, and more importantly what we learned and our path ahead in 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021: Building a stronger IFF with Community and Operations</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ops-review-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 07:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ops-review-2021/</guid>
      <description>Fundraising : In numbers IFF’s fundraising model is based on individualised giving and the membership programme (recurring donations) has always been at the core of it. Over the past year, our membership base grew to 427 recurring donors, donating at an average of Rs. 800 on a month to month basis. However, after the new RBI guidelines on recurring transactions came into effect on October 1, 2021, we witnessed a 70% drop off in memberships, shaving off Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021: Bringing public policy closer to the public</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/policy-review-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 05:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/policy-review-2021/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr Throughout 2021, we have tried to respond to the various policy initiatives and projects launched by the Central and State governments with meaningful and privacy-respecting policy analysis. We have also utilized the Right to Information Act, 2005 to bring accountability in the working of every public authority.
Consultations Parliamentary engagement The importance of digital rights has grown leaps and bounds in recent times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 : Digital Transparency informs public debate</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/transparency-review-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 03:11:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/transparency-review-2021/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr Throughout 2021, we have tried to raise awareness around the various policies and projects that the Central and State government have developed and introduced. By utilising the Right to Information Act, 2005 as well as the Information Technology (Guidelines for Intermediaries and Digital Media Ethics Code) Rules, 2021 (‘IT Rules 2021’), we have tried to bring transparency &amp;amp; accountability in the working of every public authority and significant social media intermediary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021: A year of standing for your digital rights in courts</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/2021-lit-year-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 07:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/2021-lit-year-review/</guid>
      <description>As a digital liberties organisation, IFF’s mission statement is to ensure that Indian citizens can use the internet with liberties guaranteed by the Constitution. To that end, we engage in strategic litigation to defend the rights of the litigants that approach us and make incremental changes in society. In 2020, as all of us relied on digital connections more than ever, issues such as access to the internet, surveillance, censorship and data protection gained prominence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 in Review: Impact through Strategic Litigation</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/year-in-review-digital-rights-litigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 04:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/year-in-review-digital-rights-litigation/</guid>
      <description>Despite the challenges posed by the COVID-19 pandemic, IFF has provided legal representation to nine organizations and individuals in 2020. The clients we have represented this year include media organizations, businessmen, environmentalists, disability rights activists and RTI activists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 in Review: Transparency for our digital rights</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/year-in-review-transparency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/year-in-review-transparency/</guid>
      <description>Read about all our initiatives throughout the year to increase transparency and accountability around digital rights issues in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 in Review: Policy Advocacy in the year of Covid</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-year-in-review-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-year-in-review-policy/</guid>
      <description>2020 has been quite the eventful year, and the policy front was no different. Here is a quick breakdown of all that we achieved this year. For 2021, we hope to further increase our collaboration to increase the impact of digital rights across the spectrum of individual liberty and social welfare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 in Review: Scaling up IFF&#39;s Operations and Community</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/year-in-review-scaling-up-iffs-operations-and-commuity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 05:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/year-in-review-scaling-up-iffs-operations-and-commuity/</guid>
      <description>In January 2020, we set out with concise goals: Streamline and standardise internal processes and pick up the pace with our community engagement efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
