<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Protection on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/data-protection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Protection on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 12:22:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/data-protection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>#4 Cybersec Charcha: A Global overview of the state of surveillance after the pegasus revelations</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/4-cybersec-charcha-a-global-overview-of-the-state-of-surveillance-after-the-pegasus-revelations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 12:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/4-cybersec-charcha-a-global-overview-of-the-state-of-surveillance-after-the-pegasus-revelations/</guid>
      <description>Your monthly round-up of all things cybersecurity! This edition of Cybersec Charcha focuses on spyware, the Pegasus Project reports and the booming surveillance industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#PrivacyOfThePeople - To Date or To Data? / Swipe Left on Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/privacyofthepeople-to-date-or-to-data-swipe-left-on-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 05:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/privacyofthepeople-to-date-or-to-data-swipe-left-on-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>In continuation of our weekly series #PrivacyOfThePeople, we examine how dating and matrimonial services share your personal data and just how well the Bill protects us. We explore the need to secure such data as well as why the current regulations are inadequate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing Examination Data: No Child’s Play</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/securing-examination-data-no-childs-play-untitled/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 05:55:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/securing-examination-data-no-childs-play-untitled/</guid>
      <description>Concerned about the threat to children&amp;rsquo;s privacy and safety caused by such data breaches, in July 2021, IFF sent thirty-two representations to the State and Union Territory Commissions for the Protection of Child Rights in India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women’s safety on the internet has to account for intersectionality</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/womens-safety-on-the-internet-intersectionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 12:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/womens-safety-on-the-internet-intersectionality/</guid>
      <description>In light of recent incident wherein women belonging to the Muslim community were targeted, we have written to the NCW &amp;amp; DCW with our recommendations as well as to GoDaddy.com asking them to remove the domain registered with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: India’s incoming data laws need our urgent attention</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/update-indias-incoming-data-laws-need-our-urgent-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 10:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/update-indias-incoming-data-laws-need-our-urgent-attention/</guid>
      <description>The report of the Joint Parliamentary Committee on the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019 is to be submitted next week. In this blogpost, we look at the possible ways forward for the Bill, highlight some of the issues that may emerge, and provide recommendations for addressing them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will India&#39;s Healthcare Data Be Protected? #PrivacyOfThePeople</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/will-indias-healthcare-data-be-protected-privacy-of-the-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 05:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/will-indias-healthcare-data-be-protected-privacy-of-the-people/</guid>
      <description>In the continuation of our weekly series #PrivacyOfThePeople, we look at the impact of the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019 in relation to healthcare data. We explore the need to secure such data as well as why private companies and foreign hackers are interested in the data of senior citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for June, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-june-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 06:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-june-2021/</guid>
      <description>Since our last report for the month of May, IFF has filed 18  RTI requests, 2 First Appeals and 1 Second Appeal. Here, we give you an overview of the requests filed and why demanding transparency and accountability from Government authorities essential in our fight to protect digital rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Data Protection Bill and Social Media Users: #PrivacyOfThePeople</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/privacyofthepeople-social-media-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 06:13:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/privacyofthepeople-social-media-users/</guid>
      <description>In our new weekly series  #PrivacyOfThePeople, we look at the impact of the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019 on different sections of society.  In this post, we discuss whether the Bill actually protects user data  when it comes to social media platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government endorses the use of facial recognition for “touchless” vaccination process</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/government-endorses-the-use-of-facial-recognition-for-touchless-vaccination-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 04:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/government-endorses-the-use-of-facial-recognition-for-touchless-vaccination-process/</guid>
      <description>We filed an RTI application with the Ministry of Health and Family Welfare to verify reports about the government using facial recognition technology (FRT) for the verification of beneficiaries of the COVID-19 vaccines. In their response the Ministry confirmed the use of FRT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#PrivacyOfThePeople - Agristack and Farmers’ Issues</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/privacy-of-the-people-agristack-and-farmer-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 12:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/privacy-of-the-people-agristack-and-farmer-issues/</guid>
      <description>In the second post in our #PrivacyOfThePeople series, we discuss the issue of farmer rights under the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019 with respect to aggressive digitization by governmental initiatives. Who really benefits from Agristack systems and how does a loss of privacy affect farmers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#PrivacyofThePeople - ASHA Workers and Employee Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/privacyofthepeople-asha-workers-and-employee-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 10:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/privacyofthepeople-asha-workers-and-employee-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>In our new series #PrivacyofThePeople, we will look at the impact of the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019 on different sections of society. In this post, we discuss how the Bill affects workplace surveillance at large through the ASHA workers’ recent fight for digital privacy and detail .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our recommendations to protect Indians against data breaches</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/our-recommendations-to-protect-indians-against-data-breaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 06:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/our-recommendations-to-protect-indians-against-data-breaches/</guid>
      <description>In view of the rise in data breaches, we write to MEITY with recommendations to prevent data breaches and provide redressal against them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: Protecting whistleblowers, digital security researchers, and vulnerability testers</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-protecting-whistleblowers-digital-security-researchers-and-vulnerability-testers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 08:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-protecting-whistleblowers-digital-security-researchers-and-vulnerability-testers/</guid>
      <description>In Part 10 of the #DataProtectionTop10 series, we discuss the need for protection of whistleblowers, digital security researchers, and vulnerability testers. We recommend that the Bill make suitable amendments to provide clear provisions detailing such protections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: Some holes that need to be plugged</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-some-holes-that-need-to-be-plugged/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 06:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-some-holes-that-need-to-be-plugged/</guid>
      <description>In Part 9 of the #DataProtectionTop10, we analyse some miscellaneous provisions in the PDPB and recommend that the Bill acknowledge a natural person as the owner of her data, provide sound provisions for facilitating the transition to the new regime, and give the RTI Act precedence over the Bill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: On the Importance of a Strong, Transparent, and Independent Data Protection Authority</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-on-the-importance-of-a-strong-and-independent-data-protection-authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 07:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-on-the-importance-of-a-strong-and-independent-data-protection-authority/</guid>
      <description>We analyse the provisions in the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019 which relate to the Data Protection Authority of India (DPA) and its independence, transparency, and constitution. We recommend that it not be bound by the Central Government&amp;rsquo;s orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cybersec Charcha: Understanding the booming ransomware industry</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/cybersec-charcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 07:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/cybersec-charcha/</guid>
      <description>In the second edition of Cybersec Charcha, we are taking a deep dive into understanding the unregulated ransomware industry, what a ransomware attack means and the consequences it can have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Despite CIC’s observation that MeitY&#39;s response to us was “grossly improper,&#34; MeitY issues the same response again #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/meity-response-was-grossly-improper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 06:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/meity-response-was-grossly-improper/</guid>
      <description>CIC directed the CPIO to re-visit our original RTI and provide a revised reply and info, if (comments on consultation on PDPB). However, the CPIO simply cited the same exemption under S.8 of the RTI Act that she had provided before the CIC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: 
State Security and Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-state-security-and-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 09:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-state-security-and-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>In Part 7 of the #DataProtectionTop 10 series, we discuss the provisions in the Bill which enable the State to engage in large scale surveillance. Blanket exemptions without a sound oversight and review mechanism raise concerns. Thus, we recommend that a chapter on surveillance reforms be inserted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: Data Localisation</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectionttop10-data-localisation-a-threat-to-free-and-open-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 06:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectionttop10-data-localisation-a-threat-to-free-and-open-internet/</guid>
      <description>In part 6 of the #DataProtectionTop10 series, we look at the restrictions imposed by the PDPB on the transfer of personal data outside India. We recommend that the Bill explicitly define critical personal data and not impose undue restrictions that affect the open nature of the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: Voluntary Social Media Verification</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-voluntary-social-media-verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 08:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-voluntary-social-media-verification/</guid>
      <description>In Part 5 of the #DataProtectionTop10 series, we analyse the various issues with the inclusion of social media intermediaries under the  Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019, and the provision for voluntary verification of user accounts.  We recommend that the relevant clauses be removed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: On the need to protect the rights of users</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-on-the-need-to-protect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 08:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-on-the-need-to-protect/</guid>
      <description>In part 4 of the #DataProtectionTop10 series, we explore the issues with the user rights under the Bill. Certain rights are not absolute and contain significant exemptions. The Bill also fails to include certain rights. To address these concerns, we recommend changes to strengthen user rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: Exceptions to Consent - A Torn Safety Net</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-exceptions-to-consent-a-torn-safety-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 08:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-exceptions-to-consent-a-torn-safety-net/</guid>
      <description>In part 3 of the #DataProtectionTop10 series, we look into various issues regarding the consent provisions for the processing of the personal data under the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: Impostors under the Personal Data Protection Bill</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-imposters-under-the-personal-data-protection-bill/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 07:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-imposters-under-the-personal-data-protection-bill/</guid>
      <description>In post 2 of the #DataProtectionTop10 series, we examine provisions on government access to non-personal data and setting up of privacy sandboxes, and discuss potential changes that could be made to include a more rights based perspective on non-personal data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DataProtectionTop10: Lost in Muddled Objectives</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-lost-in-muddled-objectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 07:59:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dataprotectiontop10-lost-in-muddled-objectives/</guid>
      <description>This is a new series on the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019 to deal exclusively with the issues and pathways for reform under the Bill. In this post we look at the objective and the Preamble of the Bill, and guage whether the bill serve ordinary Indians or the government and large corporations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#StartfromScratch: Constitutional Utopias of Digital Protection</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/constitutional-utopias-of-digital-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 04:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/constitutional-utopias-of-digital-protection/</guid>
      <description>In the final piece in our series on the Data Protection Bill, we first explain the 7 fundamental principles of the Indian Privacy Code. Then we analyse two alternative data protection bills: the Data (Privacy and Protection) Bill, 2017 and the Personal Data and Information Privacy Code Bill, 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching CyberSec Charcha: IFF&#39;s monthly digital security update!</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/launching-cybersec-charcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 08:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/launching-cybersec-charcha/</guid>
      <description>We are launching CyberSec Charcha, a free, monthly cyber security newsletter with a round up of the latest developments in digital security. Sign up today!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We urge CBSE to consider the pandemic as a time for care for students, not violations of their privacy.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/cbses-response-to-our-representation-fails-to-account-for-the-privacy-of-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 06:18:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/cbses-response-to-our-representation-fails-to-account-for-the-privacy-of-students/</guid>
      <description>Read our analysis of CBSE&amp;rsquo;s response to our representation on facial recognition use on students for access to digital documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buffering Justice : A call for greater participation in the Draft Vision Document for Judicial Digitisation</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digitization-of-indian-judiciary-phase-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 05:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digitization-of-indian-judiciary-phase-iii/</guid>
      <description>E-Committee has released the draft vision document of e-Courts Project Phase III. We encourage you to submit your comments on &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ecommittee@aij.gov.in&#34;&gt;ecommittee@aij.gov.in&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, we have provided our inputs on the document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#StartFromScratch: Why is the data protection bill being criticized?</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/why-is-the-data-bill-being-criticized/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 06:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/why-is-the-data-bill-being-criticized/</guid>
      <description>In the third edition of #StartFromScratch, we explain the key issues with the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#StartFromScratch: An Explainer on the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/startfromscratch-an-explainer-on-the-personal-data-protection-bill-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 07:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/startfromscratch-an-explainer-on-the-personal-data-protection-bill-2019/</guid>
      <description>Part 2 of our series on the data bill will explain the basics of the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019. In it, we provide an introduction to the main definitions, the Data Processing Authority is, user rights, and exemptions provided to the government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CIC observes that IT Ministry&#39;s denial on RTI for comments on the Data Protection Bill is, &#34;grossly improper&#34; #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/persist-transparency-dpd-cic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 05:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/persist-transparency-dpd-cic/</guid>
      <description>In a positive order in our second appeal related to the Data Protection Bill, the CIC directed the CPIO of MeitY to re-visit the RTI application and provide us with a revised reply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kwik to deny a data breach, MobiKwik must move faster to address it</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/mobikwik-data-breach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 07:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/mobikwik-data-breach/</guid>
      <description>We have written to the Computer Emergency Response Team (CERT-IN) asking them to initiate an inquiry over the data breach in terms of Section 70B(6) of the Information Technology Act, 2000. In this post, we point out the five steps MobiKwik must take to alleviate the situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for January, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-january-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 07:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-january-2021/</guid>
      <description>Read more about RTI work for the month of January, 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delhi HC issues notice to govt in petition challenging denial of RTI  regarding Aarogya Setu  #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/delhi-hc-hearing-aarogya-setu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 11:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/delhi-hc-hearing-aarogya-setu/</guid>
      <description>Today, the Delhi HC issued notice to the CPIOs of DeitY, MeitY, NeGD and NIC in a petition filed by RTI activist, Saurav Das, challenging denial of information relating to the creation of the Aarogya Setu app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explainer: WhatsApp Privacy Policy Changes #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/explainer-whatsapp-privacy-policy-changes-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 06:21:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/explainer-whatsapp-privacy-policy-changes-2021/</guid>
      <description>The new privacy policy confirms that Facebook may now have access to messages shared with businesses on WhatsApp and it provides more insight into expansive meta data collection by WhatsApp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We wrote to the UGC and the Ministry of Education on exam proctoring</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-to-the-ugc-and-the-ministry-of-education-on-exam-proctoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-to-the-ugc-and-the-ministry-of-education-on-exam-proctoring/</guid>
      <description>Following multiple reports of the use of exam proctoring technology by various universities across the country, we wrote to the University Grants Commission and the Ministry of Education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Kanoon defends the right to provide access to court records</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indian-kanoon-kerala-hc-right-to-be-forgotten/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indian-kanoon-kerala-hc-right-to-be-forgotten/</guid>
      <description>In response to a petition filed before the Kerala HC, Indian Kanoon has clarified that a right to be forgotten cannot be judicially created without a statutory basis and explained that court records are public documents whose reproduction cannot be prohibited by citing the right to privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The non-personal data policy process remains opaque and problematic #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-non-personal-data-policy-process-remains-opaque-and-problematic-saveourprivacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 04:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-non-personal-data-policy-process-remains-opaque-and-problematic-saveourprivacy/</guid>
      <description>Replies to Right to Information requests filed to the Committee of Experts working on the Non-Personal Data Governance framework highlight an underlying transparency problem which has been mirrored throughout 2020 by various other such data-related consultations by the Government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for December, 2020</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iffs-right-to-information-report-for-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 04:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iffs-right-to-information-report-for-december/</guid>
      <description>In this monthly series, we aim to provide information about how our RTI work is carried out and utilised to demand transparency and accountability from public authorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal govt documents provide insight into the creation and expansion of Aarogya Setu #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/aarogya-setu-minutes-of-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 06:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/aarogya-setu-minutes-of-meetings/</guid>
      <description>Minutes of meetings of the 9th Empowered Group on Technology and Data Management provide an insider view into the creation and expansion of Aarogya Setu and other government data collection projects during the COVID-19 pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Panoptic: Right to Information Updates from Delhi Police, Kolkata Police and Telangana State Technology Services</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/project-panoptic-right-to-information-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 05:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/project-panoptic-right-to-information-updates/</guid>
      <description>Replies to RTI requests filed with the Delhi Police, the Kolkata Police and the Telangana State Technology Services shed light on how these public authorities are using their FRT systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening the Joint Parliamentary Committee process on the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/strengthening-the-working-of-the-jpc-on-the-pdpb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 06:03:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/strengthening-the-working-of-the-jpc-on-the-pdpb/</guid>
      <description>The Joint Parliamentary Committee for Personal Data Protection Bill, 2019 is considering a revolutionary legislative proposal. To strengthen its process we request that the JPC work within its mandate and not consider extraneous issues, and that it consider more consultations with civil society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mandatory imposition of Aarogya Setu by Delhi Govt is illegal and ineffective #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/mandatory-imposition-of-aarogya-setu-by-delhi-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 05:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/mandatory-imposition-of-aarogya-setu-by-delhi-govt/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the Delhi Government and its Excise Department urging against mandatory imposition of the Aarogya Setu app. Our alarm bells were rung by a circular issued by the Excise Department which directed licensed wholesale liquor vendors to ensure mandatory use of Aarogya Setu by every worker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>While India copes with COVID-19, Aadhaar continues its function creep #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/aadhaar-good-governance-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 09:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/aadhaar-good-governance-rules/</guid>
      <description>After the Aadhaar Amendment Act 2019 and the Aadhaar Good Governance Rules 2020, there remain virtually no limitations on the use of Aadhaar authentication, which had earlier been restricted by the SC to only government entities and only for receipt of benefits and subsidies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move fast, break things? Not when sensitive health data is at stake! #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ndhm-data-privacy-policy-consultation-submission/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 06:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ndhm-data-privacy-policy-consultation-submission/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the National Health Authority seeking enactment of general and sectoral data protection laws and meaningful public consultation prior to deployment of any national digital health ID programme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch the Watchmen Series Part 2 : The Centralised Monitoring System</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/watch-the-watchmen-series-part-2-the-centralised-monitoring-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 03:59:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/watch-the-watchmen-series-part-2-the-centralised-monitoring-system/</guid>
      <description>In the second part of our Watch the Watchmen series, we take a look at the Centralised Monitoring System (CMS) which aims to automate the process of lawful interception &amp;amp; monitoring of telecommunications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Digital Health Mission Data Policy Consultation: Not now, not like this, not without all of us! #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ndhm-data-policy-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 04:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ndhm-data-policy-representation/</guid>
      <description>Post Delhi HC hearing, a follow up  representation was sent by the petitioner highlighting continuing violation of statutory obligations and urging the government to re-calculate deadline for submission of feedback after implementing recommended changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delhi HC directs govt to consider  representation regarding national Health Data Management Policy #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ndhm-data-policy-delhi-hc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 08:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/ndhm-data-policy-delhi-hc/</guid>
      <description>The petition heard by the Delhi HC raised concerns about the unreasonably short deadline for submission of feedback at the height of the COVID-19 pandemic, and highlighted how the existing process excludes persons with disabilities, non-English speakers and people without internet access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch the Watchmen Series Part 1 : The National Intelligence Grid</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/watch-the-watchmen-part-1-the-national-intelligence-grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 04:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/watch-the-watchmen-part-1-the-national-intelligence-grid/</guid>
      <description>We take a closer look at the proposed National Intelligence Grid which aims to tackle terror threats in the country and is scheduled go live on December 31, 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kerala HC to hear Aarogya Setu petitions in September 2020 #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kerala-hc-aarogya-setu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 07:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kerala-hc-aarogya-setu/</guid>
      <description>On 24 August, the Kerala HC heard a writ petition regarding third party data sharing and mandatory imposition of the Aarogya Setu app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over 130 individuals and organizations oppose mandatory use of Aarogya Setu in Delhi district courts #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/aarogya-setu-delhi-district-courts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 12:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/aarogya-setu-delhi-district-courts/</guid>
      <description>The representation highlights that making Aarogya Setu a pre-condition to access judicial establishments is likely to create barriers to justice, compromise the privacy of lawyers and their clients, and lacks any basis in law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survey about use of Aarogya Setu for air travel #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/aarogya-setu-air-travel-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 05:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/aarogya-setu-air-travel-survey/</guid>
      <description>Take this survey about use of Aarogya Setu for air travel so we can identify the scale of the problem and take appropriate remedial measures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banning 59 Apps sets a concerning precedent. A detailed statement and initial action. #WhatTheBlock</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/59-apps-blocked-our-statement-and-initial-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 11:11:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/59-apps-blocked-our-statement-and-initial-action/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we, through our statement, indicate areas of concerns around the legality of the process and also indicate how, by filing Right to Information requests, we are hoping for greater public disclosure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bulk data sharing policy scrapped is an incremental victory that requires follow up action #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/morth-bulk-data-sharing-policy-scrapped/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/morth-bulk-data-sharing-policy-scrapped/</guid>
      <description>The MoRTH has scrapped its Bulk Data Sharing Policy. While this is a great step, there are a few critical privacy loopholes that still remain to be addressed. We wrote to the ministry identifying as well providing recommendations to tackle these loopholes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Committee on IT is meeting next week! #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/its-time-to-stop-data-breaches-and-security-vulnerabilities-we-write-to-the-it-ministry-saveourprivacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 02:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/its-time-to-stop-data-breaches-and-security-vulnerabilities-we-write-to-the-it-ministry-saveourprivacy/</guid>
      <description>The Committee on IT is meeting on June 10, 2020 to discuss the issue of, &amp;ldquo;Citizens data security and privacy&amp;rdquo;. We are hopeful it puts questions on Aarogya Setu and Data Breaches to the Ministry of IT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s time to stop data breaches and security vulnerabilities. We write to the IT Ministry. #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/its-time-to-stop-data-breaches-and-security-vulnerabilities-we-write-to-the-it-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 23:35:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/its-time-to-stop-data-breaches-and-security-vulnerabilities-we-write-to-the-it-ministry/</guid>
      <description>Till we fix the regulatory and cyber security plumbing of our digital, public infrastructure the data leaks and cyber security vulnerabilities will continue</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We wrote to the Kerala Government and the Expert Committee formed on the Sprinklr Inc. Data Protection issue in Kerala highlighting the need for preserving the ideal of Constitutional Federalism #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-to-the-kerala-government-and-the-expert-committee-formed-on-the-sprinklr-inc-data-protection-issue-in-kerala-highlighting-the-need-for-preserving-the-ideal-of-constitutional-fe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 10:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-to-the-kerala-government-and-the-expert-committee-formed-on-the-sprinklr-inc-data-protection-issue-in-kerala-highlighting-the-need-for-preserving-the-ideal-of-constitutional-fe/</guid>
      <description>In our representation to the Government of Kerala and the Expert Committee formed on the issue, we have pointed out certain lacunae in the Kerala HC order addressing the issue and have made specific suggestions on how best to resolve them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kerala High Court hears challenges against mandatory imposition of Aarogya Setu</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kerala-hc-hears-challenges-against-mandatory-imposition-of-aarogya-setu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 12:49:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kerala-hc-hears-challenges-against-mandatory-imposition-of-aarogya-setu/</guid>
      <description>The Kerala High Court has directed MeitY to file a response to petitions challenging mandatory imposition of Aarogya Setu and to state on record that data collected by the app will not be misused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workers of a digital world unite to advance privacy, dignity and autonomy! #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/workers-privacy-during-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 07:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/workers-privacy-during-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>This May Day, IFF and a diverse group of individuals and organizations write to the government to ensure that privacy, dignity and autonomy of workers is not compromised during the COVID-19 crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal Notice to BECIL for it&#39;s tender to procure employee tracking smartwatches and a Covid-19 mass surveillance system #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/legal-notice-to-becil-for-its-tender-to-procure-employee-tracking-smartwatches-and-a-mass-surveillance-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 09:04:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/legal-notice-to-becil-for-its-tender-to-procure-employee-tracking-smartwatches-and-a-mass-surveillance-system/</guid>
      <description>IFF has sent a legal notice to a government entity BECIL that intends to procure two items (amongst a larger procurement of various other medical safety devices), i.e.  “Personnel Tracking GPS Solution” and the “Covid–19 Patient Tracking Tool”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We wrote to NCRB and MHA requesting them to halt their ongoing National Automated Facial Recognition System (AFRS) project #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-to-ncrb-and-mha-requesting-them-to-halt-their-ongoing-national-automated-facial-recognition-system-afrs-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 05:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-to-ncrb-and-mha-requesting-them-to-halt-their-ongoing-national-automated-facial-recognition-system-afrs-project/</guid>
      <description>We have shared a representation with the NCRB and the Hon’ble Minister of Home Affairs Mr Amit Shah highlighting the legal and constitutional issues with their National Automated Facial Recognition System (AFRS) project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Protection and the National Population Register #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/data-protection-and-the-national-population-register/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 11:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/data-protection-and-the-national-population-register/</guid>
      <description>IFF&amp;rsquo;s brief highlights how NPR violates data protection principles of lawfulness, consent, purpose limitation, data minimization and accountability. Based on this case study, the brief identifies various loopholes in the PDP Bill and recommends necessary changes to the Joint Parliamentary Committee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workplace Surveillance: Your employer could be watching you</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/workplace-surveillance-your-employer-could-be-watching-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 06:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/workplace-surveillance-your-employer-could-be-watching-you/</guid>
      <description>Read IFF&amp;rsquo;s public brief highlighting the impact of the Personal Data Protection Bill 2019 on workplace surveillance and participate in the consultation being held by the Joint Parliamentary Committee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Educate and advocate for better privacy protection before the Data Protection JPC</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/educate-and-advocate-for-better-data-protection-saveourprivacy-ins-analysis-of-the-pdp-bill-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 06:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/educate-and-advocate-for-better-data-protection-saveourprivacy-ins-analysis-of-the-pdp-bill-2019/</guid>
      <description>Read SaveOurPrivacy.in&amp;rsquo;s analysis of the PDP Bill, 2019. This helps you form your views and participate in the invitation to public comments invited by the Joint Parliamentary Committee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s the final countdown (kinda) on the Data Protection Bill #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/its-the-final-countdown-kinda-saveourprivacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 11:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/its-the-final-countdown-kinda-saveourprivacy/</guid>
      <description>Joint parliamentary committee invites evidence on the Data Protection Bill, 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security researchers need legislative protection for responsible disclosure</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/security-researchers-need-legislative-protection-from-vexatious-lawsuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 04:52:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/security-researchers-need-legislative-protection-from-vexatious-lawsuits/</guid>
      <description>Security researchers, vulnerability testers and journalists need to be protected,  especially when reporting on data breaches in India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We need a transparent and accessible Joint Parliamentary Committee on Data Protection!</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/transparent-and-accessible-joint-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 06:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/transparent-and-accessible-joint-committee/</guid>
      <description>To ensure people are brought to the forefront in determining their own data protection regime, we write to the Joint Parliamentary Committee with a few suggestions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here comes the Bill, all dressed in Nil #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/here-comes-the-bill-all-dressed-in-nil/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 08:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/here-comes-the-bill-all-dressed-in-nil/</guid>
      <description>As the Data Protection Bill has made its appearance, we list out existing and new additions to our concerns with the Bill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How far have we come as India prepares for its much awaited data protection law.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 05:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dp/</guid>
      <description>As the Personal Data Protection Bill, 2018 makes it way to Parliament, we showcase some of IFF&amp;rsquo;s work in ensuring India has a well-established data protection framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need silver linings? NPCI responds to our representation. It is investigating the Truecaller &#34;Breach&#34;</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/need-some-pick-me-up-news-ncpi-is-investigating-the-truecaller/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 04:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/need-some-pick-me-up-news-ncpi-is-investigating-the-truecaller/</guid>
      <description>NPCI writes back indicated two specific steps to counter the Truecaller breach. First it had stopped on boarding new Truecaller users on the UPI Platform. Second the matter is under investigation and we will be informed after diligence is completed in all matters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>True (caller) or False (caller)? We ask NPCI to answer this question.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/true-caller-or-false-caller-we-ask-ncpi-to-answer-this-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 07:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/true-caller-or-false-caller-we-ask-ncpi-to-answer-this-question/</guid>
      <description>Truecaller users faced automatic registration of their UPI based IDs without their knowledge and consent.  We write to the NPCI suggesting a few measures to consider in addressing these issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Data and Information Privacy Code Bill, 2019 introduced in the Lok Sabha today! #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/personal-data-and-information-privacy-code-bill-2019-introduced-in-the-lok-sabha-today-saveourprivacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 12:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/personal-data-and-information-privacy-code-bill-2019-introduced-in-the-lok-sabha-today-saveourprivacy/</guid>
      <description>IFF goes to Parliament with Dr. Ravikumar (Lok Sabha, MP from Tamil Nadu). Today, the Personal Data and Information Privacy Code Bill, 2019 was introduced!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“No more data collection without privacy protection” #DNABill #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/no-more-data-collection-without-privacy-protection-dnabill-saveourprivacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 10:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/no-more-data-collection-without-privacy-protection-dnabill-saveourprivacy/</guid>
      <description>In the present winter session of parliment a key proposal impacting our privacy may pass into law. The, DNA Technology (Use and Application) Regulation Bill, 2018 is up for consideration &amp;amp; passage and we need to oppose it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter (session) is here! #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/winter-session-is-here-saveourprivacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 11:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/winter-session-is-here-saveourprivacy/</guid>
      <description>The winter session of parliament will start on December 11, 2018 in which important legislative business on privacy will be conducted across three key legislations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The drafting process for the Data Protection Bill should not be shrouded in secrecy #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-drafting-process-for-the-data-protection-bill-should-not-be-shrouded-in-secrecy-saveourprivacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 12:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/the-drafting-process-for-the-data-protection-bill-should-not-be-shrouded-in-secrecy-saveourprivacy/</guid>
      <description>The Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology has denied SaveOurPrivacy.in&amp;rsquo;s request for transparency in the drafting of India&amp;rsquo;s privacy law. We have filed first appeals under the RTI Act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#SaveOurPrivacy initial statement on Justice Srikrishna Committee Report</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/saveourprivacy-initial-statement-on-justice-srikrishna-committee-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/saveourprivacy-initial-statement-on-justice-srikrishna-committee-report/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on SaveOurPrivacy.in
The Expert Committee chaired by Retd. Justice B.N. Srikrishna submitted its 176 page report to the Minister of Electronics and Information Technology at 1600 Hrs on 27 July 2018 (today). The Committee also submitted a draft of the legislation on data protection titled, ‘The Personal Data Protection Bill, 2018’. After weeks of secrecy, denial of information in RTIs about the proceedings of the Committee, the report as well as the draft legislation have now been placed in public domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We call on the TRAI to protect user privacy in the Indian telecom sector!</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-call-on-the-trai-to-protect-user-privacy-in-the-indian-telecom-sector/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-call-on-the-trai-to-protect-user-privacy-in-the-indian-telecom-sector/</guid>
      <description>Fresh off the historic nine judge decision of the Supreme Court holding privacy as a fundamental right, IFF has called on the TRAI to protect user privacy and data protection in its ongoing public consultation “Privacy, Security and Ownership of the Data in the Telecom Sector”. We previously posted a short summary of this consultation paper back in September.
You can read our full November 6 comments to the TRAI here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
