<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>OTT on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://internerfreedom.in/tags/ott/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OTT on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://internerfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 09:09:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://internerfreedom.in/tags/ott/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Union of India seeks a transfer of cases challenging IT Rules, 2021</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/union-of-india-seeks-a-transfer-of-cases-challenging-it-rules-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 09:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/union-of-india-seeks-a-transfer-of-cases-challenging-it-rules-2021/</guid>
      <description>A two-judge bench of the Supreme Court has listed the Union of India&amp;rsquo;s transfer petition before another bench on 16th July 2021. The petition seeks a transfer to the Supreme Court of 4 cases challenging IT Rules, 2021 which are pending before different High Courts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madras High Court issues notice in petition challenging the Intermediary Rules 2021 by T. M. Krishna</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/madras-high-court-issues-notice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 05:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/madras-high-court-issues-notice/</guid>
      <description>Madras High issued notice on a writ petition by T.M. Krishna challenging the Intermediary Rules 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tandav is a Case Study for OTT censorship under the IT Rules, 2021 #LetUsChill</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/tandav-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 07:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/tandav-case-study/</guid>
      <description>Documents accessed through RTI paint a grim picture for creativity and diversity of content for online streaming platforms in India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming to streaming services near you: Self-censorship!</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/self-censorship-and-the-end-of-good-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 05:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/self-censorship-and-the-end-of-good-content/</guid>
      <description>In light of the recently notified Intermediary Rules, we have made an explainer on the IAMAI&amp;rsquo;s toolkit for the self-regulation code for OCC providers. Here, we describe the grievance redressal structure, analyse some of the concerns at hand, and explain how the toolkit will enmesh with the Rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#LetUsChill: Confusion and Opacity over OTT guidelines</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/ott-transparency-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 13:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/ott-transparency-representation/</guid>
      <description>The Ministry of Information &amp;amp; Broadcasting may be considering regulating online content on Over-The-Top (OTT) platforms. We wrote a letter to the Ministry, in which we detailed potential harms, asked for clarity, and requested a thorough implementation of the pre-legislative consultation policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF intervenes in Madras HC PIL seeking censorship on online streaming platforms #LetUsChill</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/iff-intervenes-madras-hc-pil-ott-regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 07:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/iff-intervenes-madras-hc-pil-ott-regulation/</guid>
      <description>In the impleadment application, we have cautioned against judicial intervention at this stage because OTT regulation is a complex and technical issue best addressed through legislative and policy making processes involving extensive stakeholder consultation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you TRAI for recommending against internet licensing! #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/thank-you-trai-for-recommending-against-internet-licensing-savetheinternet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 14:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/thank-you-trai-for-recommending-against-internet-licensing-savetheinternet/</guid>
      <description>In a victory for internet users the telecom regulator pushed back against some awful proposals by telecom companies to force online service providers for licensing, revenue sharing or breaking their encryption. We have written to the DOT to accept them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online video streaming and TV are not the same. So why is the IAMAI trying to make it so?</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/online-video-streaming-and-tv-are-not-the-same-so-why-is-the-iamai-trying-to-make-it-so/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 11:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/online-video-streaming-and-tv-are-not-the-same-so-why-is-the-iamai-trying-to-make-it-so/</guid>
      <description>The Internet and Mobile Association of India (IAMAI) launched a self-regulation code for online video streaming platforms. We have written to IAMAI asking them to roll it back since it is a precursor to self-censorship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protect users, do not license the Internet #OTTConsultation #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/protect-users-do-not-license-the-internet-ottconsultation-savetheinternet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 05:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/protect-users-do-not-license-the-internet-ottconsultation-savetheinternet/</guid>
      <description>The TRAI in November, 2018 released a consultation paper on regulation of OTT services. Yesterday, IFF made it’s submission on it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
