<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>aadhaar on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/aadhaar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aadhaar on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 04:51:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/aadhaar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IFF submits its comments on the Draft Aadhaar (Pricing of Aadhaar Authentication Services) Regulations</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-submits-its-comments-on-the-draft-aadhaar-pricing-of-aadhaar-authentication-services-regulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 04:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-submits-its-comments-on-the-draft-aadhaar-pricing-of-aadhaar-authentication-services-regulations/</guid>
      <description>We have provided our comments on the Draft Aadhaar (Pricing of Aadhaar Authentication Services) Regulations 2021. In our comments, we recommended that Aadhaar authentication charges be scrapped and private entities be barred from acting as ‘requesting entities’ for authentication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government endorses the use of facial recognition for “touchless” vaccination process</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/government-endorses-the-use-of-facial-recognition-for-touchless-vaccination-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 04:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/government-endorses-the-use-of-facial-recognition-for-touchless-vaccination-process/</guid>
      <description>We filed an RTI application with the Ministry of Health and Family Welfare to verify reports about the government using facial recognition technology (FRT) for the verification of beneficiaries of the COVID-19 vaccines. In their response the Ministry confirmed the use of FRT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad Rules for Good Governance</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/bad-rules-for-good-governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 07:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/bad-rules-for-good-governance/</guid>
      <description>We explain why the Aadhaar Good Governances Rules are unconstitutional as they exceed the limits of the Aadhaar Act, violate the Puttaswamy judgement and proportionality test, and are vague and non-voluntary. We have petitioned the Committees on Subordinate Legislation to review the Rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comments on the Draft Social Security Rules to safeguard worker&#39;s rights #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/worker-surveillance-through-labour-reforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 09:12:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/worker-surveillance-through-labour-reforms/</guid>
      <description>The Ministry of Labour released the Draft Code on Social Security (Central) Rules, 2020. In our comments on the draft, we have highlighted the following issues: mandatory aadhaar based verification and inadequate security safeguards for employee databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>While India copes with COVID-19, Aadhaar continues its function creep #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/aadhaar-good-governance-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 09:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/aadhaar-good-governance-rules/</guid>
      <description>After the Aadhaar Amendment Act 2019 and the Aadhaar Good Governance Rules 2020, there remain virtually no limitations on the use of Aadhaar authentication, which had earlier been restricted by the SC to only government entities and only for receipt of benefits and subsidies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint Statement : The Government of Kerala must withdraw compulsory Aadhaar for state government jobs</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/joint-statement-kerala-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/joint-statement-kerala-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>Kalyani Menon Sen, a petitioner in the Aadhaar case has sent a legal notice to the Government of Kerala which has made Aadhaar mandatory for state government jobs. We are issuing a joint statement supporting this action.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
