<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>aarogyasetu on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/categories/aarogyasetu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aarogyasetu on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 07:25:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/categories/aarogyasetu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Delhi High Court issues directions on suggestions to improve the CoWIN platform #VaccinesForAll</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/delhi-high-court-issues-directions-on-suggestions-to-improve-the-cowin-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 07:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/delhi-high-court-issues-directions-on-suggestions-to-improve-the-cowin-platform/</guid>
      <description>Delhi High Court issued a series of directions offered by the Amicus, Senior Advocate Rajshekhar Rao on a note prepared by IFF. Hopefully it will soon lead to massive improvements including alternate modes or registration, co-win becoming more accessible, multilingual and having a privacy policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sustained, strategic litigation helps advance transparency in digital policymaking #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/how-we-are-helping-rti-activists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 04:27:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/how-we-are-helping-rti-activists/</guid>
      <description>Updates from the High Court of Delhi on the writ petition of Saurav Das who is challenging the Central Information Commission&amp;rsquo;s order denying him information on Aarogya Setu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hindsight is 20/20: Assessing outcomes from Aarogya Setu</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/the-past-and-future-of-aarogya-setu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 07:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/the-past-and-future-of-aarogya-setu/</guid>
      <description>We are close to a year since the launch of Arogya Setu. This is why we have written to the National Informatics Centre, pointing out that issues with Aarogya Setu have still not been addressed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delhi HC issues notice to govt in petition challenging denial of RTI  regarding Aarogya Setu  #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/delhi-hc-hearing-aarogya-setu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 11:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/delhi-hc-hearing-aarogya-setu/</guid>
      <description>Today, the Delhi HC issued notice to the CPIOs of DeitY, MeitY, NeGD and NIC in a petition filed by RTI activist, Saurav Das, challenging denial of information relating to the creation of the Aarogya Setu app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal govt documents provide insight into the creation and expansion of Aarogya Setu #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/aarogya-setu-minutes-of-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 06:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/aarogya-setu-minutes-of-meetings/</guid>
      <description>Minutes of meetings of the 9th Empowered Group on Technology and Data Management provide an insider view into the creation and expansion of Aarogya Setu and other government data collection projects during the COVID-19 pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Govt officials to justify denial of information about Aarogya Setu in secret hearing before CIC #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/cic-legal-notice-aarogya-setu-show-cause-hearing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 05:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/cic-legal-notice-aarogya-setu-show-cause-hearing/</guid>
      <description>We sent a legal notice to the Central Information Commission challenging its refusal to let RTI activist, Saurav Das attend the show cause hearing in his complaint which seeks information about creation of the Aarogya Setu app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mandatory imposition of Aarogya Setu by Delhi Govt is illegal and ineffective #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/mandatory-imposition-of-aarogya-setu-by-delhi-govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 05:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/mandatory-imposition-of-aarogya-setu-by-delhi-govt/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the Delhi Government and its Excise Department urging against mandatory imposition of the Aarogya Setu app. Our alarm bells were rung by a circular issued by the Excise Department which directed licensed wholesale liquor vendors to ensure mandatory use of Aarogya Setu by every worker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-domain orgs and individuals raise concerns about Aarogya Setu #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/aarogya-setu-multi-domain-joint-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 04:28:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/aarogya-setu-multi-domain-joint-statement/</guid>
      <description>8 organizations and 145 individuals have written to MoHFW, MeitY and the IT Standing Committee raising serious concerns regarding Aarogya Setu and other COVID-19 apps and presented a clear set of 16 demands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kerala HC to hear Aarogya Setu petitions in September 2020 #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/kerala-hc-aarogya-setu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 07:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/kerala-hc-aarogya-setu/</guid>
      <description>On 24 August, the Kerala HC heard a writ petition regarding third party data sharing and mandatory imposition of the Aarogya Setu app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four months on, Aarogya Setu is still not open-source. WHY and WHEN is what the nation really wants to know! #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/aarogya-setu-should-be-open-source-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 05:52:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/aarogya-setu-should-be-open-source-now/</guid>
      <description>Four months, after its initial release, the Aarogya Setu app is not open-source in the true sense of the term. Source code releases have been slow and incomplete. This is preventing the Indian tech community from collaborating and contributing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over 130 individuals and organizations oppose mandatory use of Aarogya Setu in Delhi district courts #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/aarogya-setu-delhi-district-courts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 12:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/aarogya-setu-delhi-district-courts/</guid>
      <description>The representation highlights that making Aarogya Setu a pre-condition to access judicial establishments is likely to create barriers to justice, compromise the privacy of lawyers and their clients, and lacks any basis in law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survey about use of Aarogya Setu for air travel #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/aarogya-setu-air-travel-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 05:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/aarogya-setu-air-travel-survey/</guid>
      <description>Take this survey about use of Aarogya Setu for air travel so we can identify the scale of the problem and take appropriate remedial measures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RWA uncles, please calm down about Aarogya Setu #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/aarogya-setu-rwas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 12:06:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/aarogya-setu-rwas/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the government seeking issuance of an advisory which clarifies that Resident Welfare Associations cannot make use of Aarogya Setu mandatory for entry into housing societies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A look at Aarogya Setu through the Right to Information lens #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/aarogya-setu-through-the-right-to-information-lens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 06:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/aarogya-setu-through-the-right-to-information-lens/</guid>
      <description>IFF has filed multiple Right to Information requests with various governmental authorities on the Aarogya Setu application. In this post, we will highlight these requests, the substantial replies that we received as well as the non-answers which also tell us a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement: Victory! Aarogya Setu changes from mandatory to, “best efforts”.</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/aarogya-setu-victory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 06:08:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/aarogya-setu-victory/</guid>
      <description>As lockdown 4.0 was extended, we recorded a small but significant win as the installation of Aarogya Setu has now been changed to a best effort basis. On May 2 we had sent a letter to the Ministry of Home Affairs calling the Ministry to roll back an order requiring the mandatory use of Aarogya Setu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Studied the Protocol: And No This Doesn’t Sufficiently Protect Your Privacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/we-studied-the-protocol-and-no-this-doesnt-sufficiently-protect-your-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 08:08:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/we-studied-the-protocol-and-no-this-doesnt-sufficiently-protect-your-privacy/</guid>
      <description>According to our analysis on the Aarogya Setu Data Access and Knowledge Sharing Protocol released by MeitY on May 11, 2020, the protocol falls considerably short of principles of legality, necessity and proportionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kerala High Court hears challenges against mandatory imposition of Aarogya Setu</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/kerala-hc-hears-challenges-against-mandatory-imposition-of-aarogya-setu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 12:49:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/kerala-hc-hears-challenges-against-mandatory-imposition-of-aarogya-setu/</guid>
      <description>The Kerala High Court has directed MeitY to file a response to petitions challenging mandatory imposition of Aarogya Setu and to state on record that data collected by the app will not be misused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Committee on IT : Get up! Stand up, for our privacy rights! #AarogyaSetu #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/get-up-stand-up-for-our-privacy-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 09:52:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/get-up-stand-up-for-our-privacy-rights/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the Standing Committee for Information Technology to hold hearings on Aarogya Setu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We legally contest the Noida authorities order of criminally prosecuting people who do not have Aarogya Setu #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/we-contest-the-noida-authorities-direction-that-may-make-aarogya-setu-a-path-to-jail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 13:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/we-contest-the-noida-authorities-direction-that-may-make-aarogya-setu-a-path-to-jail/</guid>
      <description>Earlier today we facilitated a legal challenge to the Noida Authorities to revoke the mandatory imposition of Aarogya Setu under a threat of criminal imprisonment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>45 organizations and more than 100 prominent individuals push back against the coercion of Aarogya Setu</title>
      <link>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/45-organizations-and-105-prominent-individuals-push-back-against-the-coercion-of-aarogya-setu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 06:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internetfreedomfoundation.github.io/archive/post/45-organizations-and-105-prominent-individuals-push-back-against-the-coercion-of-aarogya-setu/</guid>
      <description>We have sent a joint representation to the Prime Minister&amp;rsquo;s Office that is endorsed by 45 organisations and more than 100 individuals against the mandatory use of the Aarogya Setu App dated May 1, 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
