<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Statement on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/categories/statement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statement on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 05:17:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/categories/statement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Statement: One year of inaction, delay and evasion on the NSO-Pegasus hack #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/nso-pegasus-hack-one-year-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 05:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/nso-pegasus-hack-one-year-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>Despite multiple government and parliamentary bodies examining the Pegasus hack, a whole year has passed and we still do not know who was responsible for this egregious violation of the privacy of human rights defenders in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SC&#39;s Kashmir communication shutdown judgement is just the beginning of a long uphill campaign</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/scs-judgement-on-kashmir-communication-is-just-the-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 14:17:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/scs-judgement-on-kashmir-communication-is-just-the-beginning/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court&amp;rsquo;s judgement in Anuradha Bhasin v. Union of India is a step in the right direction but fails to provide immediate relief to Kashmiris who have already suffered immense hardship due to the 158 day communication shutdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement against Internet Shutdowns in the North East</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-on-internet-shutdowns-in-the-north-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 06:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-on-internet-shutdowns-in-the-north-east/</guid>
      <description>Internet shutdowns are a pan-India problem and there is no conclusive evidence that they prevent violence. We urge the Central Government to consider issuing an advisory on the frequent use of internet disruptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement: Scary disclosures on use of NSO spyware in India signal a need for urgent reform</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-scary-disclosures-on-use-of-nso-spyware-in-india-signal-a-need-for-urgent-remedy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 11:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-scary-disclosures-on-use-of-nso-spyware-in-india-signal-a-need-for-urgent-remedy/</guid>
      <description>News reports have revealed the targeting of lawyers, journalists and activists in India through NSO&amp;rsquo;s illegal spyware, Pegasus.
While these revelations have left many of us shaken, we must demand transparency from the govt and push for surveillance reform in parliament and courts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#PrivacySupreme: Two years of the Right to Privacy.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/privacysupreme-two-years-of-the-right-to-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 06:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/privacysupreme-two-years-of-the-right-to-privacy/</guid>
      <description>24 August 2019 marks the second anniversary of the Indian Supreme Court’s landmark judgement in KS Puttaswamy v. Union of India. We celebrate and critically appraise this moment as we discuss our next steps in protecting the Right to Privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We strongly condemn the communications blackout in Jammu and Kashmir and urge an end to internet shutdowns across India</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kashmir_shutdowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 02:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/kashmir_shutdowns/</guid>
      <description>The developments of the past few days are of immense consequence to the future of our democracy, and the voices from Jammu and Kashmir need to be heard the loudest, not silenced en masse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democracy, first and foremost.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dr-ambedkar-taught-us-how-to-hold-power-to-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 08:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/dr-ambedkar-taught-us-how-to-hold-power-to-account/</guid>
      <description>As India looks to the next 5 years of Government, it is important to ensure the protection of individual liberties stands at the forefront.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We express support to Safeguarding Democracy from Digital Platforms</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/support-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 10:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/support-2/</guid>
      <description>IFF is in support of a statement released in collaboration with individuals and organisations demonstrating the need to uphold and defend the integrity of the next general elections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement of concern on the Sabu Mathew George Case : Don’t “auto-block” online expression</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-of-concern-on-the-sabu-mathew-george-case-dont-auto-block-online-expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 12:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/statement-of-concern-on-the-sabu-mathew-george-case-dont-auto-block-online-expression/</guid>
      <description>The Supreme Court of India has over the past one year passed various orders in the case of Sabu Mathew George v. Union of India &amp;amp; Ors. [WP(C) 341/2008] that are undermining internet freedom, particularly the right of free expression online. The case concerns allegations that search engines are acting in contravention of S. 22 of the Pre-Conception and Pre-Natal Diagnostic Techniques (Prohibition of Sex Selection) Act (hereinafter referred to as “the Act”) insofar as they are showing results relating to sex determination kits and techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
