<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>joint statement on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/joint-statement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in joint statement on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 07:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/tags/joint-statement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Joint Statement: Ensure equitable access to COVID-19 vaccines and health care resources</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/joint-statement-ensure-equitable-access-to-covid-vaccines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 07:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/joint-statement-ensure-equitable-access-to-covid-vaccines/</guid>
      <description>India is in a crisis. As people across the country battle the second wave of COVID-19, ensuring equitable, fast and easy access to healthcare, medicines and the vaccines is critical. The undersigned organizations and persons call on the Central Government, State Governments, Health Secretaries of the Union and the States, and the District Magistrates to ensure that the vaccination process focuses on increasing reach and accessibility, that there are no onerous ID requirements, including Aadhaar, for access to health services or vaccinations, and that health data is not misused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint Statement: Say no to Aadhaar based Facial Recognition for Vaccination!</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/sign-on-and-support-close-to-10-organisations-and-158-individuals-who-are-warning-against-aadhaar-based-facial-recognition-for-vaccination/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 05:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/sign-on-and-support-close-to-10-organisations-and-158-individuals-who-are-warning-against-aadhaar-based-facial-recognition-for-vaccination/</guid>
      <description>In the Joint Statement, we highlight our concerns on the use of this inaccurate technology for access to vaccines, how it may lead to potentially life threatening exclusion and ask for public support &amp;amp; sign ons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint statement against internet shutdowns to suppress farmers&#39; protests #KeepItOn</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/joint-statement-internet-shutdown-farmers-protests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 07:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/joint-statement-internet-shutdown-farmers-protests/</guid>
      <description>IFF along with FSMI and SFLC.in raises alarm about the use of internet shutdowns to undermine the fundamental right to peaceful protest. Such internet shutdowns will only increase the risk of violence and misinformation and they cannot be considered necessary or proportionate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-domain orgs and individuals raise concerns about Aarogya Setu #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/aarogya-setu-multi-domain-joint-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 04:28:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/aarogya-setu-multi-domain-joint-statement/</guid>
      <description>8 organizations and 145 individuals have written to MoHFW, MeitY and the IT Standing Committee raising serious concerns regarding Aarogya Setu and other COVID-19 apps and presented a clear set of 16 demands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint Statement : The Government of Kerala must withdraw compulsory Aadhaar for state government jobs</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/joint-statement-kerala-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/joint-statement-kerala-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>Kalyani Menon Sen, a petitioner in the Aadhaar case has sent a legal notice to the Government of Kerala which has made Aadhaar mandatory for state government jobs. We are issuing a joint statement supporting this action.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
