<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>campaign on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://internerfreedom.in/tags/campaign/</link>
    <description>Recent content in campaign on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://internerfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 09:20:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://internerfreedom.in/tags/campaign/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SaveTheInternet.in is live.</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/savetheinternet-in-is-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 09:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/savetheinternet-in-is-live/</guid>
      <description>SaveTheInternet.in is live.
With the rampant website blockings being conducted by ISP’s, IFF has taken the step to  activate the SaveTheInternet.in website. It includes a reporting tool and petition to take this movement forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Us Online Petition</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/shutdowns-petition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 11:44:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/shutdowns-petition/</guid>
      <description>Keep Us Online &amp;gt; Petition
 This is the full text of our petition. Add your signature to it.
 To: Shri Narendra Modi The Hon’ble Prime Minister&amp;rsquo;s Office South Block, Raisina Hill New Delhi - 110011
Dear Prime Minister,
We are signing this petition asking you to — keep us online!
India had more Internet shutdowns in 2016 than any other country. Recent research estimated this caused us a loss of more than Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Empowerment Foundation</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/org-def/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 10:26:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/org-def/</guid>
      <description>Keep Us Online &amp;gt; Digial Empowerment Foundation
 Digital Empowerment Foundation (DEF) is a New Delhi based social sector organisation that has worked extensively to empower marginalised communities to come online. Its work has enabled more than one million people from weaker sections of society to gain access to the internet. It has supported 5000 entities such as schools, libraries, heritage sites, micro-enterprises to leverage the power the digital world has to offer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centre for Internet and Society</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/org-cis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 10:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/org-cis/</guid>
      <description>Keep Us Online &amp;gt; Centre for Internet and Society
 The Centre for Internet and Society (CIS) India is a non-profit organisation that undertakes interdisciplinary research on internet and digital technologies from policy and academic perspectives. The areas of focus include digital accessibility for persons with disabilities, access to knowledge, intellectual property rights, openness, internet governance, telecommunication reform, digital privacy, and cyber-security. Through its diverse initiatives, CIS explores, intervenes in, and advances contemporary discourse and practices around internet, technology and society in India and elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centre for Communication Governance</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/org-ccg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 10:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/org-ccg/</guid>
      <description>Keep Us Online &amp;gt; Centre for Communication Governance
 The Centre for Communication Governance (CCG) was established in 2013 to ensure that Indian legal education establishments engage more meaningfully with information law and policy, and contribute to improved governance and policy making. CCG is the only academic research centre dedicated to working on the information law and policy in India. It seeks to embed human rights and good governance within communication policy and protect digital rights in India through rigorous academic research and capacity building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ on Internet Shutdowns</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/shutdowns-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 10:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/shutdowns-faq/</guid>
      <description>Keep Us Online &amp;gt; FAQ
 What are Internet Shutdowns? Internet shutdowns are an absolute restriction placed on the use of internet services due to an order issued by a government body. It may be limited to a specific place and to specific period, time or number of days. Sometimes it can even extend indefinitely. An internet shutdown may be limited to mobile internet that you use on smartphones, or the wired broadband that usually connects a desktop - or both at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Us Online</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/keepusonline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 04:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/keepusonline/</guid>
      <description>View the petition and the frequently asked questions.
India had more Internet shutdowns in 2016 than any other country. State governments were able to shut down the Internet in different parts of the country, affecting millions of people. What’s worse is that these shutdowns happened on some official’s whim with no accountability or oversight. Internet shutdowns are not only a violation of human rights, they also cost India more than Rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Test</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/email-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 15:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/email-test/</guid>
      <description>Yes! TRAI has finally proposed net neutrality regulation!
But there&amp;rsquo;s a catch.
Big telcos are lobbying hard to kill any meaningful net neutrality, and to punch loopholes in last year&amp;rsquo;s pro-user regulations. They are very well organized and have deep pockets.
Unless TRAI hears our voices loud and clear, and knows that lakhs of Indians are watching and paying attention, telcos will get their way.
Help save the Internet one more time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petition Test</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/petition-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 18:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/petition-test/</guid>
      <description>India had more Internet shutdowns in 2016 than any other country. State governments love to shut off the Internet, supposedly to thwart everyone from protesters to exam cheats. Millions of people are routinely cut off on someone&amp;rsquo;s whim, with zero rules or oversight. This is unacceptable.
Even for stopping riots — the official justification for most shutdowns — there is evidence that blackouts do more harm than good. Cutting off Internet access prevents innocent people from using the Internet to learn about trouble spots to stay away from, from reaching out for help and from making sure that loved ones are safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Campaign Test Page</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/campaign-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 17:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/campaign-test/</guid>
      <description>Yes! TRAI has finally proposed net neutrality regulation!
But there&amp;rsquo;s a catch.
Big telcos are lobbying hard to kill any meaningful net neutrality, and to punch loopholes in last year&amp;rsquo;s pro-user regulations. They are very well organized and have deep pockets.
Unless TRAI hears our voices loud and clear, and knows that lakhs of Indians are watching and paying attention, telcos will get their way.
Help save the Internet one more time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
