<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>freespeech on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/categories/freespeech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in freespeech on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 05:49:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://archive.internetfreedom.in/categories/freespeech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Oxford Pro Bono Publico releases its report on the Regulation of Digital Media and Intermediaries</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/oxford-pro-bono-publico-releases-its-report-on-the-regulation-of-digital-media-and-intermediaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 05:49:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/oxford-pro-bono-publico-releases-its-report-on-the-regulation-of-digital-media-and-intermediaries/</guid>
      <description>To assist challenges to IT Rules, w​e reached out to Oxford Pro Bono Publico (OPBP) - a research centre at the Oxford University, requesting research on laws in other countries on social media platforms, digital news media and OTT platforms. OPBP has published their research report in December 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revealed: Over two thousand news publishers furnished their details to the MIB, despite Bombay HC’s stay</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/revealed-two-thousand-news-publishers-furnished-details-to-mib/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 06:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/revealed-two-thousand-news-publishers-furnished-details-to-mib/</guid>
      <description>IFF filed an RTI Application to find out whether the MIB has issued notices for information to news publishers, and to which publishers. The MIB has admitted that it has indeed issued two such notices, and that more than two thousand publishers have responded to these notices!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amina writes to the National Commission for Women and the Telangana State Women’s Commission against targeted harassment of Muslim Women</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-assists-amina-targeted-by-bulli-bai-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 08:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-assists-amina-targeted-by-bulli-bai-app/</guid>
      <description>After much furore around the Bulli Bai incident, some arrests have been made and the investigation is still pending. One of the victims of this incident wrote to the National Commission of Women and the Telangana State Women Commission seeking their intervention in ensuring fair investigation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>118 days since… still no justice for those targeted by the “Sulli Deals” incident.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/118-days-since-still-no-justice-for-those-targeted-by-the-sulli-deals-incident/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 05:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/118-days-since-still-no-justice-for-those-targeted-by-the-sulli-deals-incident/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the Delhi Police asking them to expeditiously investigate the &amp;lsquo;Sulli Deals&amp;rsquo; incident to provide closure and support to those targeted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF writes to Google India about recent instances of YouTube copyright strikes</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-writes-to-google-india-about-recent-instances-of-youtube-copyright-strikes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 07:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/iff-writes-to-google-india-about-recent-instances-of-youtube-copyright-strikes/</guid>
      <description>We write to Google India highlighting that action taken upon copyright complaints is based on an incorrect application of copyright law and YouTube’s policies and, therefore, threatens press freedom and is in violation of the constitutional rights of digital media reporters and its audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Patrakar Defence Clinic is back again for October!</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-patrakar-defence-clinic-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 07:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-patrakar-defence-clinic-october/</guid>
      <description>IFF in collaboration with FMP launched DPDC in September to provide pro bono legal assistance to journalists. DPDC will continue to provide pro bono legal assistance throughout the year. In this post we highlight who can apply for the Clinic, and the pro bono legal services offered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MeitY blocks information about Actor Sushant Singh’s account takedown</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/meity-blocks-information-about-actor-sushant-singhs-account-takedown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 12:47:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/meity-blocks-information-about-actor-sushant-singhs-account-takedown/</guid>
      <description>Twitter unilaterally and arbitrarily suspended the account of Sushant Singh (@sushant_says) twice, i.e. on February 1 and May 26, 2021. We helped him file RTI requests with the Meity, DoT and MHA. Meity invoked the 2009 Blocking Rules and the RTI Act to deny information to Mr. Singh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pegasus: Rupesh Kumar Singh and Ipsa Shatakshi and other journalists approach SC</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/pegasus-rupesh-kumar-singh-and-ipsa-shatakshi-and-other-journalists-approach-sc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 06:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/pegasus-rupesh-kumar-singh-and-ipsa-shatakshi-and-other-journalists-approach-sc/</guid>
      <description>Rupesh Kumar Singh and Ipsa Shatakshi, activists reporting on issues related to Adivasi people in Jharkhand, approached the SC asking to declare that the use of a spyware such as Pegasus is unconstitutional. IFF has provided legal assistance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to do if your social media account is blocked?</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/what-to-do-if-your-social-media-account-is-blocked/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 12:06:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/what-to-do-if-your-social-media-account-is-blocked/</guid>
      <description>Refer to this explainer to understand what to do if your account is blocked on social media channels like Twitter, YouTube, Facebook, and Instagram.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women’s safety on the internet has to account for intersectionality</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/womens-safety-on-the-internet-intersectionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 12:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/womens-safety-on-the-internet-intersectionality/</guid>
      <description>In light of recent incident wherein women belonging to the Muslim community were targeted, we have written to the NCW &amp;amp; DCW with our recommendations as well as to GoDaddy.com asking them to remove the domain registered with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Tech releases its transparency reports in compliance with the IT Rules: Here’s what we found</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/big-tech-releases-its-transparency-reports-in-compliance-with-the-it-rules-heres-what-we-found/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 13:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/big-tech-releases-its-transparency-reports-in-compliance-with-the-it-rules-heres-what-we-found/</guid>
      <description>Google, Facebook, Instagram, WhatsApp and Twitter have released their transparency reports in compliance with Rule 4(1)(d) of the Information Technology (Guidelines for Intermediaries and Digital Media Ethics Code) Rules, 2021 (the 2021 IT Rules).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for June, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-june-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 06:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-june-2021/</guid>
      <description>Since our last report for the month of May, IFF has filed 18  RTI requests, 2 First Appeals and 1 Second Appeal. Here, we give you an overview of the requests filed and why demanding transparency and accountability from Government authorities essential in our fight to protect digital rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter must apply its own policies transparently and consistently when suspending users’ accounts</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/twitter-must-apply-its-own-policies-transparently-and-consistently-when-suspending-users-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 04:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/twitter-must-apply-its-own-policies-transparently-and-consistently-when-suspending-users-accounts/</guid>
      <description>Twitter unilaterally and arbitrarily suspended the account of Sushant Singh (@sushant_says) twice. He sent a formal representation to Twitter highlighting issues with Twitter’s policies and actions, relating to transparency, free expression and consistency, and urged an open dialogue on its policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live and let Live: The Supreme Court releases draft rules for live streaming of court proceedings</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/live-and-let-live-the-supreme-court-releases-draft-rules-for-live-streaming-of-court-proceedings-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 14:11:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/live-and-let-live-the-supreme-court-releases-draft-rules-for-live-streaming-of-court-proceedings-2/</guid>
      <description>The e-Committee has released draft rules for live streaming of all proceedings in all courts. We strongly welcome this step, and offer small changes which can further improve the Rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revealed: RTI Request uncovers MeitY letters to Twitter asking to remove the ‘manipulated media’ tag</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/revealed-rti-request-uncovers-meity-letters-to-twitter-asking-to-remove-the-manipulated-media-tag/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 05:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/revealed-rti-request-uncovers-meity-letters-to-twitter-asking-to-remove-the-manipulated-media-tag/</guid>
      <description>We were provided copies of two letters from MeitY to Twitter, which do not cite any provision of law, but have asked Twitter to refrain from implementing its policy and process of affixing the ‘Manipulated Media’ tag on tweets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madras High Court issues notice in petition challenging the Intermediary Rules 2021 by T. M. Krishna</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/madras-high-court-issues-notice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 05:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/madras-high-court-issues-notice/</guid>
      <description>Madras High issued notice on a writ petition by T.M. Krishna challenging the Intermediary Rules 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for May, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-may-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 06:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-may-2021/</guid>
      <description>Since our last report in the month of April, IFF has filed 32 RTI requests and 1 first appeal. Here, we give you an overview of the requests filed and explain why demanding transparency from government authorities is one of the key elements in our fight to protect digital rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indore Collector&#39;s welcome response - problematic paragraph repealed</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indore-collectors-welcome-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 16:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indore-collectors-welcome-response/</guid>
      <description>Today, in a major victory for online free speech, the Collector, Indore issued an order repealing paragraph 7 of Indore&amp;rsquo;s 144 order, and replacing it with clearer language, prohibiting only posts &amp;ldquo;that pose a danger to public peace, law and order, and health of the public&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indore administration curbs speech on social media</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indore-administration-curbs-speech-on-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 13:03:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indore-administration-curbs-speech-on-social-media/</guid>
      <description>Indore administration issued an over-broad order under Section 144(1) CrPC, 1973 banning speech related to Covid-19 on social media platforms. We have filed an application before the  Collector, Indore seeking withdrawal of the Order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MEITY responds to our representation to unblock Twitter accounts. Confirms orders and denies disclosure.</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/meity-response-to-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 08:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/meity-response-to-representation/</guid>
      <description>In February, we had written to MeitY with regards to the blocking of Twitter accounts. MeitY responded to us recently, saying that they did nothing wrong. We have written back to the Ministry this week explaining how they are constitutionally required to disclose the blocking orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transparency: A Right to Information Report for April, 2021</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-april-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/digital-transparency-a-right-to-information-report-for-april-2021/</guid>
      <description>Since our last report in the month of March, IFF has filed 7 RTI requests. Here, we give you an overview of the requests filed and why demanding transparency from government authorities is one of the key elements in our fight to protect digital rights which has taken a hit in the lockdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Kanoon defends the right to provide access to court records</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indian-kanoon-kerala-hc-right-to-be-forgotten/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/indian-kanoon-kerala-hc-right-to-be-forgotten/</guid>
      <description>In response to a petition filed before the Kerala HC, Indian Kanoon has clarified that a right to be forgotten cannot be judicially created without a statutory basis and explained that court records are public documents whose reproduction cannot be prohibited by citing the right to privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Section 118A repeal important steps remain for the Government of Kerala</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/after-section-118a-repeals-important-steps-remain-for-the-government-of-kerala/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 08:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/after-section-118a-repeals-important-steps-remain-for-the-government-of-kerala/</guid>
      <description>Read our proposals to the Government of Kerala to help avoid any overbroad or unnecessary criminalisation of online speech while also making sure abuse, threats or any of the harms that emerge on social media can be checked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kerala&#39;s Proposed Amendment to curb online abuse is eerie in its similarity to the unconstitutional S.66A</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/keralas-proposed-amendment-to-curb-online-abuse-is-eerie-in-its-similarity-to-the-unconstitutional-s-66a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/keralas-proposed-amendment-to-curb-online-abuse-is-eerie-in-its-similarity-to-the-unconstitutional-s-66a/</guid>
      <description>Read IFF&amp;rsquo;s representation to the Government of Kerala highlighting the similarities between their proposed amendment to the Kerala Police Act and the unconstitutional S.66A of the IT Act, 2000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We write to the Criminal Law Reform Committee which could make it even easier for TV anchors to read your texts #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/criminal-law-reform-committee-submission/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 07:02:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/criminal-law-reform-committee-submission/</guid>
      <description>Our submission reiterates demands to disband the Committee and we have also provided substantive inputs on various issues at the intersection of criminal law and digital rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t swipe next! We write to the Parliamentary Standing Committee for sustained hearings and an international human rights audit of Facebook India</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-demand-scrutiny-on-fb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 07:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-demand-scrutiny-on-fb/</guid>
      <description>There has been an alarming press report published in the Wall Street Journal on August 14, 2020 titled, “Facebook’s Hate-Speech Rules Collide with Indian Politics”. It merits urgent intervention and investigation into human rights breaches by Facebook India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIFT&#39;s Social Media Policy, 2020 violates the Right to Freedom of Speech and Expression</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/nifts-social-media-policy-2020-violates-the-right-to-freedom-of-speech-and-expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 07:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/nifts-social-media-policy-2020-violates-the-right-to-freedom-of-speech-and-expression/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the Director General of NIFT as well as the Ministry of Textiles asking them to recall the policy which hampers the right to freedom of speech and expression of the students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Major changes to Indian criminal law are underway! How can we use this process to defend and advance digital rights? #RightToMeme</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/criminal-law-amendment-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 05:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/criminal-law-amendment-committee/</guid>
      <description>The Ministry of Home Affairs has established a Committee to recommend changes to Indian criminal law within six months. We must ensure the Committee&amp;rsquo;s recommendations do not lead to arbitrary prosecution of internet users or have a chilling effect on online speech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We urge the Maharashtra Government to formulate objective standards to protect social media users from bullying! #RighttoMeme</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-the-maharashtra-govt-on-the-ongoing-arbitrary-criminal-prosecutions-for-online-speech-righttomeme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 04:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-the-maharashtra-govt-on-the-ongoing-arbitrary-criminal-prosecutions-for-online-speech-righttomeme/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the Hon’ble Chief Minister and Home Minister of the Government of Maharashtra worried by a series of criminal prosecutions against social media users which created a chilling effect on their right to freedom of speech and expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on IFF’s Zombie Tracker</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/update-on-zombie-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 08:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/update-on-zombie-tracker/</guid>
      <description>IFF, in collaboration with CivicDataLab, is building a “Zombie Tracker” to track cases under S. 66A, Information Technology Act, at the district level. S.66A of the IT Act is termed as a legal zombie since, even though it was declared unconstitutional in 2015, its use is ongoing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We wrote to the Mumbai Police asking them to review and amend their Social Media Regulation Order issued under S.144, CrPC #FreeToMeme</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-to-the-mumbai-police-asking-them-to-review-and-amend-their-social-media-order-issued-under-s-144-crpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 04:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/we-wrote-to-the-mumbai-police-asking-them-to-review-and-amend-their-social-media-order-issued-under-s-144-crpc/</guid>
      <description>On May 23, 2020 the Mumbai Police issued an Order under S.144, CrPC. The order prohibits the spread of certain information through social media platforms. We have sent a representation to the Mumbai Police &amp;amp; the Maharashtra Home Dept. asking them to review and amend the order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>66A Zombies continue to menace Free Speech on the Internet #ZombieTracker</title>
      <link>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/66a-zombies-continue-to-menace-free-speech-on-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 10:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archive.internetfreedom.in/post/66a-zombies-continue-to-menace-free-speech-on-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>Despite repeated directions by the Supreme Court, that all pending cases under S. 66A of the Information Technology Act be closed and also that no fresh charges may be registered, the provision continues to be invoked across the country.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
