<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Consultations on Internet Freedom Foundation</title>
    <link>https://internerfreedom.in/categories/consultations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Consultations on Internet Freedom Foundation</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://internerfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 07:47:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://internerfreedom.in/categories/consultations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>E-commerce Rules amendments: Protects consumers but lacks clarity</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/e-commerce-rules-amendments-protects-consumers-but-lacks-clarity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 07:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/e-commerce-rules-amendments-protects-consumers-but-lacks-clarity/</guid>
      <description>The recently proposed changes to the e-commerce rules, seek to  ensure consumer protection against unfair trade practices However, in a bid to create a more robust compliance mechanism, the rules run the risk of creating greater fault lines in India’s e-commerce industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Striking the balance between privacy and public interest in judicial proceedings: Our comments to the Supreme Court’s Draft Live Streaming Rules</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/striking-the-balance-between-privacy-and-public-interest-in-judicial-proceedings-our-comments-to-the-supreme-courts-draft-live-streaming-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 08:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/striking-the-balance-between-privacy-and-public-interest-in-judicial-proceedings-our-comments-to-the-supreme-courts-draft-live-streaming-rules/</guid>
      <description>Draft Model Rules for Live-Streaming and Recording of Court Proceedings were released by the Supreme Court’s e-Committee. IFF submitted its comments to the Draft Rules welcoming the Rules, and suggesting that the Rules can strike a better balance between  privacy and public interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We write to the Supreme Court e-Committee with CDL to improve the eCourts platform</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/we-write-to-the-supreme-court-e-committee-with-cdl-to-improve-the-ecourts-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 07:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/we-write-to-the-supreme-court-e-committee-with-cdl-to-improve-the-ecourts-platform/</guid>
      <description>We write to Supreme Court e-Committee highlighting the difficulties we faced on eCourt platform while building the Zombie Tracker. We have also provided our recommendations which seek to enable others to conduct data-driven research of judicial trends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We write to the Criminal Law Reform Committee which could make it even easier for TV anchors to read your texts #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/criminal-law-reform-committee-submission/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 07:02:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/criminal-law-reform-committee-submission/</guid>
      <description>Our submission reiterates demands to disband the Committee and we have also provided substantive inputs on various issues at the intersection of criminal law and digital rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move fast, break things? Not when sensitive health data is at stake! #SaveOurPrivacy</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/ndhm-data-privacy-policy-consultation-submission/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 06:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/ndhm-data-privacy-policy-consultation-submission/</guid>
      <description>We wrote to the National Health Authority seeking enactment of general and sectoral data protection laws and meaningful public consultation prior to deployment of any national digital health ID programme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Valentine’s, we send a love letter for net neutrality to TRAI #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/on-valentines-we-send-a-love-letter-for-net-neutrality-to-trai-savetheinternet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 11:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/on-valentines-we-send-a-love-letter-for-net-neutrality-to-trai-savetheinternet/</guid>
      <description>IFF responded to TRAI’s public consultation on net neutrality enforcement and highlighted the need to reduce discretion, increase transparency and accountability, boost the local measurement ecosystem, and build better more-inclusive institutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read our summary of TRAI’s consultation paper on net neutrality enforcement #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/trai-consultation-on-net-neutrality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 10:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/trai-consultation-on-net-neutrality/</guid>
      <description>Read our summary and participate in TRAI&amp;rsquo;s Consultation on Traffic Management Practices (TMPs) and Multi-Stakeholder Body for Net Neutrality by Jan. 31, 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For preventing red tape and impairing innovation we submit counter-comments to TRAI on the could services consultation</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/we-provide-the-trai-with-our-counter-comments-on-the-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 07:54:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/we-provide-the-trai-with-our-counter-comments-on-the-cloud/</guid>
      <description>We just submitted our counter comments on the paper to prevent red-rape and over regulation of the cloud services sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protect users, do not license the Internet #OTTConsultation #SaveTheInternet</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/protect-users-do-not-license-the-internet-ottconsultation-savetheinternet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 05:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/protect-users-do-not-license-the-internet-ottconsultation-savetheinternet/</guid>
      <description>The TRAI in November, 2018 released a consultation paper on regulation of OTT services. Yesterday, IFF made it’s submission on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding TRAI’s most recent “Over-The-Top” Consultation Paper #SaveTheInternet #NetNeutrality</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/understanding-trais-most-recent-over-the-top-consultation-paper-savetheinternet-netneutrality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 06:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/understanding-trais-most-recent-over-the-top-consultation-paper-savetheinternet-netneutrality/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE 08.12.2018 : TRAI extends the submission guideline by a month. New Date for submissions is now 07.01.2019. Counter comments is 21.
Why have you created this public analysis?
This is a public analysis for TRAI’s Consultation Paper on OTT [Over-The-Top] Consultation released on November 12, 2018. ‘OTT’ is an acronym that sounds dull, dry and technical &amp;ndash; we suspect just so that our eyes glaze over it &amp;ndash; and we stop paying attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting India’s WiFi</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/troubleshooting-indias-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/troubleshooting-indias-wifi/</guid>
      <description>A recently-closed consultation paper by the Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) explored how public WiFi could bring high-speed Internet to a large number of unconnected Indians. The Internet Freedom Foundation regards this as a very important issue and we have formally submitted our inputs to this consultation; this post explains our position.
In the consultation paper, TRAI pointed out that our country has woefully few public WiFi hotspots, even compared to other countries far smaller than ours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFF Comments on the Draft Geospatial  Information Regulation Bill, 2016</title>
      <link>https://internerfreedom.in/post/iff-comments-on-the-draft-geospatial-information-regulation-bill-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://internerfreedom.in/post/iff-comments-on-the-draft-geospatial-information-regulation-bill-2016/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year, the Ministry of Home Affairs to the Government of India put out a draft bill for comment - the Geospatial Information Regulation Bill, 2016.
As an organisation, one of IFF&amp;rsquo;s core areas is promoting an Internet which preserves freedom for users, designers, scholars and entrepreneurs. Such freedom today is being exercised by most users to generate and contribute geospatial information. Every Indian today with a smartphone is a cartographer who is helping map and digitise India.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
